<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ebox on Kelvin Nicholson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ebox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ebox on Kelvin Nicholson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2009 21:30:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ebox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vortex86DX Instructions from ICOP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/12/vortex86dx-instructions-from-icop_3935.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2009 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/12/vortex86dx-instructions-from-icop_3935.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alexandru T. and I have exchanged a few emails, and he sent through a few helpful suggestions that were provided from ICOP. I have included them below. Thanks Alexandru!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Install Debian 5.0 on a normal PC (using a netinst image, for minimal install)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. After installation boot normally from the same PC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Then, take the kernel from &lt;a href=&#34;ftp://icop.com.tw/DIS&#34;&gt;ftp://icop.com.tw/DIS&lt;/a&gt;_info/VDX/operating_system/VDX_Linux/linux-image-2.6.30-vortex86mx_1.0_i386.deb and then issue the following commands :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;\# dpkg -i  linux-image-2.6.30-vortex86mx\_1.0\_i386.deb
# update-initramfs -k 2.6.30-vortex86mx -c
# update-grub
# restart
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. Then take the hard-drive and install it on the Vortex86DX&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lenny on Ebox 3310A</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/11/lenny-on-ebox-3310a_5547.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/11/lenny-on-ebox-3310a_5547.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a preface, I take absolutely no credit for the below instructions. Stefan L kindly sent these through these instructions on installing Debian on the 3310A. I need to send a special thanks to Stefan, as I receive a lot of emails about the 3310 - but I don&amp;rsquo;t have one, so I can&amp;rsquo;t really do much:(&lt;br&gt;
The only edit I&amp;rsquo;ve done is change out the links to my files on S3. If you find these helpful, or want to suggest an alteration, please leave a comment.&lt;br&gt;
Download these files first:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Debian 5.0 on Vortex86DX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/06/installing-debian-50-on-vortex86dx_3246.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/06/installing-debian-50-on-vortex86dx_3246.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After writing about &lt;a href=&#34;http://kelvinism.com/tech-blog/compiling-kernel-vortex86dx/&#34;&gt;compiling a new kernel&lt;/a&gt; for the Vortex86DX, I&amp;rsquo;ve had quite a few people email me asking how I installed Debian in the first place. The installation is actually quite straightforward, but it involved several quirky techniques. After doing another install I decided to keep track of the process of installing Debian 5.0 on my eBox-3300.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following guide assumes a few things. First, you are currently using Linux and a debian variety (although instructions could be altered if using Windows). Second, your USB shows up as /dev/sdb. Third, your eBox-3300 has the HDD set in Native mode. Forth, you are patient.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compiling kernel for Vortex86dx</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/05/compiling-kernel-for-vortex86dx_5058.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/05/compiling-kernel-for-vortex86dx_5058.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;ve written up a &lt;a href=&#34;http://kelvinism.com/howtos/installing-debian-50-vortex86dx/&#34;&gt;short tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on the method I used to install Debian 5.0 on this device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I purchased the eBox-3300 from WDL Systems. The system was promptly shipped, and there were no &amp;ldquo;gotchas&amp;rdquo; from WDL. The little box fit my exact needs - it is small, and built very, very well. I flew back to Australia and, after some trial and error, installed Debian 5.0 on it. For quite some time I was just using the vmlinuz file provided by WDL, which was provided by ICOP (DMP). This worked well, but there were two issues:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
