<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Voip on Kelvin Nicholson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/voip/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Voip on Kelvin Nicholson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/voip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OpenMoko In Person</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/openmoko-in-person_6379.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/openmoko-in-person_6379.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago I had the privilege of meeting up with some of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openmoko.org&#34;&gt;OpenMoko&lt;/a&gt; guys. You&amp;rsquo;ve seen me write a little bit about this project, but meeting them and actually getting to play with a device was quite enlightening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most foreigners in Taipei take taxis, but not I. My girlfriend gave me a rough estimate how to go to FIC headquarters, yet it was &amp;ndash; rough. I jumped on the right bus, going the right direction, yet didn&amp;rsquo;t really know where to get off. In my broken Chinese I started talking to a group of high school kids, who somewhat pointed me in the right direction. At one point we were coming up to a light and a lady just said: &amp;ldquo;get off, go down that road.&amp;rdquo; I grabbed my bag and jumped off the bus. The street signs started to resemble the characters I had written down, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know which direction to go in. I asked a travel agency, and they pointed me in the right direction &amp;ndash; and then it started to rain. I luckily found FIC without getting too wet, and quickly met Sean, the project leader for OpenMoko.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computex 2007 Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/computex-2007-review_8211.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/computex-2007-review_8211.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The buzz of Computex is finally wearing off, so I&amp;rsquo;ll finally scribe my account of the event. YS was kind enough to go with me, we actually called it a date. The scene was quite similar to the trade shows we saw last year, however there seemed to be fewer people. This might be because we went on the final day, although we suspect there weren&amp;rsquo;t that many people because there aren&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;sweet&amp;rdquo; deals to be had. Regardless, there were several main &amp;ldquo;halls&amp;rdquo; filled full of stuff. The first three (two were in one building) weren&amp;rsquo;t particularly interesting. I mean, there were some cool displays and lots of technology, but nothing that left me thinking &amp;ldquo;oh, that&amp;rsquo;s cool&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;oh, me wanna.&amp;rdquo; Until we hit the last hall.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
