<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Vmware on Kelvin Nicholson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/vmware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vmware on Kelvin Nicholson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 20:30:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/vmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Downloading VMWare with Firefox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/06/downloading-vmware-with-firefox_4800.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/06/downloading-vmware-with-firefox_4800.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had this issue happen to me several times, and I&amp;rsquo;m finally writing myself a note to fix it in the future. There seems to be an issue with downloading VMWare Workstation (.bundle). I first tried it with Firefox, but it just crapped out at loading it into /tmp. Next, I tried it with Lynx, but alas, it tried to download it as a text file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahah! The quickest solution I could find is to right click the link, save as, and save it as a zip. Rename it to .bundle when you&amp;rsquo;re done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Files between ESX and Linux via NFS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/03/files-between-esx-and-linux-via-nfs_6022.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/03/files-between-esx-and-linux-via-nfs_6022.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like ESX. I like Linux. It is absurdly easy to configure Linux as an NFS server and mount it in ESXIi).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Installed NFS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I currently use Ubuntu Server for my home lab, but the process is basically the same for Red Hat and derivatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install nfs-common
sudo apt-get install nfs-kernel-server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, configure NFS so it can server your local LAN. Normally you would list only specific servers, but, well, we&amp;rsquo;re being cheap and dirty today. Open /etc/exports in VI or your editor of choice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beginning Scripting ESXi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/01/beginning-scripting-esxi_6126.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/01/beginning-scripting-esxi_6126.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not impressed too often with much software, especially the closed source kind. I find a leaning preference to all things FOSS. If I had a million dollars, I&amp;rsquo;d likely spend all day contributing to all the projects I wish I had time to contribute to. Regardless, there are a select few closed-source products that I believe are truly excellent. I mean, the type of software where you aren&amp;rsquo;t asking &amp;ldquo;I wish this could do this&amp;rdquo; and start asking &amp;ldquo;I wonder what else this can do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install ESX from a USB (no CDROM)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/install-esx-from-usb-no-cdrom_3723.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/install-esx-from-usb-no-cdrom_3723.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My little server doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a cdrom, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to actually run ESX from a USB (i.e. esx-on-a-stick). Here are my notes of configuring a flash disk to boot the ESX installer (so you can install it onto a local disk). For this demo, my USB is /dev/sdb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install the syslinux utils to your computer (apt-get install syslinux mboot)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install the MBR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo install-mbr /dev/sdb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy all the files from the ISO to your fat32 formated partition&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrating large disks into ESXi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/migrating-large-disks-into-esxi_4692.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/migrating-large-disks-into-esxi_4692.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had the need to move a rather large (450GB) VMDK file from an external hard drive into ESXi. Since ESXi doesn&amp;rsquo;t support external hard drives, this makes things quite a bit more difficult. At first I tried using SCP to copy the file over (after enabling SSH access for ESXi). However, when I tried to do this the time left was almost 20 hours &amp;ndash; a tad too long!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speeding Up VMWare Server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/speeding-up-vmware-server_791.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/speeding-up-vmware-server_791.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found VMWare Server to have very slow I/O, and sought to improve it. Below are a list of tests I performed, the change, and the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  
  
\### Host OS ###  
/dev/sdb1:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:  220 MB in  3.05 seconds =  72.17 MB/sec  
kelvin@gorilla:~$ sudo hdparm -t /dev/sdb1  
  
/dev/sdb1:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:  266 MB in  3.01 seconds =  88.33 MB/sec  
kelvin@gorilla:~$ sudo hdparm -t /dev/sdb1  
  
/dev/sdb1:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:  310 MB in  3.01 seconds = 102.99 MB/sec  
  
  
\### Before Changes ###  
  
/dev/mapper/openfiler-data:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:    8 MB in  3.36 seconds =   2.38 MB/sec  
\[root@files etc\]# hdparm -t /dev/mapper/openfiler-data  
  
/dev/mapper/openfiler-data:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:   24 MB in  3.63 seconds =   6.61 MB/sec  
\[root@files etc\]# hdparm -t /dev/mapper/openfiler-data  
  
/dev/mapper/openfiler-data:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:   28 MB in  4.54 seconds =   6.16 MB/sec  
  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I made several changes, but the changes that seemed to have the most impact are below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Raw Disks with VMware Server 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/using-raw-disks-with-vmware-server-2_3562.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/using-raw-disks-with-vmware-server-2_3562.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For various reasons I had the need to open a raw disk inside VMware Server 2. The reports from the field say that this just isn&amp;rsquo;t supported. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t need to actually run a raw disk, I needed to get some data off it &amp;ndash; 400GB worth. It turns out &amp;rsquo;not supported&amp;rsquo; really means &amp;rsquo;not in the UI.&amp;rsquo; I don&amp;rsquo;t know the reason why it isn&amp;rsquo;t in the UI, maybe marketing wants people to use ESX, or maybe the UI guys fell behind with their workload.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VM Automatic Startup in Server 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/vm-automatic-startup-in-server-2_6579.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/vm-automatic-startup-in-server-2_6579.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think possibly one of the most practical upgrades in VMware Server 2 appears to be the ability to automatically turn on virtual machines in a stagnated order. I have fond memories of turning on a server with 10 virtual machines, and when they all turn on at once, the hard disk grinds to a halt. This forced me to turn on the machines manually afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;+1 VMware in my books.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 8.04 64-Bit and VMware Server 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/ubuntu-804-64-bit-and-vmware-server-2_1451.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/ubuntu-804-64-bit-and-vmware-server-2_1451.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I now have successful installation of VMware Server 2 (Beta RC1) on top of Ubuntu 8.04 64-bit. I have been using various virtualization technologies for years, and VMware is usually the easiest to install and configure. So far, VMware Server 2 RC1, has proven to be the exception to the rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I am very excited by the direction VMware is taking &amp;ndash; this new server version looks to have great potential.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware Tools in VMware Server 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/vmware-tools-in-vmware-server-2_6233.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/vmware-tools-in-vmware-server-2_6233.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Installing the tools in VMware Server 2 is a little different than Workstation or the previous versions of VMware Server. Under the Summary tab of your Virtual Machine, look for a link that says &amp;ldquo;Install VMware Tools&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; click it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait for &amp;lsquo;Success&amp;rsquo; to show up on the bottom, and jump into your virtual machine. Mount the tools as so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mount /dev/cdrom /media/cdrom
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;And install as normal (copy the .tar.gz to /usr/src, extract it, install it). Easy peasy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
