<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Kelvin Nicholson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Kelvin Nicholson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 19:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beers of Myanmar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/04/beers-of-myanmar.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 19:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/04/beers-of-myanmar.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEif7aRldJHf11iFGfj_pzfi2I6yMjdlUiqyVIM4axh4zsh6yITSFlguCWVt2JuulOXI-sOlspMs4rxoVPOsnrUriAhPs6eNN9sGamwL7GUKsVGem57gqYBtmSdv54YRqdEayrjiwQ9BpquD/s1600/IMG_20140423_082522.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEif7aRldJHf11iFGfj_pzfi2I6yMjdlUiqyVIM4axh4zsh6yITSFlguCWVt2JuulOXI-sOlspMs4rxoVPOsnrUriAhPs6eNN9sGamwL7GUKsVGem57gqYBtmSdv54YRqdEayrjiwQ9BpquD/s1600/IMG_20140423_082522.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEif7aRldJHf11iFGfj_pzfi2I6yMjdlUiqyVIM4axh4zsh6yITSFlguCWVt2JuulOXI-sOlspMs4rxoVPOsnrUriAhPs6eNN9sGamwL7GUKsVGem57gqYBtmSdv54YRqdEayrjiwQ9BpquD/s1600/IMG_20140423_082522.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEif7aRldJHf11iFGfj_pzfi2I6yMjdlUiqyVIM4axh4zsh6yITSFlguCWVt2JuulOXI-sOlspMs4rxoVPOsnrUriAhPs6eNN9sGamwL7GUKsVGem57gqYBtmSdv54YRqdEayrjiwQ9BpquD/s1600/IMG_20140423_082522.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While in Myanmar on a recent trip I did a brief taste comparison of the three main beers available in most supermarkets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andaman&lt;/strong&gt; - Not to my taste, perhaps like XXXX, VB, Natural Light, or a light Steel Reserve.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar&lt;/strong&gt; - Quite refreshing, a bit like similar beers in the region, e.g. Chang, Tiger, or Laos Beer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABC&lt;/strong&gt; - An extra stout (and 8%!) in such a hot country? That&amp;rsquo;s a surprise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiking the W Circuit (Torres del Paine)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/06/hiking-w-circuit-torres-del-paine.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 13:33:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/06/hiking-w-circuit-torres-del-paine.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhmKGA0j5Z25NkCby3nEWwQeIyj5RZwDF-CmNKR3asVKlojpdpPc2TtR8ISaevfODn3BwaRpEB60SbTegfb7-VDUMq2pIOWhMPRLKRFfzoKy8XjJ3oghEt0mSLeHQL8t80G3QmkDCGOdFFV/s1600/IMG_2686.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhmKGA0j5Z25NkCby3nEWwQeIyj5RZwDF-CmNKR3asVKlojpdpPc2TtR8ISaevfODn3BwaRpEB60SbTegfb7-VDUMq2pIOWhMPRLKRFfzoKy8XjJ3oghEt0mSLeHQL8t80G3QmkDCGOdFFV/s320/IMG_2686.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We have just returned from hiking the &amp;ldquo;W&amp;rdquo;, a famous circuit through the Torres del Paine, in Patagonia. Although we did some research before doing the trek, it turns out we made a number of assumptions that turned out to be incorrect. I will detail in this entry what we learned, a few things that worked well, and a few things that did not work so well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will try to avoid posting spoilers of the major sites, and instead focus on logistics of doing the trek. First things first: much of this content is from what we learned at a talk given at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.erraticrock.com/&#34;&gt;Erratic Rock&lt;/a&gt; hostel, at 3PM the day before entering the park. The single biggest suggestion I would give you is to go to this talk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned from Kathmandu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/01/lessons-learned-from-kathmandu.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 23:34:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/01/lessons-learned-from-kathmandu.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our first trip to Kathmandu is now over, so there are some lessons learned I should scribe. Some of these are obvious, and which we abide by whenever travelling, and some we simply forgot in our (very) impromptu trip to Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When agreeing on a price, make 100% sure the other person states the price back to you. I thought a price had been agreed to when the other person responded &amp;ldquo;ok ok, you are a lucky man&amp;rdquo;, but this does not count. As they say, reconfirm, reconfirm, reconfirm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned for Lightweight Travel to Europe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/01/lessons-learned-for-lightweight-travel.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 22:55:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/01/lessons-learned-for-lightweight-travel.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that our Europe trip has ended, I need to leave a note of things I wish we had done better, both travel-wise, and the stuff we brought along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to travel light, and find it a little comical when I see people struggling with giant 70L backpacks; my partner and I always do carry-on, no matter for a two week trip, or two months. (This means our packs have to weigh less than 7KG). Even in winter it is possible to pack light. The trick seems to be only packing what one will use regularly, with no duplicates, of appropriate size, and hopefully reusable for other purposes. Don&amp;rsquo;t pack anything you would be gutted if it broke.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass Spam Delete Django</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/10/mass-spam-delete-django_8712.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/10/mass-spam-delete-django_8712.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you can read, I&amp;rsquo;ve been traveling around quite a bit lately. This means I haven&amp;rsquo;t been checking the comments on my blog, which means quite a bit of spam has been entered. I am blocking the spam via akismet, however, it is still recorded in the database. Being somebody who hates cluttered desktops, you can imagine how I feel about having a lot (447) of spam. Well, since akismet flips the is_public switch True for good comments and False for bad comments, that makes a &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; easy query in mysql.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Portable Travel Stick</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/my-portable-travel-stick_1543.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/my-portable-travel-stick_1543.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This will be my last post from Taiwan, and I&amp;rsquo;m placing it in my tech section. Shortly I will be flying to Hong Kong, and then traveling into China. I&amp;rsquo;m not bringing my laptop with me. I&amp;rsquo;m always a little wary of using public computers, especially in many of the poorly run internet cafes. Often the logged in user is the administrator, and we all know the computers are obviously crawling with worms and keyloggers. What can I do?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
