<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Backpacking on Kelvin Nicholson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/backpacking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Backpacking on Kelvin Nicholson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 10:19:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/backpacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Post Backpacking Trip Clean-Up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/post-backpacking-trip-clean-up.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 10:19:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/post-backpacking-trip-clean-up.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have the privilege of being able to afford all those random little backpacking items, and while I don&amp;rsquo;t baby my gear, I do try to take care of it. Especially things that keep me safe. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I do after every trip with a few of the items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have what are probably the two most popular water filters on the market: the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.katadyn.com/us/us/14946-8019639-katadyn-befree-0.6L_usa&#34;&gt;Katadyn BeFree&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sawyer.com/products/sawyer-squeeze-filter/&#34;&gt;Sawyer Squeeze&lt;/a&gt;. The point of this article isn&amp;rsquo;t about comparing filters, but I recommend both: I use the BeFree for solo day hikes / fastpacking or if water is plentiful, and the Squeeze in pretty much every other situation (e.g. if I need to filter for other people). If buying now then I would be super keen to try out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.platy.com/ie/filtration/quickdraw-microfilter/11458.html&#34;&gt;Platypus QuickDraw&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Katoomba to Mittagong (131km)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/katoomba-to-mittagong-131km.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 08:22:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/katoomba-to-mittagong-131km.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Where: Katoomba to Mittagong (via Hill Top for reasons below)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When: 2020/12/27 18:00 to 2020/12/30 morning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distance: 131km, with maybe 30 km of buckwhacking (details below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conditions: Day 2 was pretty weird, as it started quite hot, probably around 27C, and then it just opened up and poured. Forecasted to unload 20mm, and I think that felt about right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Useful Pre-Trip Information or Overview: I found a few GPX tracks and added a several backup tracks in Gaia GPS, but opted to follow the boring “quicker” route. I think the GPX I used was not one that had been recorded, but just one that had been created. This was one of the planning mishaps for my adventure: I overestimated possible pace. The GPX had 5km/hr average. I read previous trip reviews of people saying they could jog the track. It quickly became apparent there was no way anybody would be able to do parts of the track that quickly, so either I went a different way, the track got more difficult, or I haven’t mastered bushwhacking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cox’s River return via Narrowneck</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/coxs-river-return-via-narrowneck.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 23:50:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/coxs-river-return-via-narrowneck.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; Read below for a long list of warnings. After reading some of the comments below, e.g. from Des, it seems like the track can vary significantly depending on when you do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR - in winter, after bush fires and floods, this track is a 7/6. Left Katoomba Railway Station at about 10:00am on a Saturday in early August, so I guess technically still winter. I packed quite light and intended to do this in two days, and hopefully even get back to Sydney by 5pm. I had all the topological maps offline in Gaia GPS, and created a route based on the maps in Wildwalks; I couldn’t find a GPS trace. For the record: not a single time did I ever feel lost. It is very simple from a navigation perspective: keep Cox river to right. Walk in Breakfast Creek until it forks to Carlons Creek - go left. Now, go up. And up. Here are my notes and where things got slow. Six Foot Track - beautiful and very, very easy. First 11km (starting at Katoomba station) average pace was around ~10:15/km. The next 7km was a tad bit slower, maybe around 12:00/km.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultralight Backpacking - Food &amp; Electrolytes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/ultralight-backpacking-food.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 20:11:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/ultralight-backpacking-food.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In about 2001 or 2002 I read a book called &amp;ldquo;Beyond Backpacking - Ray Jardine&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Lightweight Hiking&amp;rdquo;, which set me on a path to being as light as possible. It came in very handy when I did my first section hike of the PCT, about 7 days, and I vaguely remember a total pack weight of about 25 lbs - with 4 litres of water. I was a broke college student then, so I guess clipping toothbrushes and straps really paid off. I also used a weird mesh hammock thing and I think a tarp of some kind. I have been &amp;ldquo;ultralight&amp;rdquo; ever since, even when renting equipment in Patagonia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Aid Kit (Backpacking)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/06/my-first-aid-kit-backpacking.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 21:23:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2019/06/my-first-aid-kit-backpacking.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two first aid kits: one that is in my bag when I go to work, and another when I go hiking. The one in my bag has more stuff in it, but overall the contents are pretty similar. In particular with the hiking kit I am only carrying what is likely to be used, items that cannot be improvised with what I can find, and items that I know how to use. It would be easy to &lt;em&gt;pack my fears&lt;/em&gt; and include a tourniquet or triangle bandage or EpiPen, but if I allowed myself to fear that level of risk I would also wear a helmet while walking across crosswalks. The reality is I am much more likely to get blisters, minor cuts, and lots of sore muscles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overland Track Lighter Pack Tips</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/05/overland-track-lighter-pack-tips.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 21:53:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2019/05/overland-track-lighter-pack-tips.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hiking companion and I recently completed the Overland Track in Tasmania, and she posted a picture of our packs on a related group on Facebook. There was an overwhelming response, ranging from &lt;em&gt;good job!&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;you&amp;rsquo;re a liar&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;you surely didn&amp;rsquo;t have a tent&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;you must be on a tour and didn&amp;rsquo;t bring food&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can understand the skepticism. Upon inspecting what people brought, and never used, there is definitely a preference for people to &lt;em&gt;pack their fears&lt;/em&gt;. Considering this track seemed to be the first time many people have done a multi-day backpacking trip, there were a lot of things they likely would not pack after gaining a little more experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
