<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Gae on Kelvin Nicholson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/gae/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gae on Kelvin Nicholson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2010 20:30:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/gae/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 10.04, Django and GAE - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/06/ubuntu-1004-django-and-gae-part-1_8750.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2010 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/06/ubuntu-1004-django-and-gae-part-1_8750.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started to get into Google&amp;rsquo;s App Engine again, and have started developing a simple product that I had a use for. The initial first draft was a quick 200 lines in webapp, and it worked great. However, I&amp;rsquo;m starting to find certain things quite cumbersome. I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of Django, and but also about keeping things as simple as possible, which is why I picked webapp to begin with.&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m now considering making a swap to Django, but there are some development issues; namely, I&amp;rsquo;m using Ubuntu 10.04, Python 2.6, and Django 1.2. This setup presents several setbacks, as GAE has the requirement of Django 1.1 and Python 2.5. There are two solutions that I found: a) use virtualenv, which &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/blogger.g?blogID=3439832858234004835#&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve detailed&lt;/a&gt;, or b) chroot. This document will hopefully show how to configure a chroot environment of Ubuntu 9.10 and prepare it for Django on GAE. Using a jailed environment should allow you to edit your code with your normal IDE and VCS, but use Django 1.1 and Python 2.5.&lt;br&gt;
First, I installed schroot and debootstrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 10.04, Django and GAE - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/06/ubuntu-1004-django-and-gae-part-2_6130.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2010 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/06/ubuntu-1004-django-and-gae-part-2_6130.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All my Django sites are running 1.2, which poses a conflict with writing apps for Google&amp;rsquo;s App Engine, as use_library currently only supports &amp;lt; Django 1.1. There are two solutions that I found: a) use virtualenv, or b) chroot, which &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/howtos/ubuntu-1004-django-and-gae-part-1/&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve already detailed&lt;/a&gt;. This document will hopefully show you how to create a virtual environment to use a secondary django version, especially for GAE. Of the two options, I think this one is a bit quicker, but there will likely be tradeoffs that a chroot environment can deal with better, e.g. python imaging (I don&amp;rsquo;t use it for GAE).&lt;br&gt;
First, install PIP and virtualenv:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
