<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ossec on Kelvin Nicholson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ossec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ossec on Kelvin Nicholson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2009 20:30:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ossec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>True Consolidation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/04/true-consolidation_6503.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/04/true-consolidation_6503.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2000 I managed to acquire several retired systems to bring to Uni: this included 4-5 cheap P120 machines. At the time, I thought this was great; I had an OpenBSD box as my gateway, a FreeBSD box, a few Linux boxes, and likely something else that doesn&amp;rsquo;t even exist now. The school has a superfast connection, unlimited bandwidth, and I was curious. Although I didn&amp;rsquo;t really have &lt;em&gt;time&lt;/em&gt;, I still managed to install and have all these servers running from my room.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charting the Hackers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/charting-hackers_7870.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/charting-hackers_7870.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A normal internet connection gets attacked, a lot. The majority of attacks are of the form &amp;ldquo;hello, anybody there?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; where most people just don&amp;rsquo;t answer. But sometimes, just sometimes, the question gets an answer. Depending on the answer, the attacker will start to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks back I was a little bored and started fiddling. I wanted to play with my Cisco, but also wanted to play with OSSEC, but also has a GIS craving. In the end I decided to create a map of the people who ask, &amp;ldquo;hello&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating OSSEC with Cisco IOS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/integrating-ossec-with-cisco-ios_7061.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/integrating-ossec-with-cisco-ios_7061.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I rank OSSEC as one of my favorite pieces of open source software, and finally decided to play around with it more in my own free time. (Yup, I do this sort of stuff for &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt;). My goal was quite simple: send syslog packets from my Cisco to my &amp;ldquo;proxy&amp;rdquo; server, running OSSEC. I found that, although OSSEC supports Cisco IOS logging, it didn&amp;rsquo;t really work. In fact, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any examples or articles of anybody actually getting it to work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
