<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Graphing on Kelvin Nicholson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/graphing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graphing on Kelvin Nicholson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 21:30:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/graphing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Capped Internet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/capped-internet_4903.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/capped-internet_4903.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve lived in several different parts of the world, and they all do internet differently. Back in the US I had 8Mb/sec cable (leaving just before Fios was really an option, darn!) In New Zealand, for instance, I was paying for &amp;ldquo;high speed ADSL&amp;rdquo; rated at 1.5Mb/256k. Vrooom. Up in Taiwan I was paying 1/2 what I paid in New Zealand, but for 12Mb/1Mb. Down to Sydney and we have a rated 24Mb/1Mb.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another Baby Step</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/another-baby-step_1340.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/another-baby-step_1340.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I showed a few of my co-workers my graph and one replied &amp;ndash; oh! that&amp;rsquo;s really cool. (I think only two of my co-workers are actually interested in my geekyness). He then emailed me tonight a .kmz file containing a colorized file of his speed. I looked at the kml and noticed it appeared to be dynamically allocated judging by the top speed. Well, as you could guess, I surely had to modify my code to include colors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Event vs. DOM Driven Parsing of XML</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/event-vs-dom-driven-parsing-of-xml_6678.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/event-vs-dom-driven-parsing-of-xml_6678.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently have been &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/tech-blog/baby-steps-graphing-traffic/&#34;&gt;playing&lt;/a&gt; with parsing GPX files and spitting out the results into a special KML file. I initially wrote a parser using minidom, yet after running this the first time &amp;ndash; and my Core2Duo laptop reaching 100% utilization for 10 seconds &amp;ndash; I realized I needed to re-write it using something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a little time reading the different parsers for XML and eventually read more about &lt;a href=&#34;http://effbot.org/zone/celementtree.htm&#34;&gt;cElementTree&lt;/a&gt;. And it is included with Python2.5, sweet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
