<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Kelvin Nicholson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Kelvin Nicholson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 21:41:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>State of Health: 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2025/01/state-of-health-2024.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 21:41:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2025/01/state-of-health-2024.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, probably in late 2022, I was doing some self-reflection and was pondering what the next constraint was for improving my health. Depending on whom you ask, there are generally several areas of focus when it comes to health:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nutrition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metabolic health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing or screenings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supplementation or pharmacological interventions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conclusion I reached after seeing/eating more of my partner&amp;rsquo;s diet is that nutrition was the next area for me to focus on. My approach has typically been to deep dive on reading books, and since then I&amp;rsquo;ve read the following books related to nutrition and longevity:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post Backpacking Trip Clean-Up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/post-backpacking-trip-clean-up.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 10:19:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/post-backpacking-trip-clean-up.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have the privilege of being able to afford all those random little backpacking items, and while I don&amp;rsquo;t baby my gear, I do try to take care of it. Especially things that keep me safe. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I do after every trip with a few of the items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have what are probably the two most popular water filters on the market: the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.katadyn.com/us/us/14946-8019639-katadyn-befree-0.6L_usa&#34;&gt;Katadyn BeFree&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sawyer.com/products/sawyer-squeeze-filter/&#34;&gt;Sawyer Squeeze&lt;/a&gt;. The point of this article isn&amp;rsquo;t about comparing filters, but I recommend both: I use the BeFree for solo day hikes / fastpacking or if water is plentiful, and the Squeeze in pretty much every other situation (e.g. if I need to filter for other people). If buying now then I would be super keen to try out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.platy.com/ie/filtration/quickdraw-microfilter/11458.html&#34;&gt;Platypus QuickDraw&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Katoomba to Mittagong (131km)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/katoomba-to-mittagong-131km.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 08:22:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/katoomba-to-mittagong-131km.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Where: Katoomba to Mittagong (via Hill Top for reasons below)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When: 2020/12/27 18:00 to 2020/12/30 morning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distance: 131km, with maybe 30 km of buckwhacking (details below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conditions: Day 2 was pretty weird, as it started quite hot, probably around 27C, and then it just opened up and poured. Forecasted to unload 20mm, and I think that felt about right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Useful Pre-Trip Information or Overview: I found a few GPX tracks and added a several backup tracks in Gaia GPS, but opted to follow the boring “quicker” route. I think the GPX I used was not one that had been recorded, but just one that had been created. This was one of the planning mishaps for my adventure: I overestimated possible pace. The GPX had 5km/hr average. I read previous trip reviews of people saying they could jog the track. It quickly became apparent there was no way anybody would be able to do parts of the track that quickly, so either I went a different way, the track got more difficult, or I haven’t mastered bushwhacking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cox’s River return via Narrowneck</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/coxs-river-return-via-narrowneck.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 23:50:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/coxs-river-return-via-narrowneck.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; Read below for a long list of warnings. After reading some of the comments below, e.g. from Des, it seems like the track can vary significantly depending on when you do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR - in winter, after bush fires and floods, this track is a 7/6. Left Katoomba Railway Station at about 10:00am on a Saturday in early August, so I guess technically still winter. I packed quite light and intended to do this in two days, and hopefully even get back to Sydney by 5pm. I had all the topological maps offline in Gaia GPS, and created a route based on the maps in Wildwalks; I couldn’t find a GPS trace. For the record: not a single time did I ever feel lost. It is very simple from a navigation perspective: keep Cox river to right. Walk in Breakfast Creek until it forks to Carlons Creek - go left. Now, go up. And up. Here are my notes and where things got slow. Six Foot Track - beautiful and very, very easy. First 11km (starting at Katoomba station) average pace was around ~10:15/km. The next 7km was a tad bit slower, maybe around 12:00/km.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultralight Backpacking - Food &amp; Electrolytes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/ultralight-backpacking-food.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 20:11:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/ultralight-backpacking-food.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In about 2001 or 2002 I read a book called &amp;ldquo;Beyond Backpacking - Ray Jardine&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Lightweight Hiking&amp;rdquo;, which set me on a path to being as light as possible. It came in very handy when I did my first section hike of the PCT, about 7 days, and I vaguely remember a total pack weight of about 25 lbs - with 4 litres of water. I was a broke college student then, so I guess clipping toothbrushes and straps really paid off. I also used a weird mesh hammock thing and I think a tarp of some kind. I have been &amp;ldquo;ultralight&amp;rdquo; ever since, even when renting equipment in Patagonia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Sight Words</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/teaching-sight-words.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 23:03:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/07/teaching-sight-words.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of books on parenting. Before my daughter was born I read a book on pregnancy, one of those 500 pages texts from a high class place - Mayo Clinic or Harvard or something like that. It was helpful, but given I can&amp;rsquo;t even remember the name, clearly not something that I considered life changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Thirty-Million-Words-Building-Childs-ebook/dp/B00SI02BHE&#34;&gt;Thirty Million Words: Building a Child&amp;rsquo;s Brain&lt;/a&gt; I was all hyped up to drown my new kid in words. We travelled a lot when she was young, so didn&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of books, but she sure had them read to her. When I took a year off as a stay-at-home-dad I kept having those 30 million words ticking in my mind. By the time she was 2 1/2 she was getting five books read to her a night. By the time she was around 3 1/2 she was listening to Amazon Story Time for an hour every evening.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Aid Kit (Backpacking)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/06/my-first-aid-kit-backpacking.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 21:23:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2019/06/my-first-aid-kit-backpacking.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two first aid kits: one that is in my bag when I go to work, and another when I go hiking. The one in my bag has more stuff in it, but overall the contents are pretty similar. In particular with the hiking kit I am only carrying what is likely to be used, items that cannot be improvised with what I can find, and items that I know how to use. It would be easy to &lt;em&gt;pack my fears&lt;/em&gt; and include a tourniquet or triangle bandage or EpiPen, but if I allowed myself to fear that level of risk I would also wear a helmet while walking across crosswalks. The reality is I am much more likely to get blisters, minor cuts, and lots of sore muscles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overland Track Lighter Pack Tips</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/05/overland-track-lighter-pack-tips.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 21:53:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2019/05/overland-track-lighter-pack-tips.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hiking companion and I recently completed the Overland Track in Tasmania, and she posted a picture of our packs on a related group on Facebook. There was an overwhelming response, ranging from &lt;em&gt;good job!&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;you&amp;rsquo;re a liar&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;you surely didn&amp;rsquo;t have a tent&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;you must be on a tour and didn&amp;rsquo;t bring food&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can understand the skepticism. Upon inspecting what people brought, and never used, there is definitely a preference for people to &lt;em&gt;pack their fears&lt;/em&gt;. Considering this track seemed to be the first time many people have done a multi-day backpacking trip, there were a lot of things they likely would not pack after gaining a little more experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IoT Foray with Sonoff S20 / IFTTT / Lambda / CloudMQTT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2018/05/ys-and-i-recently-purchased-echo-from.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 14:08:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2018/05/ys-and-i-recently-purchased-echo-from.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently purchased an Echo from Amazon, and we were contemplating how else to better integrate it with our somewhat minimalistic home. I thought it would be interesting to get it to link to a WiFi-enabled power outlet, but unfortunately they are pretty expensive in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I stumbled across the &lt;a href=&#34;http://sonoff.itead.cc/en/&#34;&gt;Sonoff&lt;/a&gt; devices by Itead, and learned that they were somewhat hackable via a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arendst/Sonoff-Tasmota&#34;&gt;custom firmware&lt;/a&gt;. Coincidentally I received the two devices on the same day my daughter was off sick, so when she had her nap, I got hacking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geocoding Photos (Mac)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/12/geocoding-photos-mac.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/12/geocoding-photos-mac.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started using OSX (again), and am really enjoying it (again). One Windows-only tool that I found really useful is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geosetter.de/en/&#34;&gt;Geosetter&lt;/a&gt;, which allows you to add geo coordinates into photos. There don&amp;rsquo;t appear to be any free geocoding tools that work to my satisfaction to do this, so the next best thing was geocode like you would using Linux. Here&amp;rsquo;s how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to use the command line program &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sno.phy.queensu.ca/~phil/exiftool/&#34;&gt;ExifTool&lt;/a&gt; (by Phil Harvey) to extract coordinates from a gpx file and embed them in a directory of images.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snap-CI Deploy to OpenShift</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/11/snap-ci-deploy-to-openshift.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 23:37:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/11/snap-ci-deploy-to-openshift.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are some wonderful &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thoughtworks.com/continuous-integration&#34;&gt;CI&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thoughtworks.com/continuous-delivery&#34;&gt;CD&lt;/a&gt; tools out there right now, and some of them have very usable free tiers. A few good examples include &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.shippable.com/&#34;&gt;Shippable&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://wercker.com/&#34;&gt;Wercker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cloudbees.com/products/dev&#34;&gt;CloudBees,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.snap-ci.com/&#34;&gt;Snap-CI&lt;/a&gt;. There are others, of course, but these all allow at least one private project to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently moved my projects to Snap, and my hack for the day needed to be deployed to OpenShift. Although Snap has built in integrations for some providers, no such integration currently exists for OpenShift (yet!). However, it takes less than 10 minutes to configure a Deploy step to OpenShift, and here&amp;rsquo;s how.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solved: slow build times from Dockerfiles with Python packages (pip)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/07/solved-slow-build-times-from.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 18:13:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/07/solved-slow-build-times-from.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently had the opportunity to begin exploring &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.docker.com/&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;, the currently hip way to build application containers, and I generally like it. It feels a bit like using Xen back in 2005, when you still had to download it from cl.cam.ac.uk, but there is &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; momentum right now. I like the idea of breaking down each component of your application into unique services and bundling them up - it seems clean. The next year is going to be very interesting with Docker, as I am especially looking forward to seeing how Google&amp;rsquo;s App Engine allows Docker usage, or what&amp;rsquo;s in store for the likes of Flynn, Deis, CoreOS, or Stackdock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TLS Module In SaltStack Not Available (Fixed)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/05/tls-module-in-saltstack-not-available.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2014 12:50:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/05/tls-module-in-saltstack-not-available.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was trying to install &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/saltstack/halite&#34;&gt;HALite&lt;/a&gt;, the WebUI for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.saltstack.com/&#34;&gt;SaltStack&lt;/a&gt;, using the provided instructions. However, I kept getting the following errors when trying to create the certificates using Salt:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;   &#39;tls.create_ca_signed_cert&#39; is not available.   &#39;tls.create_ca&#39; is not available.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Basically, the &amp;rsquo;tls&amp;rsquo; module in Salt simply didn&amp;rsquo;t appear to work. The reason for this is detailed on &lt;a href=&#34;http://intothesaltmine.org/install_and_configure_halite_alpha_on_arch_linux.html&#34;&gt;intothesaltmind.org&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Use of the tls module within Salt requires the pyopenssl python extension.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That makes sense. We can fix this with something like:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;   apt-get install libffi-dev   pip install -U pyOpenSSL   /etc/init.d/salt-minion restart&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Or, better yet, with Salt alone:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beers of Myanmar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/04/beers-of-myanmar.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 19:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/04/beers-of-myanmar.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEif7aRldJHf11iFGfj_pzfi2I6yMjdlUiqyVIM4axh4zsh6yITSFlguCWVt2JuulOXI-sOlspMs4rxoVPOsnrUriAhPs6eNN9sGamwL7GUKsVGem57gqYBtmSdv54YRqdEayrjiwQ9BpquD/s1600/IMG_20140423_082522.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEif7aRldJHf11iFGfj_pzfi2I6yMjdlUiqyVIM4axh4zsh6yITSFlguCWVt2JuulOXI-sOlspMs4rxoVPOsnrUriAhPs6eNN9sGamwL7GUKsVGem57gqYBtmSdv54YRqdEayrjiwQ9BpquD/s1600/IMG_20140423_082522.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEif7aRldJHf11iFGfj_pzfi2I6yMjdlUiqyVIM4axh4zsh6yITSFlguCWVt2JuulOXI-sOlspMs4rxoVPOsnrUriAhPs6eNN9sGamwL7GUKsVGem57gqYBtmSdv54YRqdEayrjiwQ9BpquD/s1600/IMG_20140423_082522.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEif7aRldJHf11iFGfj_pzfi2I6yMjdlUiqyVIM4axh4zsh6yITSFlguCWVt2JuulOXI-sOlspMs4rxoVPOsnrUriAhPs6eNN9sGamwL7GUKsVGem57gqYBtmSdv54YRqdEayrjiwQ9BpquD/s1600/IMG_20140423_082522.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While in Myanmar on a recent trip I did a brief taste comparison of the three main beers available in most supermarkets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andaman&lt;/strong&gt; - Not to my taste, perhaps like XXXX, VB, Natural Light, or a light Steel Reserve.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar&lt;/strong&gt; - Quite refreshing, a bit like similar beers in the region, e.g. Chang, Tiger, or Laos Beer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABC&lt;/strong&gt; - An extra stout (and 8%!) in such a hot country? That&amp;rsquo;s a surprise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Error opening /dev/sda: No medium found</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/03/error-opening-devsda-no-medium-found.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 10:02:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/03/error-opening-devsda-no-medium-found.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had this issue before, solved it, and had it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say you plug in a USB drive into a Linux machine, and try to access it (mount it, partition it with fdisk/parted, or format it), and you get the error&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;  Error opening /dev/sda: No medium found  &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally the first thing you will do is ensure that it appeared when you plugged it in, so you run &amp;lsquo;dmesg&amp;rsquo; and get:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;  sd 2:0:0:0: [sda] 125045424 512-byte logical blocks: (64.0 GB/59.6 GiB)  &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Flow Through Worm Bin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/01/continuous-flow-through-worm-bin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 14:45:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/01/continuous-flow-through-worm-bin.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months ago we decided we wanted a worm bin, as we were eating a lot of vegetables, and tossing away bits that weren&amp;rsquo;t used. We were also buying soil for our plants, so it made sense to try to turn one into another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of our friends gave us some worms from her compost - no idea what kind - and I build an experimental CFT worm bin (&lt;a href=&#34;http://vermicomposters.ning.com/forum/topics/diy-flow-through-bins-a&#34;&gt;sample plans&lt;/a&gt;). We harvested once at about two months, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think it was quite ready. We&amp;rsquo;ll keep experimenting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free Splunk Hosting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/11/free-splunk-hosting.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 00:18:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/11/free-splunk-hosting.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhidCIsvAamk9SjeJxqIcMmNA_hjCUOzREgxQ3hJuSXhU4RIHXuQO6WXMZZ1Eu34jI3exx0F8JwVX4Fu2iO_jBIazNkArv21u4OSbo3GFY_YcTScbA_kC0u5p0iiE_YyhAOl85Ze-742pB6/s1600/SplunkOpenShift.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhidCIsvAamk9SjeJxqIcMmNA_hjCUOzREgxQ3hJuSXhU4RIHXuQO6WXMZZ1Eu34jI3exx0F8JwVX4Fu2iO_jBIazNkArv21u4OSbo3GFY_YcTScbA_kC0u5p0iiE_YyhAOl85Ze-742pB6/s1600/SplunkOpenShift.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first used Splunk about 10 years ago after an old colleague installed it on a computer in the corner, and ever since then I have preached about it. If you have log data, of any kind, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend you give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Splunk people have a a few pretty good options for trying Splunk out, as you can either use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.splunkstorm.com/&#34;&gt;Splunk Storm&lt;/a&gt; or Splunk Free. The first option is obviously hosted, and has a generous storage option, but also does not allow long term storage of data. I send system log data to Splunk Storm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding The Same (Misspelled) Name Using Python/NLTK</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/09/finding-same-misspelled-name-using.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 17:24:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/09/finding-same-misspelled-name-using.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been meaning to play around with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://nltk.org/&#34;&gt;Natural Language Toolkit&lt;/a&gt; for quite some time, but I had been waiting for a time when I could experiment with it and actually create some value (as opposed to just play with it). A suitable use case appeared this week: matching strings. In particular, matching two different lists of many, many thousands of names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give you an example, let&amp;rsquo;s say you had two lists of names, but with the name spelled incorrectly in one list:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sydney&#39;s Education Levels Mapped</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/09/sydneys-education-levels-mapped.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 10:45:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/09/sydneys-education-levels-mapped.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was talking to a friend about what education levels might look like across Sydney, and a friend challenged me to map it. The below map is my first draft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The map was derived by combining three datasets from the Australian Bureau of Statistics (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.abs.gov.au/&#34;&gt;ABS&lt;/a&gt; - a department releasing some great datasets). The first dataset was the spatial data for &amp;ldquo;SA2&amp;rdquo; level boundaries, the second the population data for various geographic areas, and the third from the 2011 Census on Non-School Qualification Level of Education (e.g. Certificates, Diplomas, Masters, Doctorates). I aggregated all people with bachelors or higher in an SA2 region, and then divided that number by the total number of people in that region. A different methodology could have been used.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sydney Commute Times Mapped Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/08/sydney-commute-times-mapped-part-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 07:55:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/08/sydney-commute-times-mapped-part-2.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/2013/07/sydney-commute-times-mapped-part-1.html&#34;&gt;Sydney Commute Times Mapped Part 1&lt;/a&gt; I took a small step to a bigger goal of mashing together public transport in Sydney, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://strategies.planning.nsw.gov.au/Portals/0/Documents/MetroCommunityGuide.pdf&#34;&gt;Metropolitan Strategy for Sydney to 2031&lt;/a&gt;. The question I wanted to answer is this: how aligned is Sydney&amp;rsquo;s public transport infrastructure and the Metropolitan Strategy&amp;rsquo;s of a &amp;ldquo;city of cities&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the release of GTFS data by 131500 it is possible to visualise how long it takes via public transport to commute to the nearest &amp;ldquo;centre&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Self Interview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/quantified-self-interview.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2013 16:44:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/quantified-self-interview.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;YS and I were recently interviewed about self-tracking and Quantified Self by one of the major news channels in Australia. I will reflect on the experience after the show has aired, but it was an overall great experience. We have a new respect for filming what may ultimately be just a two minute segment. Depending on how the editing is done it will either provoke the hosts to contemplate the value of a data-centric macroscopic view of the world, or give them lots of fodder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coffee, Beer, Wine and Time of Day</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/coffee-beer-wine-and-time-of-day.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2013 16:23:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/coffee-beer-wine-and-time-of-day.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I like Tableau, a piece of software to visualise data, is that it aggregates on dates really well. Below is a spread of beer / wine / coffee over 18 months, but grouped by what hour is fell in. You can see some trends, like I usually consume coffee in the morning, and that I usually drink after 17:00. There are exceptions, of course, like that beer I had at 10AM, and that coffee I had at 1AM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some QS Numbers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/some-qs-numbers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 08:26:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/some-qs-numbers.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is the possibility I will be giving an interview on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantified_Self&#34;&gt;Quantified Self&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;movement&amp;rdquo;. What follows is a brief summary of QS, the things I track, and some pretty charts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Quantified Self&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose it depends on who you talk to. Wikipedia states that it is &amp;ldquo;a movement to incorporate technology into data acquisition on aspects of a person&amp;rsquo;s daily life in terms of inputs&amp;rdquo;, but I side more on the idea that the movement is &amp;ldquo;a collaboration of users and tool makers who share an interest in self knowledge through self-tracking.&amp;rdquo; It is at this point that it is probably important to interject that most people are self-trackers: weight, height, reps at the gym, hours worked, and so forth. If you have ever made a goal, you probably tracked how you could reach it. What makes us QS folk a bit different is that we tend to track &lt;em&gt;lots&lt;/em&gt; of things, correlate between them, and share our results. So, with this theme, let me share what I track.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sydney Commute Times Mapped Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/sydney-commute-times-mapped-part-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 10:06:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/sydney-commute-times-mapped-part-1.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I quite like open data. I like data based on open standards (or mostly open standards) even better. Many transport operators around the world have started releasing their timetable data using (mostly) open standards, e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_Transit_Feed_Specification&#34;&gt;GTFS&lt;/a&gt;. One of the nice things about using a standard is that clever people have created tools to work with the timetable data, and those tools can now be used to manipulate timetable data from hundreds of agencies. The magnificent OpenTripPlanner is one such tool, and it works well with &lt;a href=&#34;http://131500.info/&#34;&gt;131500&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s GTFS data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Mesh Blocks with TileMill</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/mapping-mesh-blocks-with-tilemill.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 02:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/mapping-mesh-blocks-with-tilemill.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This quick tutorial will detail how to prepair the ABS Mesh Blocks to be used with MapBox&amp;rsquo;s TileMill. Beyond scope is how to install postgresql, postgis and TileMill. There is a lot of documentation how to do these tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we create a database to import the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.abs.gov.au/AUSSTATS/abs@.nsf/DetailsPage/1270.0.55.001July%202011?OpenDocument&#34;&gt;shapefile&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.abs.gov.au/AUSSTATS/abs@.nsf/DetailsPage/2074.02011?OpenDocument&#34;&gt;population data&lt;/a&gt; into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using &amp;lsquo;psql&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;SQL Query&amp;rsquo;, create a new database:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;CREATE DATABASE transport WITH TEMPLATE postgis20 OWNER postgres;
# Query returned successfully with no result in 5527 ms.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is necessary to first import the Mesh Block spatial file using something like PostGIS Loader.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Urban Density in Sydney</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/mapping-urban-density-in-sydney.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 00:34:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/mapping-urban-density-in-sydney.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Five years ago I started exploring different mapping technologies by detailing instructions on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/2008/04/setting-up-mapnik-server-on-ubuntu_118.html&#34;&gt;installing Mapnik&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/2008/11/revised-modtile-install-howto_1369.html&#34;&gt;mod_tile&lt;/a&gt;. Times have changed significantly in the last five years, and thanks a lot to the products offered by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mapbox.com/&#34;&gt;MapBox&lt;/a&gt;. After playing with TileMill, MBTiles, Leaflet and UTFGrids, it is great how many annoyances have been fixed by MapBox. I find it enjoyable making maps now, as I no longer need to worry about patching code just to get it to run, or mucking about with oddities in web browser.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiking the W Circuit (Torres del Paine)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/06/hiking-w-circuit-torres-del-paine.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 13:33:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/06/hiking-w-circuit-torres-del-paine.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhmKGA0j5Z25NkCby3nEWwQeIyj5RZwDF-CmNKR3asVKlojpdpPc2TtR8ISaevfODn3BwaRpEB60SbTegfb7-VDUMq2pIOWhMPRLKRFfzoKy8XjJ3oghEt0mSLeHQL8t80G3QmkDCGOdFFV/s1600/IMG_2686.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhmKGA0j5Z25NkCby3nEWwQeIyj5RZwDF-CmNKR3asVKlojpdpPc2TtR8ISaevfODn3BwaRpEB60SbTegfb7-VDUMq2pIOWhMPRLKRFfzoKy8XjJ3oghEt0mSLeHQL8t80G3QmkDCGOdFFV/s320/IMG_2686.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We have just returned from hiking the &amp;ldquo;W&amp;rdquo;, a famous circuit through the Torres del Paine, in Patagonia. Although we did some research before doing the trek, it turns out we made a number of assumptions that turned out to be incorrect. I will detail in this entry what we learned, a few things that worked well, and a few things that did not work so well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will try to avoid posting spoilers of the major sites, and instead focus on logistics of doing the trek. First things first: much of this content is from what we learned at a talk given at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.erraticrock.com/&#34;&gt;Erratic Rock&lt;/a&gt; hostel, at 3PM the day before entering the park. The single biggest suggestion I would give you is to go to this talk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>February Sydney Python Presentation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/02/february-sydney-python-presentation.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 23:10:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/02/february-sydney-python-presentation.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February I gave a presentation to about 80 people at the Sydney Python group hosted by Atlassian. Firstly, Atlassian&amp;rsquo;s office was beautiful, feeling a little like Google&amp;rsquo;s Sydney office, but with beer on tap instead of cereal dispensers. Secondly, the talk before me on Cython by &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/113985890803565448326/posts&#34;&gt;Aaron Defazio&lt;/a&gt; was exceptionally interesting, garnering lots of questions from the audience. My presentation, more of a show and tell on piping location data to Google&amp;rsquo;s Latitude through App Engine, was also meant to subtly share my views on the need for innovation in the public sector (all sectors, really).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned from Kathmandu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/01/lessons-learned-from-kathmandu.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 23:34:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/01/lessons-learned-from-kathmandu.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our first trip to Kathmandu is now over, so there are some lessons learned I should scribe. Some of these are obvious, and which we abide by whenever travelling, and some we simply forgot in our (very) impromptu trip to Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When agreeing on a price, make 100% sure the other person states the price back to you. I thought a price had been agreed to when the other person responded &amp;ldquo;ok ok, you are a lucky man&amp;rdquo;, but this does not count. As they say, reconfirm, reconfirm, reconfirm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrate Custom Blog to Blogger</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/01/migrate-custom-blog-to-blogger.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 20:14:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/01/migrate-custom-blog-to-blogger.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last ten years I have run this website from various systems. First it was on Wordpress, then Mambo, then Joomla, and since early 2006 it has been running on custom code written using Django. I used this site as a learning tool for Django, re-wrote it after gaining more knowledge of Django, and then re-wrote it again when Google released App Engine. However, I recently realised that for the last few years I have spent more time writing little features than actually writing. I have entire trips that I never wrote because I was too busy writing code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to convert 131500 TDX to GTFS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/07/how-to-convert-131500-tdx-to-gtfs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 13:59:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/07/how-to-convert-131500-tdx-to-gtfs.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TDX data has been available for a number of years on 131500.info, but many tools are GTFS specific. I also find GTFS easier to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, converting from TDX to GTFS is not overly difficult, and below are some instructions. This howto is a bit old, as I am only now copying it from my &amp;ldquo;Notes&amp;rdquo; folder to put online to help others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; You can now directly download GTFS from the TransportInfo website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://tdx.131500.com.au/&#34;&gt;https://tdx.131500.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye Facebook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/05/goodbye-facebook_21.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2012 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/05/goodbye-facebook_21.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I seldom used Facebook, and felt a bit depressed after logging on each time. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I am alone, but each time still felt a bit like a secret spitting contest. A bit, not a lot, but sort of subconsciously. Oh, he has a nice (sounding) job. -1 I&amp;rsquo;ve traveled more than her. +3 The old school cool guy is back living with his parents. +3 She has five kids already - I knew that would happen! -5 Honestly, though, even at an involuntary subconscious level, I don&amp;rsquo;t like spitting contests. I would rather be sharing ideas or creating something. Wish me luck.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>131500trains Updates to GTalk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/05/131500trains-updates-to-gtalk_8.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2012 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/05/131500trains-updates-to-gtalk_8.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a little hack I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share. There are maybe other ways to do this, but this way took all of two minutes, which suits me. My daily routine has me taking a train along the Inner West Line (here in Sydney), and I wanted to know in advance if there was any issues with the line. 131500 provides weekely emails about upcoming trackwork, and there&amp;rsquo;s an RSS feed of delays; this is what you&amp;rsquo;d see in many of the Sydney transport-related apps. Another information source is through Twitter. For all of these sources I only really care about the one line I take every day - the quickest answer would seem to be if I could only get updates on Twitter for my line&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned for Lightweight Travel to Europe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/01/lessons-learned-for-lightweight-travel.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 22:55:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/01/lessons-learned-for-lightweight-travel.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that our Europe trip has ended, I need to leave a note of things I wish we had done better, both travel-wise, and the stuff we brought along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to travel light, and find it a little comical when I see people struggling with giant 70L backpacks; my partner and I always do carry-on, no matter for a two week trip, or two months. (This means our packs have to weigh less than 7KG). Even in winter it is possible to pack light. The trick seems to be only packing what one will use regularly, with no duplicates, of appropriate size, and hopefully reusable for other purposes. Don&amp;rsquo;t pack anything you would be gutted if it broke.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned: Losing Parts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/11/lessons-learned-losing-parts_458.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/11/lessons-learned-losing-parts_458.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how many times I&amp;rsquo;ve lost tiny parts and had to spend time trying to find them. I realized after removing the back of my monitor that I&amp;rsquo;m starting to learn from those mistakes; instead of just sticking the screws in a box with other screws, and then having to dig them out, I taped them to the back of the monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/OqMPZv-C1FIlFQUDle20ttMTjNZETYmyPJy0liipFm0?feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjdsrGGIgIwudUyykswXY0FS7wK2fssrepfNQqldElC7NFgom4pMNJ8amETDCayCKzgOkMeJFNlSNbC4y6lOs9Oj9fK1i5DWNpTF5CoRr_h0rb1s-OUm88qoNyODThD1zm4vmh0Ygt1a3Qu/s400/IMG_20111103_191634.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sounds small, but after doing it I realised how many times I had to hunt through a box of screws trying to find the exact one that fit. Lesson learned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Destroying Hard Drives</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/10/destroying-hard-drives_7046.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/10/destroying-hard-drives_7046.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re like me there is a box of hard drives sitting in a dusty corner somewhere. Some are mine, some are others&amp;rsquo;, but they are all in a failed or semi-failed state. So, why have I lugged them around? I&amp;rsquo;ve been a bit paranoid about throwing them away. Some of the hard drives are encrypted, others aren&amp;rsquo;t, and the drives from friends certainly aren&amp;rsquo;t. Although the chances of somebody getting the drive from a landfill and restoring it is minimal, I never wanted to take the chance.&lt;br&gt;
So, I kept lugging a bag of drives through each move.&lt;br&gt;
My friend Clinton has recently returned from Europe, and he brought me a gift: a Swiss-made Victorinox, the &amp;lsquo;CyberTool&amp;rsquo;. After playing with it for several minutes I noticed it came with a Torx 8, 10 and 15 bit. This was a reminder that one method of mostly disabling a hard drive is to destroy the platters.&lt;br&gt;
Other methods I have heard are to use a hammer and nails - which I unfortunately don&amp;rsquo;t have in our tiny apartment. Whilst finishing Dexter I started pulling apart the box of hard drives, and it surprisingly didn&amp;rsquo;t take long to disable them.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Step 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Remove Torx screws&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fusion Tables and 131500 Stops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/fusion-tables-and-131500-stops_465.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2011 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/fusion-tables-and-131500-stops_465.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A short while ago I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/articles/visualizing-transport/&#34;&gt;visualizing transport&lt;/a&gt; by using 131500&amp;rsquo;s TDX data, converted to GTFS, and served by GeoServer. Because I&amp;rsquo;ve started &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/travelmap/&#34;&gt;playing around&lt;/a&gt; with Google&amp;rsquo;s Fusion table, I thought it would be interesting to see what all the transit stops in Sydney look like in FT. So, voila!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reload a Cisco Router WIthout Worry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/reload-cisco-router-without-worry.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 14:15:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/reload-cisco-router-without-worry.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I tried editing my Cisco&amp;rsquo;s ACL at home on the train. It went something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I logged in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started updating the ACL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I hit a blackspot in my 3g coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My command stops at &amp;ldquo;router(config)#access-&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I get a call from my partner saying &amp;ldquo;what did you do to our internet!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it is simple enough to just ask her to &amp;ldquo;flip the switch on the black box&amp;rdquo;, I still don&amp;rsquo;t like doing it. Plus, if she&amp;rsquo;s not home, I&amp;rsquo;m stuck. This accident immediately reminded me of one of a trait of the &amp;lsquo;reload&amp;rsquo; command: it can be scheduled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Converting GTFS to GraphServer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/converting-gtfs-to-graphserver.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 14:07:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/converting-gtfs-to-graphserver.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you want to use Graphserver to do some analysis with GTFS, you will need to convert GTFS into the database. This is how I did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;get-an-appropriate-ami-from-amazons-ec2&#34;&gt;Get an appropriate AMI from Amazon&amp;rsquo;s EC2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the following AMI. If you have enough memory, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ami-7000f019
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lookup and read the GTFSDB &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/gtfsdb/downloads/detail?name=GTFSDB%20INSTALL.txt&#34;&gt;INSTALL.txt&lt;/a&gt; document&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;prepare-system&#34;&gt;Prepare system&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install mercurial
hg clone https://gtfsdb.googlecode.com/hg/ gtfsdb
sudo apt-get install python-setuptools
sudo easy\_install psycopg2
sudo apt-get install build-essential
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;download-gtfs-database&#34;&gt;Download GTFS database&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ubuntu@domU-12-31-39-00-5D-B8:/mnt/gtfsdb$ pwd
/mnt/gtfsdb
sudo python setup.py install
sudo wget http://cdn.kelvinism.com/google\_transit.zip
sudo apt-get install python-psycopg2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;prepare-configuration-file&#34;&gt;Prepare configuration file&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;#default.cfg
\[options\]
create = True
database = postgresql://nsw:131500@10.128.49.175:5432/nsw
filename = /mnt/google\_transit.zip
geospatial = True
#schema = None
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;perform-import&#34;&gt;Perform import&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;screen
python gtfsdb/scripts/load.py
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Transport</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/04/visualizing-transport_1492.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/04/visualizing-transport_1492.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had several conversations with neighbors and co-workers about the &amp;ldquo;lack&amp;rdquo; of forward thinking, or at least the lack of forward action. Of course, I keep in the back of my mind that we aren&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;experts&amp;rdquo;, and the more I learn about transport the more I learn how complex it is. Dr. Sussman&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;CLIOS&lt;/em&gt; process (Complex, Large-&lt;br&gt;
Scale, Integrated, Open Systems) appears more and more true the longer I work in and study transport. There is a plethora of excuses that can be made, but the general conclusion was that the earlier we prepare the better. I can remember working near Zhongshan 7-8 years ago and driving around on huge roads in the middle of empty fields. There weren&amp;rsquo;t even stoplights at every intersection. It was then that I had an epiphany of how smart the planning was to build the infrastructure &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the masses arrived.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Removing Unused ContentTypes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/01/removing-unused-contenttypes_4881.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/01/removing-unused-contenttypes_4881.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been cleaning up my personal blog a bit, and I noticed that my tagging system recently broke. I&amp;rsquo;ve investigated the cause, and it appears to be because I removed some apps but the contenttypes remained. This meant that whenever I tried calling a tag with a TaggedItem that had been deleted, I was getting this error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;#39;NoneType&amp;#39; object has no attribute &amp;#39;\_meta&amp;#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The solution is to first list all app_labels for contenttypes, and then delete any not in use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrate imified into Django</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/01/integrate-imified-into-django_2631.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/01/integrate-imified-into-django_2631.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had the desire to send small updates to my so called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/about-me/&#34;&gt;lifestream&lt;/a&gt; page via XMPP/GTalk. I played around with Twisted Words and several other Python XMPP clients, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to keep a daemon running if unnecessary. It turns out imified took a lot of the pain out of it. The steps for me were as follows:&lt;br&gt;
Create an account with imified, and create a URL, e.g. /app/api/&lt;br&gt;
We then configure the &lt;strong&gt;urls.conf&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stock Android and Postfix</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/01/stock-android-and-postfix_2931.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/01/stock-android-and-postfix_2931.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was having some issues with my personal mail server (Postfix) and my phone (Android). The logs depicted the below issue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Jan  9 09:19:53 ip-11-222-23-223 postfix/smtpd\[12345\]: NOQUEUE: reject: RCPT from 12-13-14-15.abc.com.au\[12.13.14.15\]: 504 5.5.2 : Helo command rejected: need fully-qualified hostname; from= to= proto=ESMTP helo= 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can see here that the stock Android email client is doing a &amp;lsquo;helo localhost&amp;rsquo;. One part of my main.cf file specifies this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;smtpd\_helo\_required = yes
smtpd\_helo\_restrictions =
    permit\_mynetworks,
    reject\_non\_fqdn\_helo\_hostname,
    reject\_invalid\_helo\_hostname,
    permit\_sasl\_authenticated,
    permit
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;To resolve, unfortunately, just change the order to authenticated clients are permitted earlier:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Splunk with Python</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/10/hacking-splunk-with-python_9416.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/10/hacking-splunk-with-python_9416.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I saw an opening to give a 5-10 minute lightening talk at SyPy (Sydney Python), and with two nights to prepare, decided it would be interesting to explore Splunk&amp;rsquo;s usage of Python. Below was the quick presentation I gave.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enable ICMP through UFW</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/09/enable-icmp-through-ufw_461.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/09/enable-icmp-through-ufw_461.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like using Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s UFW command, but today I needed to allow outgoing ICMP. I received results as so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  
$ ping 4.2.2.2  
PING 4.2.2.2 (4.2.2.2) 56(84) bytes of data.  
ping: sendmsg: Operation not permitted  
ping: sendmsg: Operation not permitted  
ping: sendmsg: Operation not permitted  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;To allow outbound icmp I edited &amp;lsquo;before.rules&amp;rsquo; and added the following lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo vi /etc/ufw/before.rules
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  
\# allow outbound icmp  
\-A ufw-before-output -p icmp -m state --state NEW,ESTABLISHED,RELATED -j ACCEPT  
\-A ufw-before-output -p icmp -m state --state ESTABLISHED,RELATED -j ACCEPT  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using HTML in a Django form label</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/07/using-html-in-django-form-label_2240.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2010 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/07/using-html-in-django-form-label_2240.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had the need to add some HTML to the label for a form field using Django. The solution is pretty easy, except I didn&amp;rsquo;t see it written explicitly anywhere, and I missed the memo of the function I should be using.&lt;br&gt;
My form first just had the HTML in the form label as so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
from django import forms

class AccountForm(forms.Form):
    name = forms.CharField(widget=forms.TextInput(), max\_length=15, label=&amp;#39;Your Name ([why](http://www.blogger.com/questions/whyname/)?&amp;#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, when I displayed it, the form was autoescaped.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/PyGNXDrpXtrgBNnoOLlfLA?feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhvsLvb6I4SDBB3NKptLZzGLGnwUZK0KmYlx7X9UC2_fzyQCNTkeFiKz5-4_3BmKArYZhRwU8TNEIhrGAMsb039N47hxcY8BIMEJjfK1UafYCRvAPzY18c8ceq3QFOOsp_oGO6SavZ1LmGR/s800/accountsform.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 10.04, Django and GAE - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/06/ubuntu-1004-django-and-gae-part-1_8750.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2010 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/06/ubuntu-1004-django-and-gae-part-1_8750.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started to get into Google&amp;rsquo;s App Engine again, and have started developing a simple product that I had a use for. The initial first draft was a quick 200 lines in webapp, and it worked great. However, I&amp;rsquo;m starting to find certain things quite cumbersome. I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of Django, and but also about keeping things as simple as possible, which is why I picked webapp to begin with.&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m now considering making a swap to Django, but there are some development issues; namely, I&amp;rsquo;m using Ubuntu 10.04, Python 2.6, and Django 1.2. This setup presents several setbacks, as GAE has the requirement of Django 1.1 and Python 2.5. There are two solutions that I found: a) use virtualenv, which &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/blogger.g?blogID=3439832858234004835#&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve detailed&lt;/a&gt;, or b) chroot. This document will hopefully show how to configure a chroot environment of Ubuntu 9.10 and prepare it for Django on GAE. Using a jailed environment should allow you to edit your code with your normal IDE and VCS, but use Django 1.1 and Python 2.5.&lt;br&gt;
First, I installed schroot and debootstrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 10.04, Django and GAE - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/06/ubuntu-1004-django-and-gae-part-2_6130.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2010 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/06/ubuntu-1004-django-and-gae-part-2_6130.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All my Django sites are running 1.2, which poses a conflict with writing apps for Google&amp;rsquo;s App Engine, as use_library currently only supports &amp;lt; Django 1.1. There are two solutions that I found: a) use virtualenv, or b) chroot, which &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/howtos/ubuntu-1004-django-and-gae-part-1/&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve already detailed&lt;/a&gt;. This document will hopefully show you how to create a virtual environment to use a secondary django version, especially for GAE. Of the two options, I think this one is a bit quicker, but there will likely be tradeoffs that a chroot environment can deal with better, e.g. python imaging (I don&amp;rsquo;t use it for GAE).&lt;br&gt;
First, install PIP and virtualenv:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debug Postfix Tip</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/05/debug-postfix-tip_7051.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/05/debug-postfix-tip_7051.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing I love about open source stuff is that the developers usually take great care to allow awesome debug messages. There&amp;rsquo;s a catch-22, however: how much logging to enable? Today I was creating a Postfix/Dovecot/Postgresql install and I kept getting an error message in mail.log, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t very helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily you can turn up the verbosity in Postfix for error messages. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to find out what component is in error, e.g. &amp;ldquo;postfix/virtual[4467]: warning:&amp;rdquo;, and then open master.cf. Add a -v to the end of the daemon that&amp;rsquo;s faulting, and you&amp;rsquo;ll get more logging than you know what to do with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retiring Another Site</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/05/retiring-another-site_942.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2010 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/05/retiring-another-site_942.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After much consideration, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to retire yet another website: Colddirt. This site was created as an example of how to use the different parts of Django, mostly in just one afternoon. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided it is time to just take a few screenshots and retire the site - the domain is expiring, and honestly, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend $10 to renew the domain. So, here are the screenshots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/ePVyNddWOBJSJWqEIhYalw?feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi09jrZynm_kNvbfNESRQ9Dp8epPrHZ2iIrLNkGcoV2XpenNw51zVDWyq9rQmtdnYtabIsTnGaN0G9cWio2VhwKEmXkAdDd0ec0E6yr4uLeokPiZrVVMhoy3b9Ud34QWHHpPAueSWNnn_So/s400/colddirt_2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retiring Old Websites</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/05/retiring-old-websites_2251.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2010 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/05/retiring-old-websites_2251.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes all good things &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/tech-blog/rip-old-sites/&#34;&gt;come to an end&lt;/a&gt;. There aren&amp;rsquo;t too many links going into either of these sites, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to redirect all of them to a page on my blog saying the website doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist anymore. I&amp;rsquo;ve already created simple screendumps for nostalgic purposes with the Firefox plugin Screengrab!, so the remaining simple server-side steps are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit the DNS records from the live server to the server with the notice page is on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new vhost on the server the notice exists on, add old websites as ServerAlias.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a redirect in the vhost to the notice about the retired sites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reload apache config.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The below vhost entry will redirect any link to the retired sites to the notice page.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIP Old Sites</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/05/rip-old-sites_7527.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2010 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/05/rip-old-sites_7527.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve created several websites, some with the hope of becoming big and popular. Naturally, I&amp;rsquo;m still waiting to create a site that becomes big and popular. In the meantime, it seems appropriate to retire some of the older sites and ideas. The truth is, I&amp;rsquo;m moving all my little sites from MySQL on a mediocre VPS to Postgresql on EC2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I put some sweat and blood into these sites, I thought it would be only appropriate to record how the sites looked for future sentimental value. I downloaded a small plug-in for Firefox to take full-length pictures, and I thus post them here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fun with OSM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/02/fun-with-osm_3920.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/02/fun-with-osm_3920.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have to admit, to me, editing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openstreetmap.org/&#34;&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt; is actually a little therapeutic. Sort of like gardening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first major contribution was when I brought my little QStarz GPS unit across Indonesia, by train, sitting against the window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/a9waevHOnamwhJuZ0631AQ?feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhVRc8DuYUf5aDc9yLzjBA5JZmXTczhYyV8R4LeLVmss6J1D7RvhUo5MvP-NRqbOQ7a-v9UBY0vqlIEG_nXnQ0XJ3cZjDGBtmAygoJNRUu7R3ptkL7TtnRQM3fnRYhq01LZjLCLi6b2c3ll/s288/indorailroad.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/xg8TeUUtiZZhLH8T2irceA?feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEihqDfKD5tB1QYhRxDb3FFUfxBaDTMn7gNCdK7SeVrC_JzI5OwYdYS2NFaZ5hh-dtX3GgRW4Ony8XAbIr8hRKYNP1UMQmKAoSM7CoX-YsoYdYYwwCQm_jjnRCzRFcxdkiD2olu-guGS0s4e/s288/dubbozoo.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most recent contribution was our trip to Dubbo, where I helped fill in a few missing roads, and added an initial outlay of Dubbo Zoo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a GPS or have $60 to spend on one, and like anything CAD-drawing like, give editing OSM a try!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduce Bandwidth By Shrinking Images</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/01/reduce-bandwidth-by-shrinking-images_3510.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2010 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/01/reduce-bandwidth-by-shrinking-images_3510.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s brother has a simple WordPress-based website that I set up for him a few year ago - and he likes to post a lot of images. For various reasons I have it hosted on my VPS in Australia, which only comes with 15GB of bandwidth, most likely because I got a crazy good deal on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is, that isn&amp;rsquo;t much bandwidth. Each page of his site was previously using almost 10MB of bandwidth per view - which meant the 15GB was running out. I deduced the high usage in Firebug and noticed it was *gasp* from large images, some almost 1MB large. The images on the server are contained in subdirectories under a gallery folder - and I wanted to resize them. What I actually wanted to do was:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>French Word Collage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/01/french-word-collage_8613.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/01/french-word-collage_8613.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last year YS and I have been studying French once a week (4.5hr on Saturday!) A few months ago I wrote some Python code to read the RSS feeds of the most popular French newspaper site, and then kept track of the count of each word. I repeated this every week for a few months.&lt;br&gt;
In the end I had a database of the top ~3000 words used on the site. Today I decided I wanted to play with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blogger.com/www.processing.org&#34;&gt;Processing&lt;/a&gt;, so created this little word collage. It is 1680x1050, my monitor&amp;rsquo;s resolution. Two thumbs up for Processing!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vortex86DX Instructions from ICOP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/12/vortex86dx-instructions-from-icop_3935.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2009 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/12/vortex86dx-instructions-from-icop_3935.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alexandru T. and I have exchanged a few emails, and he sent through a few helpful suggestions that were provided from ICOP. I have included them below. Thanks Alexandru!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Install Debian 5.0 on a normal PC (using a netinst image, for minimal install)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. After installation boot normally from the same PC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Then, take the kernel from &lt;a href=&#34;ftp://icop.com.tw/DIS&#34;&gt;ftp://icop.com.tw/DIS&lt;/a&gt;_info/VDX/operating_system/VDX_Linux/linux-image-2.6.30-vortex86mx_1.0_i386.deb and then issue the following commands :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;\# dpkg -i  linux-image-2.6.30-vortex86mx\_1.0\_i386.deb
# update-initramfs -k 2.6.30-vortex86mx -c
# update-grub
# restart
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. Then take the hard-drive and install it on the Vortex86DX&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lenny on Ebox 3310A</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/11/lenny-on-ebox-3310a_5547.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/11/lenny-on-ebox-3310a_5547.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a preface, I take absolutely no credit for the below instructions. Stefan L kindly sent these through these instructions on installing Debian on the 3310A. I need to send a special thanks to Stefan, as I receive a lot of emails about the 3310 - but I don&amp;rsquo;t have one, so I can&amp;rsquo;t really do much:(&lt;br&gt;
The only edit I&amp;rsquo;ve done is change out the links to my files on S3. If you find these helpful, or want to suggest an alteration, please leave a comment.&lt;br&gt;
Download these files first:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Atheros Module and Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/09/new-atheros-module-and-ubuntu_1580.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/09/new-atheros-module-and-ubuntu_1580.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Atheros for quite some time, and I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked the madwifi drivers. They allowed really easy switching into monitor mode, and decent levels of packet injection. However, since I&amp;rsquo;m mostly in an office now, instead of writing web apps in cafes and trying to score free internet, I don&amp;rsquo;t really need anything fancy. My gentoo stage 1 (3?) days are over. I use Ubuntu, because I&amp;rsquo;m lazy, and it mostly works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remove Dead Tags</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/09/remove-dead-tags_6886.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/09/remove-dead-tags_6886.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed my django-tagging install has been giving a lot of empty entries when doing a lookup on a tag. Tonight I finally got around to looking at what was causing this. This is surely not the best way to do this, but at 12:00am on a weekday, well, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be doing it in the first place&amp;hellip; I first wanted to see what type of content was generating the error:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most Frequently Used French Words</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/08/most-frequently-used-french-words_140.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/08/most-frequently-used-french-words_140.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently studying French with my partner, and if you&amp;rsquo;ve read any of this site, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice I&amp;rsquo;m a bit of a techie. Often several of my interests collide, which is what happened today. I was searching for the &amp;ldquo;most frequent french words,&amp;rdquo; and while I found some lists, nothing was exactly what I wanted.&lt;br&gt;
My desire was to have a PDF of the top few thousand most used French words. With the English translation next to it. In order. I&amp;rsquo;ve found some great resources, which I&amp;rsquo;ll list now&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing SMS Gateways</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/07/testing-sms-gateways_5212.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/07/testing-sms-gateways_5212.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For one of my projects I&amp;rsquo;m testing an SMS gateway, and decided it would be fun to build a useful alarm clock out of it. For those of you who know Python, you may find this funny. /dev/ttyUSB0 is my Arduino with a temperature sensor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;import serial
import urllib2

def check\_temp():
ser = serial.Serial(&amp;#39;/dev/ttyUSB0&amp;#39;, 9600)
t = ser.readline().strip()
return float(t)

t = check\_temp()
if int(t) &amp;lt; 8:
message = &amp;#34;It+is+now+%f+degrees;+chuck+a+sicky.&amp;#34; % t
f = urllib2.urlopen(&amp;#39;http://api.clickatell.com/http/sendmsg?user=johnd&amp;amp;password=p@55w0rd&amp;amp;api\_id=2132867&amp;amp;from=61433735555&amp;amp;to=61433735555&amp;amp;text=%s&amp;#39; % message)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;And in crontab:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arduino 101</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/07/arduino-101_3715.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/07/arduino-101_3715.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight, I&amp;rsquo;m proud to say, I&amp;rsquo;ve returned to childhood. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, fun over, back to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last year I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to purchase an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arduino.cc/&#34;&gt;Arduino&lt;/a&gt;, for no other reason than to play with. Like a kid. My Arduino arrived two days ago. This is a story of problems, but not the pull-your-hair-out type, more the&amp;hellip; like when you run out of gas in the middle of Sydney. Going to your Christmas dinner. In your friend&amp;rsquo;s car. Long story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple Arduino &#43; LED Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/07/simple-arduino-led-tutorial_319.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/07/simple-arduino-led-tutorial_319.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this you&amp;rsquo;ll need: an Arduino, an LED, a USB cable, and the Arduino software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/VUU7F7qd8doQ0pCcs88wPQ?feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgSGIXNe3gLRzm8r7ioq8niUHdBdzZBD8L9WoBp4oQAIAtlbMGaI7r3RjGzEup0sN-sZKP7E0JQuUaH9jTtPE0at4L6MK_QwduouTOIyQFyEzC2bB9U_Y8ausq1PNXwdbqUzOccLRPNg2FF/s400/arduinowLED.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the LED, and plug it in to your Arduino. Plug in the long end to pin 13, plug the short end to the GND.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plug in the Arduino into your laptop. Go to Tools-&amp;gt;Serial Port. Choose the USB port that appears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take the code from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arduino.cc/en/Tutorial/BlinkingLED&#34;&gt;BlinkingLED tutorial&lt;/a&gt; and paste it in to the arduino like so:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPS Gem Find - TangoGPS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/06/gps-gem-find-tangogps_8634.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/06/gps-gem-find-tangogps_8634.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a simple, no-hassles GPS display program for Linux, and I believe I finally found one: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tangogps.org/gps/cat/About&#34;&gt;TangoGPS&lt;/a&gt;. My requirements were quite simple; I needed something that would talk to gpsd, and display a dot on OpenStreetMaps. I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to do this in other programs (even in 3d in WorldWind), but I wanted something to download the maps for me, and GTK+ would be a plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TangoGPS was easy to install (apt-get install tangogps), and on my test &amp;lsquo;drive&amp;rsquo; home tonight on the train, worked a treat. See related screenshots.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISO Code Error</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/06/iso-code-error_1265.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/06/iso-code-error_1265.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve received this error a few times when working with pytz:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Error reading file &amp;#39;/usr/share/xml/iso-codes/iso\_3166.xml&amp;#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;In short, install the &amp;lsquo;iso-codes&amp;rsquo; package in Ubuntu/Debian. I&amp;rsquo;m sure this is covered in the manual that I didn&amp;rsquo;t read, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure others didn&amp;rsquo;t read it too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install iso-codes
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Debian 5.0 on Vortex86DX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/06/installing-debian-50-on-vortex86dx_3246.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/06/installing-debian-50-on-vortex86dx_3246.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After writing about &lt;a href=&#34;http://kelvinism.com/tech-blog/compiling-kernel-vortex86dx/&#34;&gt;compiling a new kernel&lt;/a&gt; for the Vortex86DX, I&amp;rsquo;ve had quite a few people email me asking how I installed Debian in the first place. The installation is actually quite straightforward, but it involved several quirky techniques. After doing another install I decided to keep track of the process of installing Debian 5.0 on my eBox-3300.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following guide assumes a few things. First, you are currently using Linux and a debian variety (although instructions could be altered if using Windows). Second, your USB shows up as /dev/sdb. Third, your eBox-3300 has the HDD set in Native mode. Forth, you are patient.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operation Cold House</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/06/operation-cold-house_7266.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/06/operation-cold-house_7266.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My house is cold. I want to start playing with simple electronics before starting &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/projects/operation-field/&#34;&gt;Operation Field&lt;/a&gt;, so have created Operation Cold House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just simply sticking a temperature sensor onto an Arduino, linking that up to my little home &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/tech-blog/true-consolidation/&#34;&gt;server&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, and uploading that to my website. I&amp;rsquo;ll display some nifty graphs, too, and link it to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pachube.com/&#34;&gt;Pachube&lt;/a&gt;. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Complete! The proof is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/howtos/simple-arduino-led-tutorial/&#34;&gt;in the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/tech-blog/arduino-101/&#34;&gt;pudding&lt;/a&gt;. I now have a personal website from home (sorry, not public) that displays the daily and weekly temperature at home. The process is basically like this: my little Arduino gathers the temperature, and is polled every minute with a python script via cron. This script then sticks the time and temperature into MySQL. It also exports the temperature to Pachube. Every 30m I have a script that queries MySQL and uses Google&amp;rsquo;s Chart&amp;rsquo;s API to graph the temperature. Looks great, I&amp;rsquo;ll post a graph soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downloading VMWare with Firefox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/06/downloading-vmware-with-firefox_4800.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/06/downloading-vmware-with-firefox_4800.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had this issue happen to me several times, and I&amp;rsquo;m finally writing myself a note to fix it in the future. There seems to be an issue with downloading VMWare Workstation (.bundle). I first tried it with Firefox, but it just crapped out at loading it into /tmp. Next, I tried it with Lynx, but alas, it tried to download it as a text file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahah! The quickest solution I could find is to right click the link, save as, and save it as a zip. Rename it to .bundle when you&amp;rsquo;re done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a Movie from Images</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/06/create-movie-from-images_6692.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/06/create-movie-from-images_6692.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started leaving my webcam on as a motion detector to find out who is leaving the shopping cards on our lawn, and ultimately have found it useful to stitch the images together into a movie. There are several ways to do this - and my way maybe isn&amp;rsquo;t the best - but it works for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first installed and configured &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lavrsen.dk/twiki/bin/view/Motion/WebHome&#34;&gt;motion&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;rsquo;ve used for years. I then created a file in ~/.motion called motion.com:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compiling kernel for Vortex86dx</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/05/compiling-kernel-for-vortex86dx_5058.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/05/compiling-kernel-for-vortex86dx_5058.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;ve written up a &lt;a href=&#34;http://kelvinism.com/howtos/installing-debian-50-vortex86dx/&#34;&gt;short tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on the method I used to install Debian 5.0 on this device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I purchased the eBox-3300 from WDL Systems. The system was promptly shipped, and there were no &amp;ldquo;gotchas&amp;rdquo; from WDL. The little box fit my exact needs - it is small, and built very, very well. I flew back to Australia and, after some trial and error, installed Debian 5.0 on it. For quite some time I was just using the vmlinuz file provided by WDL, which was provided by ICOP (DMP). This worked well, but there were two issues:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing locale errors in Ubuntu 8.04</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/05/fixing-locale-errors-in-ubuntu-804_7736.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/05/fixing-locale-errors-in-ubuntu-804_7736.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve hit this problem a few times, and figured I&amp;rsquo;d leave a note for myself how to fix it. Ubuntu 8.04 seems to hiccup sometimes (on a VPS) for generating the correct locales. In particular, I get this error, a lot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;perl: warning: Setting locale failed.
perl: warning: Please check that your locale settings:
LANGUAGE = (unset),
LC\_ALL = (unset),
LANG = &amp;#34;en\_US.UTF-8&amp;#34;
are supported and installed on your system.
perl: warning: Falling back to the standard locale (&amp;#34;C&amp;#34;).
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Normally I just do &amp;lsquo;dpkg-reconfigure locales&amp;rsquo;, but with 8.04, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to do squat. The solution is to edit the &lt;strong&gt;/var/lib/locales/supported.d/local&lt;/strong&gt; file, and insert the correct locales (it will normally not exist, so create it):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing mysql warning message</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/05/fixing-mysql-warning-message_4782.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/05/fixing-mysql-warning-message_4782.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After restoring databases from one server to another I sometimes get this error on Ubuntu or Debian:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;error: &amp;#39;Access denied for user &amp;#39;debian-sys-maint&amp;#39;@&amp;#39;localhost&amp;#39; (using password: YES)&amp;#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This makes a lot of sense, and the solution is pretty simple. If you look in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cat /etc/mysql/debian.cnf
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll see the defaults for your system. Copy the password listed there, and open a connection to MySQL as root (or some other user). Next, enter this (lets say your password specified in debian.cnf was &amp;lsquo;abracadabra&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operation Field</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/04/operation-field_8222.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/04/operation-field_8222.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is time for a new project. I&amp;rsquo;ve finally decided I want to do some electronics stuff - at least play around in that realm a little. However, I want to &amp;ldquo;get out and about&amp;rdquo; a little as well, so this leads me to my idea: a controllable long-range RC plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been debating whether to go the embedded Linux route, or the more simple microcontroller route. One of the first things I stumbled upon was &lt;a href=&#34;http://diydrones.com/profiles/blog/show?id=705844%3ABlogPost%3A44814&#34;&gt;ArduPilot&lt;/a&gt;, a cheap Arduino-based board allowing for a UAV. However, after looking through the requirements I would have needed to purchase an RF transmitter, and they aren&amp;rsquo;t cheap. This made me rethink the ArduPilot route and to evaluate what I really wanted to do: control the plan. My ultimate goal is to attach a joystick to my computer and be able to control the RC plane. This presents another problem with the ArduPilot, however, as there isn&amp;rsquo;t an extra Rx pin available on the ArduPilot board (or so the forums say), I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to transmit coordinates on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>True Consolidation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/04/true-consolidation_6503.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/04/true-consolidation_6503.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2000 I managed to acquire several retired systems to bring to Uni: this included 4-5 cheap P120 machines. At the time, I thought this was great; I had an OpenBSD box as my gateway, a FreeBSD box, a few Linux boxes, and likely something else that doesn&amp;rsquo;t even exist now. The school has a superfast connection, unlimited bandwidth, and I was curious. Although I didn&amp;rsquo;t really have &lt;em&gt;time&lt;/em&gt;, I still managed to install and have all these servers running from my room.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Files between ESX and Linux via NFS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/03/files-between-esx-and-linux-via-nfs_6022.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/03/files-between-esx-and-linux-via-nfs_6022.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like ESX. I like Linux. It is absurdly easy to configure Linux as an NFS server and mount it in ESXIi).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Installed NFS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I currently use Ubuntu Server for my home lab, but the process is basically the same for Red Hat and derivatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install nfs-common
sudo apt-get install nfs-kernel-server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, configure NFS so it can server your local LAN. Normally you would list only specific servers, but, well, we&amp;rsquo;re being cheap and dirty today. Open /etc/exports in VI or your editor of choice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renaming Apache Log Locations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/01/renaming-apache-log-locations_1724.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2009 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/01/renaming-apache-log-locations_1724.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I realized a few of my log files were growing unusually large, and even worse, logrotate was skipping them. I took a look in logrotate.d and straight away realized why: I had created silly names for the log file. logrotate look for .log files, but I had specified mine as .log &amp;ndash; e.g. kelvinism_access_log. I was as familiar with logrotate when I set up the domains, so set forth to get them in the rotation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beginning Scripting ESXi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/01/beginning-scripting-esxi_6126.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/01/beginning-scripting-esxi_6126.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not impressed too often with much software, especially the closed source kind. I find a leaning preference to all things FOSS. If I had a million dollars, I&amp;rsquo;d likely spend all day contributing to all the projects I wish I had time to contribute to. Regardless, there are a select few closed-source products that I believe are truly excellent. I mean, the type of software where you aren&amp;rsquo;t asking &amp;ldquo;I wish this could do this&amp;rdquo; and start asking &amp;ldquo;I wonder what else this can do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alexa Thumbnail Service</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/alexa-thumbnail-service_3160.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/alexa-thumbnail-service_3160.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon offers some pretty cool services: S3, EC2, Alexa Site Thumbnail, and others. A while back I wanted to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/ast/&#34;&gt;AST&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.djangoproject.com&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;, so ended up writing the Python bindings to the REST API (they didn&amp;rsquo;t previously exist. I even wrote up a quick &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/howtos/alexa-site-thumbnail-and-django/&#34;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Amazon no longer maintains AST. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/tech-blog/rip-old-sites/&#34;&gt;archive&lt;/a&gt; a few of the old sites, so no longer need to take thumbnails. However, a few other thumbnail services seem to have crept up, including &lt;a href=&#34;http://snapcasa.com/&#34;&gt;SnapCasa&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.websnapr.com/&#34;&gt;WebSnapr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charting the Hackers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/charting-hackers_7870.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/charting-hackers_7870.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A normal internet connection gets attacked, a lot. The majority of attacks are of the form &amp;ldquo;hello, anybody there?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; where most people just don&amp;rsquo;t answer. But sometimes, just sometimes, the question gets an answer. Depending on the answer, the attacker will start to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks back I was a little bored and started fiddling. I wanted to play with my Cisco, but also wanted to play with OSSEC, but also has a GIS craving. In the end I decided to create a map of the people who ask, &amp;ldquo;hello&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NetFlow into MySQL with flow-tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/netflow-into-mysql-with-flow-tools_5439.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/netflow-into-mysql-with-flow-tools_5439.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been side-tracked on another little project, and keep coming back to NetFlow. For this project I&amp;rsquo;ll need to access NetFlow data with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.djangoproject.com&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;, but this is a bit tricky. First, I&amp;rsquo;m sort of lazy when it comes to my own project; maybe not lazy, I just like taking the most direct route. The most up-to-date NetFlow collector I noticed was &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/flow-tools/&#34;&gt;flow-tools&lt;/a&gt;, and there is even a switch to export the information into MySQL. Sweet! However, I wanted to insert the flows into MySQL automatically, or at least on a regular basis. I first started writing a python script that would do the job, but after a few minutes noticed flow-capture had a rotate_program switch, and started investigating. Since I somehow couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anywhere instructions how to insert the data automatically, here&amp;rsquo;s what I came up with:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zenoss Default Password</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/zenoss-default-password_1357.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/zenoss-default-password_1357.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve evaluated Zenoss before, but forgot the default password, and searching for it didn&amp;rsquo;t come up with anything quickly. I tried everything under the sun: password, 1234, admin, God, Sex, but alas, grep to the rescue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;kelvin@monitor:/usr/local/zenoss/zenoss/etc$ grep admin \*
hubpasswd:admin:zenoss
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Update: it is listed on page 4 of the Admin PDF :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install ESX from a USB (no CDROM)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/install-esx-from-usb-no-cdrom_3723.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/install-esx-from-usb-no-cdrom_3723.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My little server doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a cdrom, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to actually run ESX from a USB (i.e. esx-on-a-stick). Here are my notes of configuring a flash disk to boot the ESX installer (so you can install it onto a local disk). For this demo, my USB is /dev/sdb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install the syslinux utils to your computer (apt-get install syslinux mboot)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install the MBR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo install-mbr /dev/sdb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy all the files from the ISO to your fat32 formated partition&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrating large disks into ESXi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/migrating-large-disks-into-esxi_4692.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/migrating-large-disks-into-esxi_4692.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had the need to move a rather large (450GB) VMDK file from an external hard drive into ESXi. Since ESXi doesn&amp;rsquo;t support external hard drives, this makes things quite a bit more difficult. At first I tried using SCP to copy the file over (after enabling SSH access for ESXi). However, when I tried to do this the time left was almost 20 hours &amp;ndash; a tad too long!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenFiler Permission Issue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/openfiler-permission-issue_2907.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/openfiler-permission-issue_2907.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had issues before with OpenFiler where doesn&amp;rsquo;t update the permissions, although they appear correct in the UI. To rectify that, I stumbled upon a one liner that fixed it. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a group called &amp;ldquo;Trusted&amp;rdquo; that you want to have full access to your music folder. Here&amp;rsquo;s the one-liner:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;\[root@files data\]# pwd
/mnt/openfiler/data
root@files data\]# setfacl --recursive -m u:nobody:rwx,g:Trusted:rwx music
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speeding Up VMWare Server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/speeding-up-vmware-server_791.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/speeding-up-vmware-server_791.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found VMWare Server to have very slow I/O, and sought to improve it. Below are a list of tests I performed, the change, and the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  
  
\### Host OS ###  
/dev/sdb1:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:  220 MB in  3.05 seconds =  72.17 MB/sec  
kelvin@gorilla:~$ sudo hdparm -t /dev/sdb1  
  
/dev/sdb1:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:  266 MB in  3.01 seconds =  88.33 MB/sec  
kelvin@gorilla:~$ sudo hdparm -t /dev/sdb1  
  
/dev/sdb1:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:  310 MB in  3.01 seconds = 102.99 MB/sec  
  
  
\### Before Changes ###  
  
/dev/mapper/openfiler-data:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:    8 MB in  3.36 seconds =   2.38 MB/sec  
\[root@files etc\]# hdparm -t /dev/mapper/openfiler-data  
  
/dev/mapper/openfiler-data:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:   24 MB in  3.63 seconds =   6.61 MB/sec  
\[root@files etc\]# hdparm -t /dev/mapper/openfiler-data  
  
/dev/mapper/openfiler-data:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:   28 MB in  4.54 seconds =   6.16 MB/sec  
  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I made several changes, but the changes that seemed to have the most impact are below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating OSSEC with Cisco IOS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/integrating-ossec-with-cisco-ios_7061.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/integrating-ossec-with-cisco-ios_7061.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I rank OSSEC as one of my favorite pieces of open source software, and finally decided to play around with it more in my own free time. (Yup, I do this sort of stuff for &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt;). My goal was quite simple: send syslog packets from my Cisco to my &amp;ldquo;proxy&amp;rdquo; server, running OSSEC. I found that, although OSSEC supports Cisco IOS logging, it didn&amp;rsquo;t really work. In fact, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any examples or articles of anybody actually getting it to work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Django with SQL Server and IIS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/using-django-with-sql-server-and-iis_4115.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/using-django-with-sql-server-and-iis_4115.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you can tell from reading some of the other pages, I like Linux and open source. But I also like to answer the question &amp;ldquo;what if&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; This post is my [brief] run down of answering &amp;ldquo;what if I could run Django on Server 2003 with SQL Server and IIS.&amp;rdquo; Why, you may ask? To be honest with you, at this point, I don&amp;rsquo;t really know. One of the deciding factors was seeing that the django-mssql project maintains support for inspectdb, which means I could take a stock 2003 server running SQL Server, inspect the DB, and build a web app on top of it. The Django docs offer a lengthy &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.djangoproject.com/wiki/DjangoOnWindowsWithIISAndSQLServer&#34;&gt;howto&lt;/a&gt; for using Django with IIS and SQL Server, but the website for PyISAPIe seems to have been down for the last month or so. Without further delay, below are my notes on installing Django with SQL Server and IIS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Cisco Wireless Firmware</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/upgrading-cisco-wireless-firmware_3066.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/upgrading-cisco-wireless-firmware_3066.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m always forgetting the exact string to enter at the CLI for updating the IOS on a wireless Cisco AP, so I&amp;rsquo;ll just put it here to end my future searches:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Chimp# archive download-sw /force-reload /overwrite tftp://192.168.83.150/c1100-k9w7-tar.123-8.JEC1.tar
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;192.168.83.150 obviously being your tftp server, and the .tar file sitting in the root of the tftp server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose if you wanted to backup your IOS you could do something along the lines of:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backup OpenFiler to S3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/backup-openfiler-to-s3_9140.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/backup-openfiler-to-s3_9140.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Backing up your Openfiler box to S3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I don&amp;rsquo;t think most pople would expect to backup their entire NAS/SAN to Amazon&amp;rsquo;s S3, there might be a few very crucial things you need to backup. For instance, my girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s PhD papers and data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen an implementation using Ruby and s3sync &amp;ndash; something that I do on my server &amp;ndash; but I&amp;rsquo;m trying to migrate everything to Python. Although there are a lot of great tools out there for S3, many of them Python-based, I wanted to do one thing and do it well: have one complete full backup available, and using as little bandwidth as possible. In these regards Duplicity would work well, except I wanted the ability to browse the S3 store using any other tool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure Timevault to Remote Server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/configure-timevault-to-remote-server_2418.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/configure-timevault-to-remote-server_2418.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using TimeVault with a shared drive as a backend is actually quite easy, but it does require a few special things setup. Note: this is gonna be a brief summary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install samba-tools, smbfs&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install samba-tools smbfs
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot more other stuff may install as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a script that mounts your samba share. You could also do this in fstab, but I tend to suspend my laptop when I come home, and I like clicking buttons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PyGTK &#43; py2exe for Windows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/pygtk-py2exe-for-windows_8282.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/pygtk-py2exe-for-windows_8282.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing down these quick notes so I can remember the steps for getting py2exe to work with GTK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download the GTK+ runtime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download py2exe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy over your project into the windows box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a setup.py file (see below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &amp;ldquo;c:\Python25\python.exe setup.py py2exe&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy over the lib, etc, and share folder from C:\Program Files\GTK2-Runtime into the dist folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run app!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;setup.py:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;from distutils.core import setup
import py2exe

setup(
name = &amp;#39;ploteq&amp;#39;,
description = &amp;#39;Bunnys Plotting Tool&amp;#39;,
version = &amp;#39;1.0&amp;#39;,

windows = \[
{
&amp;#39;script&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;ploteq.py&amp;#39;,
}
\],

options = {
&amp;#39;py2exe&amp;#39;: {
&amp;#39;packages&amp;#39;:&amp;#39;encodings&amp;#39;,
&amp;#39;includes&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;cairo, pango, pangocairo, atk, gobject&amp;#39;, 
}
},

data\_files=\[
&amp;#39;ploteq.glade&amp;#39;,
\]
)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slope Finder for the Missus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/slope-finder-for-missus_5304.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/slope-finder-for-missus_5304.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I do sysadminy stuff all day, I don&amp;rsquo;t really get a chance to do much coding (or not as much of a chance as I would like). You can imagine my joy when my girlfriend expressed a problem she needed solved: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to need to solve 100s of slope equations, i.e. where two lines intersect. Can you write a program to do it?&amp;rdquo; Sure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked if she wanted to do a batch input or just a one-off type of deal, she decided on the latter. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve done a fair bit of PyGTK stuff, I had never actually needed to convert it to Windows. I debated using IronPython &amp;ndash; but needed to use a special library to help solve the equations (I&amp;rsquo;m lazy).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capped Internet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/capped-internet_4903.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/capped-internet_4903.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve lived in several different parts of the world, and they all do internet differently. Back in the US I had 8Mb/sec cable (leaving just before Fios was really an option, darn!) In New Zealand, for instance, I was paying for &amp;ldquo;high speed ADSL&amp;rdquo; rated at 1.5Mb/256k. Vrooom. Up in Taiwan I was paying 1/2 what I paid in New Zealand, but for 12Mb/1Mb. Down to Sydney and we have a rated 24Mb/1Mb.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revised mod_tile Install HOWTO</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/revised-modtile-install-howto_1369.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/revised-modtile-install-howto_1369.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the laundry list of things I did while creating a mod_tile VMware appliance based on Ubuntu Server 8.04. I&amp;rsquo;ve kept descriptions limited but left all the commands in. Let&amp;rsquo;s start installing things&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful goodies for compiling source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get build-essential
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More goodies for Mapnik + Friends&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install libboost-dev libboost-filesystem-dev libboost-filesystem1.34.1 libboost-iostreams-dev libboost-iostreams1.34.1 libboost-program-options-dev libboost-program-options1.34.1 libboost-python-dev libboost-python1.34.1 libboost-regex-dev libboost-regex1.34.1 libboost-serialization-dev libboost-serialization1.34.1 libboost-thread-dev libboost-thread1.34.1 libicu-dev libicu38 libstdc++5 libstdc++5-3.3-dev python2.5-dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo aptitude install libfreetype6 libfreetype6-dev libjpeg62 libjpeg62-dev libltdl3 libltdl3-dev libpng12-0 libpng12-dev libtiff4 libtiff4-dev libtiffxx0c2 python-imaging python-imaging-dbg proj
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo aptitude install libcairo2 libcairo2-dev python-cairo python-cairo-dev libcairomm-1.0-1 libcairomm-1.0-dev libglib2.0-0 libpixman-1-0 libpixman-1-dev libpthread-stubs0 libpthread-stubs0-dev ttf-dejavu ttf-dejavu-core ttf-dejavu-extra
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo aptitude install libgdal-dev python2.5-gdal postgresql-8.3-postgis postgresql-8.3 postgresql-server-dev-8.3 postgresql-contrib-8.3
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo aptitude install libxslt1.1 libxslt1-dev libxml2-dev libxml2 gdal-bin libgeos-dev libbz2-dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo aptitude install apache2 apache2-threaded-dev apache2-mpm-prefork apache2-utils
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo aptitude install subversion
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This checks out the mapnik source:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Raw Disks with VMware Server 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/using-raw-disks-with-vmware-server-2_3562.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/using-raw-disks-with-vmware-server-2_3562.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For various reasons I had the need to open a raw disk inside VMware Server 2. The reports from the field say that this just isn&amp;rsquo;t supported. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t need to actually run a raw disk, I needed to get some data off it &amp;ndash; 400GB worth. It turns out &amp;rsquo;not supported&amp;rsquo; really means &amp;rsquo;not in the UI.&amp;rsquo; I don&amp;rsquo;t know the reason why it isn&amp;rsquo;t in the UI, maybe marketing wants people to use ESX, or maybe the UI guys fell behind with their workload.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VM Automatic Startup in Server 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/vm-automatic-startup-in-server-2_6579.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/vm-automatic-startup-in-server-2_6579.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think possibly one of the most practical upgrades in VMware Server 2 appears to be the ability to automatically turn on virtual machines in a stagnated order. I have fond memories of turning on a server with 10 virtual machines, and when they all turn on at once, the hard disk grinds to a halt. This forced me to turn on the machines manually afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;+1 VMware in my books.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 8.04 64-Bit and VMware Server 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/ubuntu-804-64-bit-and-vmware-server-2_1451.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/ubuntu-804-64-bit-and-vmware-server-2_1451.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I now have successful installation of VMware Server 2 (Beta RC1) on top of Ubuntu 8.04 64-bit. I have been using various virtualization technologies for years, and VMware is usually the easiest to install and configure. So far, VMware Server 2 RC1, has proven to be the exception to the rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I am very excited by the direction VMware is taking &amp;ndash; this new server version looks to have great potential.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware Tools in VMware Server 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/vmware-tools-in-vmware-server-2_6233.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/vmware-tools-in-vmware-server-2_6233.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Installing the tools in VMware Server 2 is a little different than Workstation or the previous versions of VMware Server. Under the Summary tab of your Virtual Machine, look for a link that says &amp;ldquo;Install VMware Tools&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; click it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait for &amp;lsquo;Success&amp;rsquo; to show up on the bottom, and jump into your virtual machine. Mount the tools as so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mount /dev/cdrom /media/cdrom
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;And install as normal (copy the .tar.gz to /usr/src, extract it, install it). Easy peasy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GUI to Plot Driving Speed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/05/gui-to-plot-driving-speed_6997.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/05/gui-to-plot-driving-speed_6997.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I needed another Python fix, and I need one pretty badly. I spent the weekend wondering why it appears to be impossible to edit the GUIDs inside an Exchange mailbox store (read: NOT the GUIDs stored in AD for Exchange). Anyways, I digress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goals were simple. I wanted to use Python, wanted something to do with traffic, and wanted to play around with Glade/PyGTK and graphing stuff. My end result was a little app that allows you to specify a GPX file, and it plots the waypoints (and calculates the moving average!). Pretty simple, pretty useless, but pretty fun. I really do like pretty pictures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another Baby Step</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/another-baby-step_1340.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/another-baby-step_1340.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I showed a few of my co-workers my graph and one replied &amp;ndash; oh! that&amp;rsquo;s really cool. (I think only two of my co-workers are actually interested in my geekyness). He then emailed me tonight a .kmz file containing a colorized file of his speed. I looked at the kml and noticed it appeared to be dynamically allocated judging by the top speed. Well, as you could guess, I surely had to modify my code to include colors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Event vs. DOM Driven Parsing of XML</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/event-vs-dom-driven-parsing-of-xml_6678.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/event-vs-dom-driven-parsing-of-xml_6678.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently have been &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/tech-blog/baby-steps-graphing-traffic/&#34;&gt;playing&lt;/a&gt; with parsing GPX files and spitting out the results into a special KML file. I initially wrote a parser using minidom, yet after running this the first time &amp;ndash; and my Core2Duo laptop reaching 100% utilization for 10 seconds &amp;ndash; I realized I needed to re-write it using something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a little time reading the different parsers for XML and eventually read more about &lt;a href=&#34;http://effbot.org/zone/celementtree.htm&#34;&gt;cElementTree&lt;/a&gt;. And it is included with Python2.5, sweet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Windows 2003 as an NTP Client</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/setting-up-windows-2003-as-ntp-client_4269.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/setting-up-windows-2003-as-ntp-client_4269.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had to search for the commands to setup a Windows 2003 box as an ntp client a few times now, so have decided to finally write them down here for my own good measure. Funny thing is, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure there are three ways to setup a 2003 box as an ntp client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-via-the-cli&#34;&gt;1) Via the CLI&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open up the cmd prompt and type in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;w32tm /config /manualpeerlist:&amp;#34;0.pool.ntp.org 1.pool.ntp.org 2.pool.ntp.org 3.pool.ntp.org&amp;#34; 
/syncfromflags:MANUAL /reliable:YES /update
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-via-the-cli-option-2&#34;&gt;2) Via the CLI, option 2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;net time setsntp: &amp;#34;0.pool.ntp.org 1.pool.ntp.org 2.pool.ntp.org 3.pool.ntp.org&amp;#34;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-via-gui&#34;&gt;3) Via GUI&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type in &lt;strong&gt;gpedit.msc&lt;/strong&gt; and your local GPO editor will pop up. Go to the folder as indicated in the below screenshot and Enable the &amp;ldquo;Enable Windows NTP Client&amp;rdquo; option. Next set the &amp;ldquo;Configure Windows NTP Client&amp;rdquo; option to whatever time servers you so choose. As always, make sure to keep the 0x1 at the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baby Steps at Graphing Traffic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/baby-steps-at-graphing-traffic_522.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/baby-steps-at-graphing-traffic_522.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;br&gt;
You can likely tell that I&amp;rsquo;ve been having some fun with graphing and mapping recently. I was reading a few articles about GIS and stumbled upon a pretty darn cool project at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webopticon.com/projects/neighborhood_nets&#34;&gt;Webopticon&lt;/a&gt;, which included cool pictures. I showed it to my girlfriend thinking she would find it interesting, and then realized: oh! KML has an altitude attribute. That could be interesting.&lt;br&gt;
One of my projects is to create &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/2007/12/sydneys-driving-habits.html&#34;&gt;maps of Sydney&amp;rsquo;s traffic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, so I have been experimenting heavily with Mapnik and OSM. I figured I could have some fun and finally parse some gps tracks and display the data.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/bkhs8KqkZyS7yIoA6AeNnA?feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi8Ju2Qv3TAIupmzBjORZ5wUBGjxIlwZ_0mrPb0Mku5Yob6_ldYEmtRO0GP_kQ62-aZDZ3fP8_vh6nfXv9NpP5X98oneS25YXXf9Tr-pD1RMkp7l_jbDBWBsqxrA5hIDhH8KvfVjZI0TvGc/s288/gpstracks3.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a Mapnik Server on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/setting-up-mapnik-server-on-ubuntu_118.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/setting-up-mapnik-server-on-ubuntu_118.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, we go ahead and install the needed packages. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to include &amp;ldquo;my&amp;rdquo; list of packages that were needed to get a vanilla 7.10 image up to steam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install build-essential libltdl3-dev autoconf libtool automake \\
postgresql postgresql-8.2-postgis postgresql-server-dev-8.2 \\
wget subversion libboost-python1.34.1 libboost-thread-dev \\
libboost-program-options-dev libboost-regex-dev \\
libboost-python-dev libboost-serialization-dev \\
libboost-filesystem-dev libpng12-dev libjpeg62-dev \\
libtiff4-dev zlib1g-dev libfreetype6-dev libgeos-dev \\
unzip apache2-prefork-dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next we start to download a few components. I did this in my home directory, /home/kelvin&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redirecting Fun with Lightty</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/redirecting-fun-with-lightty_330.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/redirecting-fun-with-lightty_330.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two of my colleagues were having just a little bit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/blog/Australia/i-caught-fish/#c1926&#34;&gt;too much fun&lt;/a&gt; with my blog, so I decided to have some fun back. Over a period of 10 minutes, they managed to leave 10+ comments. Luckily I have full control over my server, and was able to quickly create my practical joke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$HTTP\[&amp;#34;remoteip&amp;#34;\] == &amp;#34;123.45.678.910&amp;#34; {
url.redirect = (
&amp;#34;^/(.\*)&amp;#34; =&amp;gt; &amp;#34;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=annoying+fuck&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;&amp;#34; =&amp;gt; &amp;#34;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=annoying+fuck&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;/&amp;#34; =&amp;gt; &amp;#34;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=annoying+fuck&amp;#34;
)
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Installing mod_tile for Mapnik</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/notes-on-installing-modtile-for-mapnik_168.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/notes-on-installing-modtile-for-mapnik_168.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have no idea if these notes on how to install mod_tile will be useful for anybody. The current readme states that you need to edit the source code, but never actually where. Well, this is where, at least until the code can either take switches or can auto-configure itself. This is quite brief, so if you need more details, shoot me an email or leave a comment. I have repeated this process on two Ubuntu 7.10 machines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ethX Issues with Xen and Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/ethx-issues-with-xen-and-ubuntu_2003.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/ethx-issues-with-xen-and-ubuntu_2003.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My new guest VMs under Xen seem to be having issues where upon each reboot, the network interface gets incremented by 1. For instance, it starts at eth0, then goes to eth1, then eth2, and eventually ethX. There are two issues to fix: 1) get the count back to 0, and 2) stop it from counting again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to get them to decrease by looking in the /etc/udev/rules.d/70-persistent-net.rules file and removing all entries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Mapnik on Ubuntu 7.10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/installing-mapnik-on-ubuntu-710_6688.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/installing-mapnik-on-ubuntu-710_6688.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have managed to install mapnik 0.4, 0.5, 0.5.1 and various SVN releases in-between on Ubuntu. While this isn&amp;rsquo;t in itself exciting, I think I manage to stumble at every installation. I typically forget to add the flags when building, so, to prevent myself from stumbling again, I&amp;rsquo;m going to write them out here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build mapnik&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ python scons/scons.py PYTHON=/usr/bin/python \\ 

PGSQL\_INCLUDES=/usr/include/postgresql \\

PGSQL\_LIBS=/usr/lib/postgresql BOOST\_INCLUDES=/usr/include/boost BOOST\_LIBS=/usr/lib
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then install it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo python scons/scons.py install PYTHON=/usr/bin/python \\ 

PGSQL\_INCLUDES=/usr/include/postgresql \\

PGSQL\_LIBS=/usr/lib/postgresql BOOST\_INCLUDES=/usr/include/boost BOOST\_LIBS=/usr/lib
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then proceed as normal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>And Yet Another Remodel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/03/and-yet-another-remodel_7848.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/03/and-yet-another-remodel_7848.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have finally decided to do another remodel of this site. I had a few goals before starting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use one image&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the YUI-CSS framework&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Django&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make it easily extendable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve accomplished these goals. The site is easier to read, easy to modify, and has a few new features. More entries to come!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Database Woopsie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/02/database-woopsie_863.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/02/database-woopsie_863.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I returned to my computer today to notice I had the following error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;(145, &amp;#34;Table &amp;#39;./databasename/comments\_freecomment&amp;#39; is marked as crashed and should be repaired&amp;#34;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, crap. The solution is quite easy, however:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mysqlcheck -uUsername -pPassword databasename comments\_freecomment
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now you know what you already know, you can fix it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mysqlcheck -r -uUsername -pPassword databasename comments\_freecomment
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;If that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, you can try a slightly different method. First, go to the location where your databases are stored on the disk (most likely something like /var/lib/mysql/databasename). Next, stop the database &amp;ndash; and try to free up as much memory as possible. Then run:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPS on the SkypePhone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/02/gps-on-skypephone_9589.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/02/gps-on-skypephone_9589.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I was sort of curious if I could use my 3 Skypephone in a pinch if I got lost, which here in Sydney, happens quite often. Luckily 3&amp;rsquo;s Skypephone has both Bluetooth, and supports j2me apps. Mobile GPS unit, here I come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/3AY6h-qKwGk9NpnB9hrwsw?feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjExWMS7zKJdGCG_1MHdpb900yTseLCrbHerf2PlfzwSouqfnmJHr5V1jiIcDcbMrEul2OZUFlCYOQhTgrq_3C-cYDWmxkx-yDOr6NNwokX8P-gUikt3DSjxRi11qJrMuP4_aSRLpjhLPax/s288/DSC03368.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recipe to get maps on your Skypephone is pretty darn easy. You&amp;rsquo;ll need one dash bluetooth GPS receiver (I have the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.qstarz.com/Products/GPS%20Products/BT-Q1000.html&#34;&gt;Qstarz BT-Q1000&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&#34;http://linuxtechs.net/kruch/tb/forum/index.php&#34;&gt;TrekBuddy&lt;/a&gt;, a TrekBuddy acceptable map (&lt;a href=&#34;http://osm.bandnet.org/browse/?1,1,1,0&#34;&gt;easily downloadable&lt;/a&gt;), and one dab computer &amp;ndash; but since you&amp;rsquo;re reading this, I figure you&amp;rsquo;ve got that part taken care of.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size of Uncompressed OSM File</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/01/size-of-uncompressed-osm-file_95.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/01/size-of-uncompressed-osm-file_95.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openstreetmap.com&#34;&gt;OSM&lt;/a&gt; a little lately, and have been meaning to construct my own slippy map. At first I wanted to do it on my VPS &amp;ndash; but with rather limited storage, and even more limited memory, there just isn&amp;rsquo;t a way. Three problems exists: the first occurs when trying to use osm2pgsql to import the OSM file into the database. Current records state that this typically uses 650+ MB, something my 512MB VPS just doesn&amp;rsquo;t have (although I&amp;rsquo;m writing some code that might make this possible in the future).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Distcc</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/01/using-distcc_1425.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/01/using-distcc_1425.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of working on one of my projects, and the requirement came up to download a fairly large file (4GB). Since I only receive ~20GB/month at my house, I decided to just use my server in the U.S. The next requirement came about needing to compile Mapnik, which I had intended to do on the server at some point anyways, yet I ran into memory constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good old distcc comes to the rescue. I don&amp;rsquo;t need to use distcc that often, yet when I do, it is very handy. However, I always forget to set g++ to use distcc as well. So, for when I forget next time&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sydney&#39;s Driving Habits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/12/sydneys-driving-habits.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2007 20:20:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/12/sydneys-driving-habits.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that Sydney is one of the most liveable cities in the entire world &amp;ndash; a statement I would generally agree with. However. whoever made this statement obviously didn&amp;rsquo;t drive to work every day. I&amp;rsquo;ve reached the conclusion that one of the biggest (and only) drawbacks to Sydney, is the traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; is the traffic this bad? I have a few theories. The first theory is that Sydney drivers aren&amp;rsquo;t particularly cordial. I mean, the road could be ending on the merging lane and drivers still won&amp;rsquo;t let you in. I&amp;rsquo;ve literally sat for two blocks in near deadlock traffic with my blinker on, and nobody would let me in. Combine this with the fact that whoever designed Sydney&amp;rsquo;s roads was drunk at the time (roads that suddenly veer off to one side, other roads that go from three lanes to one, roads that steer around a park causing 20 minute delays, or roads always having a bottleneck whilst crossing the rail tracks, etc.,). This plays a role in how everybody typically drives &amp;ndash; they drive &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; close to each other. I don&amp;rsquo;t just mean tailgating, it is something else. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to quite a few cities in the world, and I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen people drive so close to each other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small Business Server 2003</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/12/small-business-server-2003_4192.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/12/small-business-server-2003_4192.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been hired for a company that does consulting for small businesses. Naturally, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had a huge exposure to SBS. My employer asked me to take the SBS MCP Certification, and this afternoon, I passed. The exam was pretty easy &amp;ndash; I think Microsoft basically took the easy questions spread out across the MCSE and dumped them into the SBS exam (some of the questions were very similar). My tips to anybody taking the exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zenity GUI to a Shell Script</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/10/zenity-gui-to-shell-script_5432.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/10/zenity-gui-to-shell-script_5432.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/whbV2vHNOr5d7pvO8qsgRw?feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEigBFNcFKSB9lKhJPiSiwDlp9q9SmO2yEu9v343B1M-2NFN5s2cJ-cUji8qR3LW1CmmitKztwUh3QxLAIjkSMYio5lIwhX1GszzhfZnufjrxugrWTNSZLH06e-qxV4ldttqBMDRBPWfXlc4/s800/zenityss.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty lazy. I don&amp;rsquo;t (ironically) like to type, and I really don&amp;rsquo;t like typing the same command over and over. I found myself switching between my external monitor and laptop quite frequently, and decided to somewhat automate the task. Although I know there are other programs out there that allow this, they either had too many features, or crashed. Xrandr works just fine, but like I said, I&amp;rsquo;m lazy&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass Spam Delete Django</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/10/mass-spam-delete-django_8712.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/10/mass-spam-delete-django_8712.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you can read, I&amp;rsquo;ve been traveling around quite a bit lately. This means I haven&amp;rsquo;t been checking the comments on my blog, which means quite a bit of spam has been entered. I am blocking the spam via akismet, however, it is still recorded in the database. Being somebody who hates cluttered desktops, you can imagine how I feel about having a lot (447) of spam. Well, since akismet flips the is_public switch True for good comments and False for bad comments, that makes a &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; easy query in mysql.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Works With Windows Vista</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/07/works-with-windows-vista_392.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/07/works-with-windows-vista_392.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in Tibet right now, so will keep this somewhat brief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the next few hours I&amp;rsquo;ll be sitting in this dingy internet cafe in Lhasa updating my blog with my travels. I happened to look down and on the monitor it says &amp;ldquo;works with windows vista&amp;rdquo;. I find this quite humorous, &lt;em&gt;of course&lt;/em&gt; it is going to work with vista, it is a normal generic monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, I guess there is a reason for marketing. Back to writing our travels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Last Xenful Comments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/last-xenful-comments_2649.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/last-xenful-comments_2649.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest things I regret is not utilizing Xen more. I&amp;rsquo;ve finally been admitted to Amazon&amp;rsquo;s EC2 Limited Beta, just two days before I leave, so not enough time to actually do anything fun. However, I think Xen is an ideal infrastructure aid for SMEs in particular. The cost of technology is continuing to decrease, which means bigger servers cost less. This is great for the small/branch office. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Portable Travel Stick</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/my-portable-travel-stick_1543.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/my-portable-travel-stick_1543.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This will be my last post from Taiwan, and I&amp;rsquo;m placing it in my tech section. Shortly I will be flying to Hong Kong, and then traveling into China. I&amp;rsquo;m not bringing my laptop with me. I&amp;rsquo;m always a little wary of using public computers, especially in many of the poorly run internet cafes. Often the logged in user is the administrator, and we all know the computers are obviously crawling with worms and keyloggers. What can I do?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenMoko In Person</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/openmoko-in-person_6379.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/openmoko-in-person_6379.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago I had the privilege of meeting up with some of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openmoko.org&#34;&gt;OpenMoko&lt;/a&gt; guys. You&amp;rsquo;ve seen me write a little bit about this project, but meeting them and actually getting to play with a device was quite enlightening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most foreigners in Taipei take taxis, but not I. My girlfriend gave me a rough estimate how to go to FIC headquarters, yet it was &amp;ndash; rough. I jumped on the right bus, going the right direction, yet didn&amp;rsquo;t really know where to get off. In my broken Chinese I started talking to a group of high school kids, who somewhat pointed me in the right direction. At one point we were coming up to a light and a lady just said: &amp;ldquo;get off, go down that road.&amp;rdquo; I grabbed my bag and jumped off the bus. The street signs started to resemble the characters I had written down, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know which direction to go in. I asked a travel agency, and they pointed me in the right direction &amp;ndash; and then it started to rain. I luckily found FIC without getting too wet, and quickly met Sean, the project leader for OpenMoko.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IIS7 GoLive Program</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/iis7-golive-program_3958.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/iis7-golive-program_3958.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can easily see that I am a big Linux fan, I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned this over and over. I&amp;rsquo;ve also mentioned that I&amp;rsquo;m finishing up my MCSE, which started as a dare with my buddy, Ian. In the process of studying for my MCSE I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a certain amount of respect for Windows Server 2003, yet I&amp;rsquo;ll comment more on this later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I really wanted to write two paragraphs about was an interesting discovery I made today. I happened to stumble over to Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s hardware site, and noticed in my little Server Spy monitor that it was running IIS/7 &amp;ndash; the first time I have seen this anywhere. Upon further investigation I perused their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iis.net/default.aspx?tabid=7&amp;amp;subtabid=79&#34;&gt;GoLive program&lt;/a&gt;, which details several ways to test drive IIS7. There are some details about Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s setup, which one would expect to be impressive. And it is. So, if you are a Microsoft person, you may want to grab a test drive of Beta3 while you still can.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computex 2007 Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/computex-2007-review_8211.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/computex-2007-review_8211.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The buzz of Computex is finally wearing off, so I&amp;rsquo;ll finally scribe my account of the event. YS was kind enough to go with me, we actually called it a date. The scene was quite similar to the trade shows we saw last year, however there seemed to be fewer people. This might be because we went on the final day, although we suspect there weren&amp;rsquo;t that many people because there aren&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;sweet&amp;rdquo; deals to be had. Regardless, there were several main &amp;ldquo;halls&amp;rdquo; filled full of stuff. The first three (two were in one building) weren&amp;rsquo;t particularly interesting. I mean, there were some cool displays and lots of technology, but nothing that left me thinking &amp;ldquo;oh, that&amp;rsquo;s cool&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;oh, me wanna.&amp;rdquo; Until we hit the last hall.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liferea RSS in Liferea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/liferea-rss-in-liferea_7495.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/liferea-rss-in-liferea_7495.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://community.linux.com/article.pl?sid=07/06/07/1458229&#34;&gt;Linux.com, Liferea was mentioned&lt;/a&gt; I find this particularly because I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Liferea for quite a few months, and haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to find anything that better suits my needs. It sits quietly in the corner until a new RSS is available, and slightly changes color. Plus, it integrates wonderfully into GNOME.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, the Linux.com article does a great job summarizing the reader, so if you are in the market, I&amp;rsquo;d take a look. For posterities sake, I took a screenshot of the Linux.com feed of Liferea, in Liferea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunneling over SSH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/tunneling-over-ssh_6040.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/tunneling-over-ssh_6040.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a rule, whenever I&amp;rsquo;m online I&amp;rsquo;m logged into my server back in the States. I&amp;rsquo;m also usually wireless, which we all know is beyond insecure &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ve found it &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; useful to tunnel firefox over SSH. I try my best to tunnel stuff over SSH back, and if you want to also, this is how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;setup-the-sshsocks-tunnel&#34;&gt;Setup the SSH/SOCKS tunnel&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m on Linux, so this is pretty darn easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh user@domain.com -D 1080
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the SSH daemon runs on a different port, you&amp;rsquo;d do something like this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turn Off Google Suggest in Firefox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/turn-off-google-suggest-in-firefox_857.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/turn-off-google-suggest-in-firefox_857.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I generally like Firefox, and generally like Google. But having Google suggest enabled when I search for things is annoying, at least on my rather small laptop screen. Mostly it is because my internet right now is pretty crap, so I try to cut down on any extra traffic. Anyhow, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even both Googling how to do this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type in &amp;lsquo;about:config&amp;rsquo; into your address bar and type &amp;lsquo;search&amp;rsquo; in the top filter bar. Look about half-way down for this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alexa Site Thumbnail And Django</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/alexa-site-thumbnail-and-django_7479.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/alexa-site-thumbnail-and-django_7479.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, you&amp;rsquo;ve seen how to look up thumbnails &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/howtos/alexa-site-thumbnail-python/&#34;&gt;via python&lt;/a&gt;, but wonder how to integrate this with Django? I created a &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/webthumbs/&#34;&gt;sample app to demonstrate&lt;/a&gt;. One thing to note about this app is it is slightly more complex than just using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/howtos/alexa-site-thumbnail-python/&#34;&gt;previously mentioned&lt;/a&gt; ThumbnailUtility. For starters, the thumbnail is downloaded from Alexa onto the server. Another part is first searching if the thumbnail exists already, and if it does, serving that instead of querying Alexa. Let&amp;rsquo;s just start with some code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alexa Site Thumbnail with Python</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/alexa-site-thumbnail-with-python_803.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/alexa-site-thumbnail-with-python_803.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For one of my sites I needed to get thumbnails, yet &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.amazonwebservices.com/connect/kbcategory.jspa?categoryID=51&#34;&gt;Alexa Site Thumbnail&lt;/a&gt; didn&amp;rsquo;t have any code snippets for Python. Well, no they/you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;thumbnailutilitypy&#34;&gt;ThumbnailUtility.py&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
import base64
import datetime
import hmac
import sha
import sys
import re
import urllib
import xml.dom.minidom

AWS\_ACCESS\_KEY\_ID = &amp;#39;your-access-key-id&amp;#39;
AWS\_SECRET\_ACCESS\_KEY = &amp;#39;your-super-secret-key&amp;#39;

# This one is for an individual thumbnail...
def create\_thumbnail(site\_url, img\_size):
    def generate\_timestamp(dtime):
        return dtime.strftime(&amp;#34;%Y-%m-%dT%H:%M:%SZ&amp;#34;)
    def generate\_signature(operation, timestamp, secret\_access\_key):
        my\_sha\_hmac = hmac.new(secret\_access\_key, operation + timestamp, sha)
        my\_b64\_hmac\_digest = base64.encodestring(my\_sha\_hmac.digest()).strip()
        return my\_b64\_hmac\_digest
    timestamp\_datetime = datetime.datetime.utcnow()
    timestamp\_list = list(timestamp\_datetime.timetuple())
    timestamp\_list\[6\] = 0
    timestamp\_tuple = tuple(timestamp\_list)
    timestamp = generate\_timestamp(timestamp\_datetime)
    signature = generate\_signature(&amp;#39;Thumbnail&amp;#39;, timestamp, AWS\_SECRET\_ACCESS\_KEY)
    parameters = {
        &amp;#39;AWSAccessKeyId&amp;#39;: AWS\_ACCESS\_KEY\_ID,
        &amp;#39;Timestamp&amp;#39;: timestamp,
        &amp;#39;Signature&amp;#39;: signature,
        &amp;#39;Url&amp;#39;: site\_url,
        &amp;#39;Action&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;Thumbnail&amp;#39;,
        &amp;#39;Size&amp;#39;: img\_size,
        }
    url = &amp;#39;http://ast.amazonaws.com/?&amp;#39;
    result\_xmlstr = urllib.urlopen(url, urllib.urlencode(parameters)).read()
    result\_xml = xml.dom.minidom.parseString(result\_xmlstr)
    image\_url = result\_xml.childNodes\[0\].getElementsByTagName(&amp;#39;aws:Thumbnail&amp;#39;)\[0\].firstChild.data
    return image\_url
  
# And this one is for a list
def create\_thumbnail\_list(all\_sites, img\_size):
    def generate\_timestamp(dtime):
        return dtime.strftime(&amp;#34;%Y-%m-%dT%H:%M:%SZ&amp;#34;)
    
    def generate\_signature(operation, timestamp, secret\_access\_key):
        my\_sha\_hmac = hmac.new(secret\_access\_key, operation + timestamp, sha)
        my\_b64\_hmac\_digest = base64.encodestring(my\_sha\_hmac.digest()).strip()
        return my\_b64\_hmac\_digest
    
    timestamp\_datetime = datetime.datetime.utcnow()
    timestamp\_list = list(timestamp\_datetime.timetuple())
    timestamp\_list\[6\] = 0
    timestamp\_tuple = tuple(timestamp\_list)
    timestamp = generate\_timestamp(timestamp\_datetime)
    
    signature = generate\_signature(&amp;#39;Thumbnail&amp;#39;, timestamp, AWS\_SECRET\_ACCESS\_KEY)
    
    image\_loc = {}
    image\_num = \[\]
    image\_size = {}
    
    count = 1   
    for s in all\_sites:
        image\_num = &amp;#39;Thumbnail.%s.Url&amp;#39; % count
        image\_loc\[image\_num\] = s
        count += 1
        
    parameters = {
        &amp;#39;AWSAccessKeyId&amp;#39;: AWS\_ACCESS\_KEY\_ID,
        &amp;#39;Timestamp&amp;#39;: timestamp,
        &amp;#39;Signature&amp;#39;: signature,
        &amp;#39;Action&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;Thumbnail&amp;#39;,
        &amp;#39;Thumbnail.Shared.Size&amp;#39;: img\_size,
        }
        
    parameters.update(image\_loc)
    
    ast\_url = &amp;#39;http://ast.amazonaws.com/?&amp;#39;
        
    result\_xmlstr = urllib.urlopen(ast\_url, urllib.urlencode(parameters)).read()
    result\_xml = xml.dom.minidom.parseString(result\_xmlstr)
    
    image\_urls = \[\]
    count = 0
    for s in all\_sites:
        image\_urls.append(result\_xml.childNodes\[0\].getElementsByTagName(&amp;#39;aws:Thumbnail&amp;#39;)\[count\].firstChild.data)
        count += 1
    return image\_urls
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is how you interact with this code for a single thumbnail:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alexa Site Thumbnail with Python II</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/alexa-site-thumbnail-with-python-ii_629.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/alexa-site-thumbnail-with-python-ii_629.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is how I actually use Alexa Site Thumbnail, and since I&amp;rsquo;min a sharing mood, I&amp;rsquo;ll extend the code your way. In short, this takes the url and searches in STORELOC first, then any urls not already in STORELOC are retrieved and named via a slug. You need to pass two variables to either of these: blog_site.url and blot_site.slug &amp;ndash; since I&amp;rsquo;m using Django, this is naturally how sites are returned after I filter a queryset. What I do is place the call to Alexa as high up the page as I can, and because I&amp;rsquo;ve threaded this, the page can continue to load without waiting for Alexa&amp;rsquo;s response. For instance, let&amp;rsquo;s say you have some model with cool sites, and you want to return the sites filtered by owner&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding Search to Django</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/adding-search-to-django_6300.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/adding-search-to-django_6300.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is fairly well documented in the Django docs, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be brief. This is the the bit of search code I use in almost all of my Django sites, and it works great:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
def search(request):
    from django.db.models import Q
    q = request.GET.get(&amp;#34;q&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;&amp;#34;)
    if q and len(q) &amp;gt;= 3:
        clause = Q(dirtword\_\_icontains=q)               \\
               | Q(description\_\_icontains=q)       \\
               | Q(tags\_\_name\_\_icontains=q)        
        site\_search = Dirt.objects.filter(clause).distinct()
    else:
        site\_search = Dirt.objects.order\_by(&amp;#39;?&amp;#39;)\[:100\]
    return list\_detail.object\_list(
        request              = request,
        queryset             = site\_search,
        template\_name        = &amp;#34;dirty/search.html&amp;#34;,
        template\_object\_name = &amp;#34;dirty&amp;#34;,
        paginate\_by          = 20,
        extra\_context        = {&amp;#34;q&amp;#34; : q},
    )  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;While this should be pretty self-explanatory, the process goes like this: q is taken from the GET request and if it is over three characters long, it is searched for in the dirtword column, through the description and also through the m2m relationship of tags__name. Yup, it is pretty nifty to be able to access relationship in this way (tags__name). You will notice that at the end of each search it says &amp;ldquo;__icontains&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; this simply does a fuzzy search for the word. Once the queryset is created (the filter) I&amp;rsquo;ve added a .distinct() on the end &amp;ndash;this prevents multiple rows from being returned to the template. If there isn&amp;rsquo;t a search, or it isn&amp;rsquo;t long enough, a random list will be returned.&lt;br&gt;
One thing I like to do is include the search as extra_context &amp;ndash; this allows you to say something like &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rsquo;ve searched for&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; at the top of your search. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine implementing a search feature as being any easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Django Syndication with Colddirt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/django-syndication-with-colddirt_5107.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/django-syndication-with-colddirt_5107.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating feeds in Django is freaking simple. I&amp;rsquo;ll start with an example of just updating a feed with the newest objects (for instace, newest blog posts). Similar to the forms.py way of handling our different forms, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a feeds.py to handle the feeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;feedspy&#34;&gt;feeds.py&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
from django.contrib.syndication.feeds import Feed
from colddirt.dirty.models import Dirt

class LatestDirts(Feed):
    title = &amp;#34;Cold Dirt&amp;#34;
    link = &amp;#34;/&amp;#34;
    description = &amp;#34;When you have dirt, you&amp;#39;ve got dirt.  Right...&amp;#34;
    copyright = &amp;#39;All Rights Unreserved&amp;#39;
    
    def items(self):
        return Dirt.objects.all()\[:50\]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;What this will do is query our Dirt DB and return an obj. The fields here are pretty well documented in the Django docs, besides being pretty obvious.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Django Syndication with Colddirt II</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/django-syndication-with-colddirt-ii_3665.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/django-syndication-with-colddirt-ii_3665.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;ve already covered a really simple syndication example, I&amp;rsquo;ll move onto something a little more complex. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to offer syndication that is slightly more custom. The Django &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.djangoproject.com/documentation/syndication_feeds/&#34;&gt;syndication docs&lt;/a&gt; give an example from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.holovaty.com/&#34;&gt;Adrian&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagocrime.org/&#34;&gt;Chicagocrime.org&lt;/a&gt; syndication of beats. I had to ponder a minute to get &amp;ldquo;custom&amp;rdquo; syndication to work, so here&amp;rsquo;s my example from start to finish.&lt;br&gt;
First, as usual, feeds.py&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;feedspy&#34;&gt;feeds.py&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;class PerDirt(Feed):

    link = &amp;#34;/&amp;#34;
    copyright = &amp;#39;Copyright (c) 2007, Blog Mozaic&amp;#39;
    
    def get\_object(self, bits):
        from django.shortcuts import get\_object\_or\_404
        if len(bits) != 1:
            raise ObjectDoesNotExist
        my\_dirt = get\_object\_or\_404(Dirt, slug\_\_exact=bits\[0\])
        return my\_dirt

    def title(self, obj):
        return obj.slug
    
    def description(self, obj):
        return obj.description
    
    def items(self, obj):
        from django.contrib.comments.models import FreeComment
        return FreeComment.objects.filter(object\_id=obj.id).order\_by(&amp;#39;-submit\_date&amp;#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can see that this differs slightly from the simpler syndication example. I&amp;rsquo;ll not a few things. But first, I need to show urls.py:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Django Newforms Usage in Colddirt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/django-newforms-usage-in-colddirt_1103.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/django-newforms-usage-in-colddirt_1103.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hear many complaints and questions about newforms, but I&amp;rsquo;ve personally found it rather easy and logical to use. There are numerous ways for you to use do forms in Django, and most likely the best way to see them all is to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.djangoproject.com/documentation/newforms/&#34;&gt;read the docs&lt;/a&gt;. On the Colddirt demo site, this is how I used newforms. I&amp;rsquo;ll take the index page as an example.&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve accessed the newforms module like so:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple Ajax with Django</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/simple-ajax-with-django_1754.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/simple-ajax-with-django_1754.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, the Django developers, in my opinion, are freaking smart. Instead of bundling Django with a particular library, they have added XML and JSON serialization; us humble users can choose whatever AJAX library we want. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prototypejs.org/&#34;&gt;Prototype 1.5.1&lt;/a&gt; has been pretty fun to work with, so I&amp;rsquo;ll kick off this demo with a really simple example.&lt;br&gt;
How simple? The intended goal is to have the total number of &amp;lsquo;dirts&amp;rsquo; update without user intervention. &lt;em&gt;Laaaammmeee&lt;/em&gt;. If you are a visual type of person, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.colddirt.com/huh/&#34;&gt;take a look&lt;/a&gt; on the Colddirt &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.colddirt.com/huh/&#34;&gt;huh&lt;/a&gt; page. That number automatically increases without user intervention. And this is how.&lt;br&gt;
The process (some pseudocode) will go like this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colddirt Information</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/colddirt-information_1890.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/colddirt-information_1890.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: Colddirt&amp;rsquo;s source code is run from Django SVN, check out on May 10th-ish. If you are using a newer branch, some things have changed. i.e. clean_data has been renamed cleaned_data. Remember to check the &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.djangoproject.com/wiki/BackwardsIncompatibleChanges&#34;&gt;BackwardsIncompatible&lt;/a&gt; page in the wiki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part 1&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/2007/06/simple-ajax-with-django_1754.html&#34;&gt;Simple AJAX with Django&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Part 2&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/2007/06/django-newforms-usage-in-colddirt_1103.html&#34;&gt;Django Newforms Usage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Part 3&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/2007/06/adding-search-to-django_6300.html&#34;&gt;Search with Django&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Part 4&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/2007/06/django-syndication-with-colddirt_5107.html&#34;&gt;Django&amp;rsquo;s Syndication Framework (simple)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Part 5&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/2007/06/django-syndication-with-colddirt-ii_3665.html&#34;&gt;Django&amp;rsquo;s Syndication Framework (little more complex)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kelvinn/colddirt&#34;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt; from Github.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Upgrade</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/ubuntu-upgrade_2905.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/ubuntu-upgrade_2905.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having been in I.T. for quite a few years, upgrading can sometimes be quite a hassle. Having switched to Linux for many years, the crazy upgrade madness of windows is gone. So, how easy is upgrading in Linux?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/gfJ0rsA5-yezsSSBzH5fSQ?feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjgdy7UBLsk4QTB1cYb0IXBmWjq5f4F5CcjYlthEQcPG8lPwKy0aYqu5Gsy30wZhOatB_KxYU0RJPubZVjO78EgQcpBmRi0zakN7fHOek4DmgG9bRj1F-FxP4vpWLmEaJvxLYRq6Qel-W2l/s288/Screenshot-feisty.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/husChXOCHJJ3h1FCRePdlA?feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiT3OQw0WwVxKnf0vp4xuaf2ClyLihyphenhyphenk2GH1Tgm3OunZWyXb_Gydptfm0ID2qBZezLkbELq6IbJgJ_jAc8LKhGJ9aLZf4ktlFS8h_e2gGVldydYnb87WLTNeUWbtc9z5fFcCAmfXQSdPj9b/s288/Screenshot-distupgrade.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yea, pretty darn easy, I must admit. And my system certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t normal! It has been an upgrade from Debian Sarge(ish) -&amp;gt; Ubuntu LTS(ish) -&amp;gt; 6.10 -&amp;gt; 7.04&amp;hellip; The only hiccup was at some point when the fonts were reinstalling (I totally ignored the &amp;ldquo;close all programs&amp;rdquo; warning:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bare-metal Restore</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/bare-metal-restore_7646.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/bare-metal-restore_7646.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you can see by my previous post, my question to squeeze more req/sec from the server, I decided to try out Gentoo (again, last time was four years ago). Now, I like Gentoo, there is no doubt about that. However, I realized things took just &lt;strong&gt;too&lt;/strong&gt; long to get set up. I guess that is the disadvantage of a source based package management tool. Back to Debian I go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solved: NO PUBKEY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/solved-no-pubkey_625.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/solved-no-pubkey_625.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve received this error more than once, so I&amp;rsquo;m finally writing my notes how I solve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;error-message&#34;&gt;Error message:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;W: GPG error: &lt;a href=&#34;http://security.debian.org&#34;&gt;http://security.debian.org&lt;/a&gt; stable/updates Release: The following signatures couldn&amp;rsquo;t be verified because the public key is not available: NO_PUBKEY A70DAF536070D3A1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This really is just your standard don&amp;rsquo;t-have-the-gpg-keys error. So, get&amp;rsquo;em &amp;ndash; take the last eight digits from the long NO_PUBKEY string &lt;strong&gt;that is displayed on your computer&lt;/strong&gt;. If you are using Debian 4.0, the above key is likely correct; if you are using Ubuntu or another version of Debian, it will be wrong. (The last eight digits are used as an identifier at the keyservers). Then:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Postfix/Dovecot &#43; MySQL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/postfixdovecot-mysql_1687.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/postfixdovecot-mysql_1687.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you can see by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/tech-blog/gentoo-test/&#34;&gt;another post&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to reinstall the server. This isn&amp;rsquo;t really a problem, I have pretty good backups. I&amp;rsquo;ve installed apache and friends a bagillion times. However, Postfix(chroot)+Dovecot authenticating from MySQl, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t install quite so smoothly.&lt;br&gt;
Just for my future reference, and maybe helpful for somebody, someday. Clearly not a tutorial. The postfix chroot = /var/spool/postfix&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;cannot-connect-to-saslauthd-server-no-such-file-or-directory&#34;&gt;cannot connect to saslauthd server: No such file or directory&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, get the saslauthd files into the postfix chroot. Edit /etc/conf.d/saslauthd (or /etc/default/saslauthd), and add this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gentoo test</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/the-gentoo-test_1297.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/the-gentoo-test_1297.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a love-hate relationship with Linux. I love it because if there is a problem, I can actually tinker and find the problem and fix it. But I hate it because I like to tinker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a fair amount of Django programming &amp;ndash; enjoying every minute of it. After completing several of my projects I decided to do some benchmarks, and the results are in! Generally I can server cached/semi-cached pages at about 200req/sec. 200req! Considering this is 5,000,000 or so requests a day, and a number I am never going to reach, I still began to wonder: why isn&amp;rsquo;t it higher? I mean, serving a static html page is at like 1000+ req/sec, so why would a cached page be significantly different? I started exploring and noticed that Apache would spike the CPU. Ok, time to be thorough, and as I said, I like to tinker.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generating a Self-Signed SSL Cert</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/generating-self-signed-ssl-cert_2490.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/generating-self-signed-ssl-cert_2490.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have the need to generate an SSL cert (Apache2) about once every 3 months. And since I&amp;rsquo;m cheap, I don&amp;rsquo;t ever actually *buy* one, I just self-sign it. And every time I forget the commands needed. So, here they are, for my reference only.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1) Generate Private Key&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;openssl genrsa -des3 -out server.key 1024
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Generate a CSR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;openssl req -new -key server.key -out server.csr
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) Remove passphrase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cp server.key server.key.org
openssl rsa -in server.key.org -out server.key
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) Generate Self-Signed Cert&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Django SVN Update Goes Splat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/django-svn-update-goes-splat_5490.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/django-svn-update-goes-splat_5490.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing this just in case somebody runs into this same issue. I&amp;rsquo;m about to go live with a website and figured it would be best to have the latest SVN snapshot checked out from Django. I updated, and noticed that my voting module didn&amp;rsquo;t quite work as expected. I was getting the following error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;#39;module&amp;#39; object has no attribute &amp;#39;GenericForeignKey&amp;#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I jumped into Trac and noticed that &lt;em&gt;just yesterday&lt;/em&gt; some things were rearranged. In short, if you are using generic relations, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to change two parts of your code. First, the generic relations field must be imported out of conttenttype.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PNG Transparency and IE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/png-transparency-and-ie_2740.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/05/png-transparency-and-ie_2740.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;I Hate IE!&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://media.kelvinism.com/images/freakingannoying.png&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve vowed to not use transparent PNGs until almost everybody has switched to IE7, where they are actually supported (despite being supported by every other major browser). I&amp;rsquo;ve done the hacks, and have had good results. I like using PNGs, I&amp;rsquo;ll admit it. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inkscape.org/&#34;&gt;Inkscape&lt;/a&gt; exports them directly, however one slight problem: transparency still exists. This isn&amp;rsquo;t really a problem since I&amp;rsquo;m not layering images, or is it?&lt;br&gt;
My initial assumption is that IE would simple pull the white background and everything would be dandy. Well, we all know what they say about assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PSAD and Syslog-NG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/04/psad-and-syslog-ng_7378.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/04/psad-and-syslog-ng_7378.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really like using PSAD, both on my server and my laptop. You never know where the mean people are. I also seem to use syslog-ng quite often, meanwhile PSAD seems oriented to syslog. This is fine, and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure the install.pl for the source built will configure syslog-ng.conf automatically. However, I almost always tend to stick with packages if I can &amp;ndash; if they are even remotely close to the current version.&lt;br&gt;
Anyways, if you need to get syslog-ng.conf configured for PSAD, this is what you need to do:&lt;br&gt;
Add this code to the &amp;ldquo;# pipes&amp;rdquo; section, maybe stick to keeping it alphabetical.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple Chrooted SSH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/03/simple-chrooted-ssh_6907.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/03/simple-chrooted-ssh_6907.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You might be asking: why would you want to chroot ssh? Why use ssh anyways? Here are the quick answers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTP usually sucks&lt;/strong&gt;. Unless sent over SSL, all information is sent &lt;em&gt;cleartext&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSH usually rules&lt;/strong&gt;. SSH sends all data over an encrypted channel &amp;ndash; the main drawback is: you can often browse around the system, and if permissions aren&amp;rsquo;t set right, read things you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chroot&amp;rsquo;d SSH rocks&lt;/strong&gt;. The solution to both the above problems&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Layer Images Using ImageMagick</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/03/layer-images-using-imagemagick_25.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/03/layer-images-using-imagemagick_25.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For one of my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brokebutnot.com/&#34;&gt;webapp projects&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m needing to layer two images. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a problem on my laptop &amp;ndash; I just fire up GIMP, do some copy &amp;rsquo;n pasting, and I&amp;rsquo;m done. However, since everything needs to be automated (scripted), and on a server &amp;ndash; well, you get the point.&lt;br&gt;
The great &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagemagick.org/&#34;&gt;ImageMagick&lt;/a&gt; toolkit comes to the rescue. This is highly documented elsewhere, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to be brief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;take-this&#34;&gt;Take this:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/qQpq_rmGDyoXcID-MUKJRA?feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh9DtidDx_8lHusK9vq-3mkIcKg0JVjCMnyYy4DjZjap556Hb8z2kl3eVTnK-Mz-yBv0D_AG-DYTg2IhIy6Zxluvhe1iv7bbB6JbhmcQKwOL8bDQNqheRmrUN3WMdPjv_s_WgOW3XvCunUQ/s400/world.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Dying Laptop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/03/a-dying-laptop_8677.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/03/a-dying-laptop_8677.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/pGNVNaArTEVlfi8xjhsPYA?feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjPyeU1z0m7gaaj64mfwy7XuGBUjkaYy3JG97vvrPx3Y2WjByfT5jz4quQqRw4-YCKFmEAhD2giX4VuwWgR2fx4Ok7hkDj1yvS2h_T5GoVreUWT6y-An287kxWhRGQXy8zaRumLvb1egW9k/s400/DSC01613.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have the pleasure of owning an old T23 laptop. To show you how old this puppy is, the current T series is at &lt;em&gt;T60&lt;/em&gt;, and those have been out for over a year. This laptop was made in 2012, and I picked it up somewhat discounted late in 2003. It is now March 2007, and this puppy is still rock solid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You heard me, it is almost six years old and still working fine &amp;ndash; that is testimony to how well this laptop was built. There are several small cracks around the case, but nothing you would notice by just walking by. This laptop has been to more countries than many people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Hate GeoIP Advertising</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/03/i-hate-geoip-advertising_6728.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/03/i-hate-geoip-advertising_6728.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/WRMH3mQauVVNRBo9Jr-mdQ?feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjUCe5P3KESIXOcTikN8dyhNqIGGwP9liL62sQXgx7FeGNf2oQjwyHSbe8UJxuveH6RlUmFs8_120nmV_9XNj3aShEdCP_nH9j8lPYXkgEGTyzaztQOH0PxR8ClpM4MYqJP2I4hmV3RGfwS/s400/geoiphell1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, I&amp;rsquo;m in a coffee shop? GeoIPized Girls = have to sit with back to wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Country_IP_database&#34;&gt;GeoIP&lt;/a&gt; is the concept that allows you to map a user&amp;rsquo;s IP to the country it came from (I hacked up my commenting system just so you can see an example, if you are a visual type of person). Advertisers have long since picked up on this as a way to make their ads &amp;ldquo;better,&amp;rdquo; hopefully becoming more appealing to their clientele. Sometimes the adaptation doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite work as expected. This morning I was searching for an eBook on Embedded Linux (it is really hard to find English tech books here) &amp;ndash; and just had to snap a few screenshots. The advertisers picked up my IP, from Taiwan, and &amp;ldquo;customized&amp;rdquo; the advertisement. Needless to say, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a total of five white females here over the entire last year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One More Point Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/03/one-more-point-linux_9010.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/03/one-more-point-linux_9010.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It should come as a surprise that I enjoy using Linux. For the record, the first time I booted into Linux on my own was 1997, this was just before entering high school. So, while some of my tech friends played with NT, I was rumbling with the Penguin. Starting in 2000 I was using Linux as my main operating system, sometimes supplemented by OS X, and only using Windows when the gaming urge surfaced. In 2004 I mostly dropped playing any games, which resulted in dropping Windows &amp;ndash; and besides for work, I haven&amp;rsquo;t used it since.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Risk in Risk Mitigation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/03/the-risk-in-risk-mitigation_5540.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/03/the-risk-in-risk-mitigation_5540.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Back in the day&lt;/em&gt; the barrier to entry for the Internet was quite high. The technology used required a steep learning curve, the equipment extremely expensive, and sometimes even hard to acquire. Fast forward to 2007 and things have certainly changed. If you know any tech people you can likely get free hosting for a small website, and even more demanding websites can be hosted &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vpslink.com/vps-hosting/&#34;&gt;for not much&lt;/a&gt;. The cost of dedicated servers has dropped even more. And the final kicker: web services. I&amp;rsquo;ve started to think of some web services not as a service, but more like outsourcing requirements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python, AST and SOAP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/03/python-ast-and-soap_3058.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/03/python-ast-and-soap_3058.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For one of my projects I need to generate thumbnails for a page. And lots and lots and lots of them. Even though I can generate them via a python script and a very light &amp;ldquo;gtk browser&amp;rdquo;, I would prefer to mitigate the server load. To do this I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to tap into the Alexa Thumbnail Service. They allow two methods: REST and SOAP. After several hours of testing things out, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to toss in the towel and settle on REST. If you can spot the error with my SOAP setup, I owe you a beer.&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m using the ZSI module for python.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS in Python (REST)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/03/aws-in-python-rest_5343.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/03/aws-in-python-rest_5343.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As some of you may know, I have some projects cooked up. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect to make a million bucks (wish me luck!), but a few extra bills in the pocket wouldn&amp;rsquo;t hurt. Plus, I&amp;rsquo;m highly considering further education, which will set me back a few-thirty grand. That said, one of my projects will rely heavily on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FAWS-home-page-Money%2Fb%3Fie%3DUTF8%26node%3D3435361&amp;amp;tag=kelvinismcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&#34;&gt;Amazon Web Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=kelvinismcom-20&amp;l=ur2&amp;o=1&#34;&gt;. Amazon has, for quite some time now, opened up their information via REST and SOAP. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying (virtually the entire day) to get SOAP to work, but seem to get snagged on a few issues. Stay tuned.&lt;br&gt;
However, in my quest to read every RTFM I stumbled upon a post regarding Python+REST to access &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2Fb%3Fie%3DUTF8%26node%3D269962011%26no%3D239513011%26me%3DA36L942TSJ2AJA&amp;amp;tag=kelvinismcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&#34;&gt;Alexa Web Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=kelvinismcom-20&amp;l=ur2&amp;o=1&#34;&gt;. After staring at Python code, especially trying to grapple why SOAP isn&amp;rsquo;t working, updating the outdated REST code was a 5 minute hack. So, if you are interested in using Alexa Web Search with Python via Rest, look below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamachi Rules</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/02/hamachi-rules_5008.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/02/hamachi-rules_5008.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around more with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hamachi.cc/&#34;&gt;Hamachi&lt;/a&gt;, and have decided that it officially rules. Since I&amp;rsquo;m a big Linux guy I don&amp;rsquo;t have access to some features, but the program seems to be a gem. It is brainlessly easy to install (even when doing 20 things at once), and works quite well. Thanks to Ben and Sean for helping me test it out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ian the Apt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/02/ian-apt_4570.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/02/ian-apt_4570.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You know you are too nerd like when your conversations are like this. Preface: I posted some packages I needed to upgrade into a Skype window (much better than a clipboard)&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[11:56:03] Kelvin Nicholson: sorry, needed to post that somewhere&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[11:56:04] Ian FItzpatrick: i am not apt!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[11:56:15] &amp;hellip; you can&amp;rsquo;t pass packages to me ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[11:56:34] Kelvin Nicholson: blah blah blah&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[11:56:43] &amp;hellip; apt-get upgrade ian&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[11:57:02] Ian FItzpatrick: apt-get error: unmet dependency, &amp;ldquo;beer 1.0-4 not found&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Version 3.0 Part Two</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/02/version-30-part-two_8083.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/02/version-30-part-two_8083.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I&amp;rsquo;m basically all done upgrading to Version 3.0, I deserve a cake or something. Here&amp;rsquo;s the 411:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past few years I have been using Mambo, then Joomla, to manage the content on my site. It worked quite well, and was in PHP, so I could add or remove any code. Indeed, I&amp;rsquo;ve written a decent amount of PHP apps. In early 2004 I wrote a PHP platform to track adventures people had gone on, and networked people seeking to go on adventures with each other. I never marketed it, and mainly created it to learn PHP, but it was a CMS (Content Management System), and a little more. Late in 2004 I wrote another blog-esque platform for my second trip to Europe. It was pretty cool, I&amp;rsquo;ll admit: Casey and I each had a blog, and people could leave us &amp;ldquo;dares&amp;rdquo; and/or messages &amp;ndash; and we could easily update our status. Overall, it worked great. You can also see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/&#34;&gt;projects&lt;/a&gt; section of my site for some of the other things I&amp;rsquo;ve done in PHP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resize a VMWare Image of Windows XP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/01/resize-vmware-image-of-windows-xp_4908.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/01/resize-vmware-image-of-windows-xp_4908.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the years I have been shrinking the number of computers I own.  At one point my dorm was littered with old P100s, running whatever OS I felt like playing with at the time.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VMWare comes to help.  In this recent oops, an image I made (for Windows XP), was slightly too small.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like reinstalling XP + cruft, so just resized the image.  This is the process:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Version 3.0</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/01/version-30_1604.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/01/version-30_1604.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To all my loyal (but most likely few, and mainly with the same last name as me):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to redo the structure of my site, yes, it is about time.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a CMS (Content Management System) to categorize everything, but it is time to ditch that and write something.  Time to stop being lazy.  Time to stop procrastinating.  Time to learn something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me make this clear: version 3.0 surely won&amp;rsquo;t be based off PHP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Darn You HiNet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/01/darn-you-hinet_4291.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/01/darn-you-hinet_4291.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may know by now, I&amp;rsquo;m in Taiwan.  Live is pretty good here, especially the internet &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m sitting on a pretty decent 12M/1M connection.  But the company I have my internet through seems pretty laid back about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spamhaus.org/statistics/networks.lasso&#34;&gt;network usage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
-- which for me isn&amp;rsquo;t good.  Their entire IP subnet appears banned from IRC, which means I have to be a little sneaky when I want to talk to my I.T. friends in New Zealand.  Worse, some websites even banned the entire subnet:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight Detection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/01/lightweight-detection_8013.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/01/lightweight-detection_8013.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love my Snort, I really do.  But sometimes, I just don&amp;rsquo;t need all the extra overhead &amp;ndash; sometimes the resources on a server are somewhat, limited.  Looking for a solution I stumbled upon &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cipherdyne.com/psad/&#34;&gt;PSAD&lt;/a&gt; , a way to detect port scans.  Since port scans are often one of the first tactics used to find vulnerabilities on a server, it is a pretty good idea to detect them.   Depending on the attack, I receive a nice little email telling me what is going on.  To test it out I first fired up nmap, and received a few emails.  Next I fired up nessus with updated plugins &amp;ndash; you can be the judge.  I now have 50 emails from myself telling me somebody is doing something naughty:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated MySQL Backups</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/01/automated-mysql-backups_7112.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/01/automated-mysql-backups_7112.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Historically I&amp;rsquo;ve used the ever-so-popular AutoMySQLBackup script.  While it seems to work just fine, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to give another solution a whirl.  This solution, provided through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zmanda.com/&#34;&gt;Zmanda&lt;/a&gt;, seems to be less hackery and more enterprise.  The instructions are very clear, and the backup test went as planned.  Looks  like this is another gem for the toolchest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S3&amp;#39;s Super Backups</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/01/s3-super-backups_8294.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/01/s3-super-backups_8294.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My buddy &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ianfitzpatrick.com/&#34;&gt;Ian&lt;/a&gt;  mentioned Amazon&amp;rsquo;s S3 service, and the potential for using it for fun webapps.  While utilizing it for webapps will have to wait a few months, I was able to use it as a cheap backup for my home server (pictures, documents, etc,.) &amp;ndash; and my server that houses my email and websites.  The setup is pretty quick, and most of it can be detailed &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.eberly.org/2006/10/09/how-automate-your-backup-to-amazon-s3-using-s3sync/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  The ruby package is &lt;a href=&#34;http://s3sync.net/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;   I&amp;rsquo;ll toss in my recommendation to use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jets3t.dev.java.net/&#34;&gt;jets3t Cockpit&lt;/a&gt; application for viewing the buckets, especially considering the Firefox extension didn&amp;rsquo;t work as advertised.  My only two comments will be this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lighttpd As Apache&amp;#39;s Sidekick</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/12/lighttpd-as-apache-sidekick_4400.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/12/lighttpd-as-apache-sidekick_4400.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, you have a web server. So, you have PHP. So, you want to make it a little quicker? The following are a few ideas to let you do that. First, let me share my experiences.&lt;br&gt;
I have always been wondering &amp;ldquo;what would a digg do to my site.&amp;rdquo; I mean, I don&amp;rsquo;t run a commenting system, so I&amp;rsquo;m refering to just some article. Because I prefer to manage my own server, I have decided to use a VPS (Virtual Private Server) from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vpslink.com/&#34;&gt;VPSLink&lt;/a&gt;. Before purchasing I searched around, read reviews, and finally tested it out. Liking what I tested, I stayed. However, since I just host a few &amp;lsquo;play&amp;rsquo; sites (http/email/ftp), and a few sites for friends, I am not going to spend much money on a high-end plan. That leaves me with a little problem: how can I maximize what I&amp;rsquo;ve got?&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried quite a few things. I finally ended up using Apache to handle php and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lighttpd.net/&#34;&gt;Lighttpd&lt;/a&gt; to serve all static crap. So, how?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Dynamic Crap Static</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/12/make-dynamic-crap-static_7513.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/12/make-dynamic-crap-static_7513.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say one page on your site is getting hit hard. And I mean, it was digg&amp;rsquo;d or something. If the page resides on some CMS or blog, and each request is being processed by PHP and resulting in requests to your database, crap is gonna hit the fan. Well, at least if you&amp;rsquo;re cheap like me, you&amp;rsquo;ll try to squeeze every penny out of what you&amp;rsquo;ve got.&lt;br&gt;
That said, mod_rewrite comes to the rescue.&lt;br&gt;
There are only a few modifications that you need to do. The first is to ensure that mod_rewrite is enabled. If you have apache installed on debian, this might do:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MySQL Compat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/11/mysql-compat_1690.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/11/mysql-compat_1690.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve run into this error quite a few times, might as well toss blog entry about it:&lt;br&gt;
ERROR 1064 at line 17: You have an error in your SQL syntax near &amp;lsquo;ENGINE=MyISAM DEFAULT CHARSET=latin1&amp;rsquo; at line 7&lt;br&gt;
One likely reason this comes about is because the data being imported/exported is not compatible with the database version. For instance, at home you export the information from a mysql5 database. Then you try to import it on a mysql3.23 database somewhere else &amp;ndash; and it craps out on you. Bummer.&lt;br&gt;
The solution is quite simple:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCSE: Security</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/11/mcse-security_5711.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/11/mcse-security_5711.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My buddy &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ianfitzpatrick.com/&#34;&gt;Ian&lt;/a&gt; and myself have decided to get our MCSEs. However, Ian is a Mac lover, and I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to stay away from Linux (and I&amp;rsquo;m too cheap right now to buy a MacBook). The irony might be subtle, yet we are still studying and making progress. For the most part, I have decided to take the tests in the following order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;70-290, Security+, 70-270, 70-291, 70-293, 70-294, 70-298, 70-299&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resize a Xen Image</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/11/resize-xen-image_3704.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/11/resize-xen-image_3704.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, you&amp;rsquo;ve got a few Xen images around, and they are starting to fill up. How do you add a few more gigs to &amp;rsquo;em?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt; root@tpe:/# xm shutdown vm01  
 root@tpe:/# cd /xenimages  
 root@tpe:/xenimages# dd if=/dev/zero bs=1024 count=1000000 &amp;gt;&amp;gt; vm01.img  
 root@tpe:/path/to/images# resize2fs -f vm01.img  
 
```That&amp;#39;s it, you just added a gig to your image called &amp;#39;vm01.img&amp;#39;.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Katapult Screencast</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/11/katapult-screencast_788.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/11/katapult-screencast_788.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ianfitzpatrick.com/&#34;&gt;Ian&lt;/a&gt; keeps bugging me at how great Quicksilver is. Knowning that there &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; be an alternative built for linux, I accidently stumbled across Katapult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it still has a little room to grow, Katapult makes a great tool in any KDE toolchest. Press ALT+SPACE, and your widget fires up, ready to take your orders. Since words don&amp;rsquo;t really do this justice, I created a screencast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/10316527&#34;&gt;Katapult Screencast&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/user3417633&#34;&gt;Kelvin Nicholson&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xen &#43; nVidia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/11/xen-nvidia_5527.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/11/xen-nvidia_5527.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve played with quite a bit of virtualization, especially VMWare for ages. About eight months ago I started to play around with Xen, and got it to work great, except for the fact that the nvidia driver wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work with the Xen kernel. That said, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna give another go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout senior high, and especially my last year, I managed to score a bunch of crappy motherboards and random parts and pieces. Six or so years later, my parents are &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; finding old motherboards. Considering these computers were mainly P120s with 64-128 megs of RAM, they weren&amp;rsquo;t so hot. What is one to do?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Video Editing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/10/open-source-video-editing_7656.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/10/open-source-video-editing_7656.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the next year I plan to make a little video, nothing fancy likely, but something that will require an editor. However, I don&amp;rsquo;t own a mac (which rules our Final Cut Pro + After Effect and iMovie, which Ian and I both have had too much fun with. Inside joke.) I&amp;rsquo;m also a die-hard Linux fan, trying to hold out buying a mac for as long as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SF to the rescure. There are four editors listed, and in the next year I&amp;rsquo;ll try them all. Overalll, they look quite promising.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Little Commands and a Pen-Test</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/10/three-little-commands-and-pen-test_9.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/10/three-little-commands-and-pen-test_9.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yea, you read that right. Three commands and you can run a pen-test on your website/webserver. So, how?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;kelvin@home:&lt;del&gt;$ sudo apt-get install nikto&lt;br&gt;
kelvin@home:&lt;/del&gt;$ sudo nikto -update&lt;br&gt;
kelvin@home:~$ nikto -h &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thoughtdeposit.net&#34;&gt;www.thoughtdeposit.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, Nikto is a web server scanner, apparently for over 3200 dangerous files/vulnerabilities. Additional features can be seen at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cirt.net/code/nikto.shtml&#34;&gt;Nikto&lt;/a&gt; website, yet you will certainly want to add this old gem to your webserver toolbelt as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lighttpd&#43;Rewrite&#43;OpenSEF&#43;Joomla</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/10/lighttpdrewriteopensefjoomla_4861.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/10/lighttpdrewriteopensefjoomla_4861.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For those of you not needing Apache and the whole kitchen sink, [insert reason here], Lighttpd is a very attractive contender. For me, it has a small memory footprint, which is highly appealing. However, getting SEO urls to work (i.e. utilizing rewrite), isn&amp;rsquo;t too straightforward.&lt;br&gt;
Tada! A little research yields two helpful links: one at lighttpd.net regarding how to &lt;a href=&#34;http://trac.lighttpd.net/trac/wiki/Docs:ModRewrite&#34;&gt;use ModRewrite&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.j-prosolution.com/opensef-documentation/1484-opensef-lighttpd.html?highlight=lighttpd&#34;&gt;another&lt;/a&gt; showing how to slightly modify the .htaccess file used by OpenSEF and Apache.&lt;br&gt;
So&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unified Linux Desktop Experience</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/10/unified-linux-desktop-experience_9273.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/10/unified-linux-desktop-experience_9273.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll admit, I think one of the thickest barriers to entry regarding Linux is variety. I love variety, but general end users don&amp;rsquo;t adjust well to change (IMHO). Thus enter the stage: Portland. So, what does this mean to the end user? This means that, eventually, the UI throughout linux will all look similar &amp;ndash; regardless if it is designed to utilize GTK, QT or anything else (that is, if it is built off the Portland standard).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTML Validification Browser-Side</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/10/html-validification-browser-side_258.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/10/html-validification-browser-side_258.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like most standards, I can&amp;rsquo;t deny it. One thing that I find too humorous is the amount of sites that are not valid, even sites that claim they are. One tool in my box is &lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/firefox/249/&#34;&gt;HTML Validator&lt;/a&gt;, an extensioin for Firefox. A nice little icon appears in the lower right, indicating whether a page is valid, not-so-valid, or really-not-so-valid. Makes it easy to check your own sites, and others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Convert VMWare Movie to FLV</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/09/convert-vmware-movie-to-flv_2236.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/09/convert-vmware-movie-to-flv_2236.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This little process, a total of two lines, took way to long to figure out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we convert the VMware avi (VMnc format) to the Microsoft avi format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt; mencoder -of avi -ovc lavc movie.avi -o movie2.avi 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, we convert the Microsoft avi format to FLV format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt; ffmpeg -i movie2.avi -r 12  -b 100 movie.flv 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can play around with the -r switch (rate per second) and the -b switch (bitrate). But, if those get larger, so does your FLV file.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another VPN Node</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/09/another-vpn-node_6602.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/09/another-vpn-node_6602.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After consulting several vendors in Kuala Lumpur, I was able to get the right Cisco with the right IOS. One of their technicians came and installed it, and that night I hooked it up to our VPN. Besides the fact that the internet distribution is still a little shady in Kuala Lumpur, the connection remains somewhat stable, and yet another node is brought on the company intranet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hunt the Anomaly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/09/hunt-anomaly_560.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/09/hunt-anomaly_560.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Information is power, or so many of us think. As an I.T. administrator, no matter what the level, it is of my opinion that knowing what your network is doing is important. This includes regular operation, what it could do in the event of a disaster, or when it is just slightly not functioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeez, I&amp;rsquo;m personifying a computer network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I wrote in another post, I setup &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/projects/monitoring-traffic-usage/&#34;&gt;network monitoring&lt;/a&gt; for several nodes. But, what happens when an anomaly occurs? This is the story of hunting down a worm/virus, from far, far away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Traffic Usage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/08/monitoring-traffic-usage_3593.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/08/monitoring-traffic-usage_3593.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the greatest benefits, in my opinion, of Cisco routers is the ability to generate netflows. In a lot of ways, I would prefer to do this than implement some appliance (say, using ntop). The ability to analyse the amount of traffic becomes extremely valuable. Not only can one measure the amount of traffic, but the type of traffic that is being generated through the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a similar configuration, I setup all four Ciscos to export netflows that stream back to a server in the States. I decided to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://nfdump.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;nfdump&lt;/a&gt; as a collector. After the dumps are collected, it is simple to setup &lt;a href=&#34;http://nfsen.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;nfsen&lt;/a&gt; to parse and analyse the received flows. It even allows you to generate &lt;a href=&#34;http://nfsen.sourceforge.net/details-graphs.png&#34;&gt;really pretty graphs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick n&amp;#39; Dirty Firewall</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/08/quick-n-dirty-firewall_8747.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/08/quick-n-dirty-firewall_8747.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a Quick n&amp;rsquo; Dirty method at implementing a very simple firewall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;locate-iptables&#34;&gt;Locate IPTables&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on your server, first locate iptables:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt; \[root@vps /\]# which iptables 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;create-ip-based-acceptdeny&#34;&gt;Create IP Based Accept/Deny&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a whitelist (ignored by firewall) or blacklist (packet dropped) if you wish:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt; \[root@vps /\]# vi /usr/local/etc/whitelist.txt 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;And/Or&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;\[root@vps /\]# vi /usr/local/etc/blacklist.txt 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;In each file, add each IP per line, for instance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt; 4.2.2.2 66.35.15.20 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;firewallsh-script&#34;&gt;firewall.sh Script&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then put the following in /etc/init.d/firewall.sh, and edit to fit your needs:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Passing the MCSE 70-291</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/07/tips-for-passing-mcse-70-291_6981.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/07/tips-for-passing-mcse-70-291_6981.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may know, I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking a few of the MCSE:Security tests when I have time.  This afternoon I passed the 70-291, which is claimed to be the hardest of all the tests (and of the one&amp;rsquo;s I&amp;rsquo;ve taken so far, I would concur).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m taking my tests at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geego.com/&#34;&gt;Geego Systems&lt;/a&gt; center.  If you are in Taipei for some reason, and needing a place to take some tests, this place is a safe bet.  Their staff is pretty darn cool, and they let me drink as much tea as I want.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LDAP Backend</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/07/ldap-backend_5061.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/07/ldap-backend_5061.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users don&amp;rsquo;t like to remember passwords, heck, I don&amp;rsquo;t like to remember to use passwords. I decided to upgrade all the webapps to authenticate off the domain, welcome a start to SSO. To do this I implemented the &lt;a href=&#34;http://adldap.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;adldap php class&lt;/a&gt; to control authentication to each webapp. Thus, a simple GPO can control who has access to the app or not. A simple solution to a rather simple problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Very Remote Backups</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/06/very-remote-backups_5452.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/06/very-remote-backups_5452.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backing up across the states has worked decently well, but due to several changes a more dedicated backup solution is in order. Desiring something quick, simple and inexpensive, research revealed a company that would perfectly fit the requirements. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ibackup.com&#34;&gt;iBackup&lt;/a&gt; was a perfect substitute - instead of SSH+rsync to another office, iBackup provides rsync over ssl to their data center. A few simple changes to the cron job, and backup location is thus changed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Upgrade in China</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/06/an-upgrade-in-china_4087.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/06/an-upgrade-in-china_4087.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time has come to bring another network on the VPN, and perform some more upgrades. The usual by now, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Get China on VPN&lt;br&gt;
-Limit access to other locations&lt;br&gt;
-Update all systems&lt;br&gt;
-Perform security audits&lt;br&gt;
-Upgrade wifi&lt;br&gt;
-Setup video conferencing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ian and I set off for our China office out of Hong Kong, and the next day started working. Total preparation was around a month, maybe a little large, mainly due to red tape. We first acquired assistance of IBM China, who were of a great help aiding us in finding our desired Cisco. One of the most important factors, which we couldn&amp;rsquo;t resolve by purchasing the Cisco in the States, is support/warranty contracts (if the Cisco totally dies, what then). Through our contact we were also able to find some local vendors that would support Wifi and the Cisco, in case of an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Domain Remame</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/06/domain-remame_1834.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/06/domain-remame_1834.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we grow any further, a new DNS scheme is in order. Following the pattern of: citycode.domain.com - shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too hard. A slightly stressful rename of the PDC (just one so far, still small) was in order. After that (and client computers re-associated), the routers were updated, the DNS server updated, and everything worked peachie. Not bad for a weekends worth of work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IPSec Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/04/cisco-ipsec-tutorial_5224.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/04/cisco-ipsec-tutorial_5224.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following sites might be helpful to configure IPSec again, or on a more complex basis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/univercd/cc/td/doc/product/iaabu/pix/pix&#34;&gt;http://www.cisco.com/univercd/cc/td/doc/product/iaabu/pix/pix&lt;/a&gt;_60/ipsec/conipsec.htm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/warp/public/707/overload&#34;&gt;http://www.cisco.com/warp/public/707/overload&lt;/a&gt;_private.shtml&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where the &amp;#39;f is my Diskspace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/04/where-is-my-diskspace_4579.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/04/where-is-my-diskspace_4579.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Logs spiraling crazy, we run out of disk space all the time. A nifty trick to find where the disk went is to issue: du -cks * |sort -rn |head -11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This returns where the disk usage is, and makes finding the bloated log a lot easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firefox &#43; BugMeNot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/02/firefox-bugmenot_9551.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/02/firefox-bugmenot_9551.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a tip for Firefox. An extension called BugMeNot enables you to right click on &amp;ldquo;general&amp;rdquo; forms and say &amp;ldquo;Login with BugMeNot.&amp;rdquo; Firefox will call the BugMeNot extension which looks up in an external database login information. For instance, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com&#34;&gt;www.nytimes.com&lt;/a&gt; requires a login, which is a great place to test it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://extensionroom.mozdev.org/more-info/bugmenot&#34;&gt;http://extensionroom.mozdev.org/more-info/bugmenot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quickie Backups</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/02/quickie-backups_2198.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/02/quickie-backups_2198.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All is well for some disasters, but what happens if our entire office burns down? SSH+rsync to the rescue, again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first setup the PDC and webapp server to backup to the file server on a regular basis (PDC: incremental every day, full on Saturday). Then the file server takes those backups (including the files stored on the file server) every night and syncs them with another server across the States. In case something drastic happens, these off-site backups should be a savior.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Custom LiveCDs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/01/building-custom-livecds_4795.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/01/building-custom-livecds_4795.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a feeling we will shortly be deploying many Linux servers to perform certain actions. Maybe we will implement Asterisk to be used as a VoIP interchange between locations, maybe the backup servers will be Linux based, maybe the BDCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that could speed up implementation at remote sites is to build live cds for certain purposes. For instance, on the file server in PDX to keep updated live cds for certain projects. Like, a BDC live cd or a backup live cd. Already setup with the most current packages (or scripts to fetch+install them). So when we get to the site we just put the CD in, click or type &amp;ldquo;load&amp;rdquo; and poof, the server is installed and configured.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python &#43; Web Developement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/01/python-web-developement_4306.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/01/python-web-developement_4306.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A developer just showed me an interesting framework to produce python-backed sites VERY quickly. This is mainly for you Ian, it natively supports AJAX as well. Here&amp;rsquo;s the link:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.turbogears.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.turbogears.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched the demo, pretty interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Server Virtualization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/01/server-virtualization_5778.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/01/server-virtualization_5778.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t want to have a billion servers each doing their own task &amp;ndash; so what can we use as a solution? Server virtualization (or semi-virtualization or para-virtualization). This involves cutting down a server into mini servers that each have full customization. Our VPS at hostmysite is like this. So why would you want to do this? A few reasons actually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Localize exploits. Let&amp;rsquo;s say DNS gets exploited &amp;ndash; the access gained would only be for DNS, and not for mail and web and everything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamachi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/01/hamachi_2396.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/01/hamachi_2396.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ianfitzpatrick.com&#34;&gt;Ian&lt;/a&gt; told me about this originally, but my pen-testing cousin just send me the link as well. p2p VPN, w00t. Hamachi is a VPN alternative that does not have the normal router problems associated with IPSEC and PPTP vpns. That is good because of firewalls and nat and things like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hamachi.cc/&#34;&gt;http://www.hamachi.cc/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MySQL Replication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/01/mysql-replication_5029.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/01/mysql-replication_5029.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The webapp server is running fine, but backups are important. Better yet, a hot computer is a great idea. To do this, I setup an older spare rackmount as a &amp;rsquo;live&amp;rsquo; webapp server, just in case. A duplicate LAMP was setup, web apps copied over SSH via rsync on a regular basis, and the icing on the cake: mysql replication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if the dedicated webapp server dies a painful death, a quick change of IP for the webapp server in the internal DNS to the backup rackmount, and nobody will know anything happened.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux as a TFTP Server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/01/linux-as-tftp-server_570.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/01/linux-as-tftp-server_570.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, you need a TFTP server for something? Cool, you must be doing something fun. I need a TFTP server to copy Cisco IOS images onto the routers; hopefully you are doing something cooler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable TFTP in inetd.conf&lt;br&gt;
Open up /etc/inetd.conf and look for the following line:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;kelvin@pluto:~$ vi /etc/inetd.conf

#tftp  dgram   udp     wait    root    /usr/sbin/in.tftpd  in.tftpd -s /tftpboot -r blksize
```This is on line 72 for me (hint: in vi press ctrl+c, then :set number). Uncomment it. If you don&amp;#39;t have this line, bummer. Search for in.tftpd and use that as a substitute.  
  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;kelvin@pluto:&lt;del&gt;$ which in.tftpd
/usr/sbin/in.tftpd
kelvin@pluto:&lt;/del&gt;$&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New File and Webapp Server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/01/new-file-and-webapp-server_9847.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/01/new-file-and-webapp-server_9847.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time has come to upgrade a few servers in the office. An older P4 2.8 was being used as a webapp server, and that needs to go. The resource utilization wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much of an issue, however the computer was aging. Plus, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t strictly built to host critical services, but since we grew so quickly, it is what was available. Additionally, the PDC was hosting user files and with these mounting in size, a dedicated file server is in order.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet In China (Essay)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2005/12/internet-in-china-essay_7360.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2005 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2005/12/internet-in-china-essay_7360.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized at the end of the 2005 school year that I was going to be two business credits short of graduating. Two! Understandable I think, since I had been working full time or over full time (one to four jobs) for the last three years. Plus, I changed my degree after the first year; not to mention I somehow crammed five years worth of credits in four years. Well, I arranged with one of my teachers (who had a great class, I must add) to guide me through the last two credits. The credits involved writing a paper regarding China and the Internet. A broad topic, I must admit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network Upgrade</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2005/11/network-upgrade_1831.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2005 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2005/11/network-upgrade_1831.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A network upgrade is in order, since we are depending more and more on our internet connectivity. Historically we have been using D-Link &amp;ldquo;Business Grade&amp;rdquo; equipment over DSL lines (decent bandwidth, but not 100% reliable, plus latency that is a little high). Time for an upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since FiOS isn&amp;rsquo;t offered yet where our office is located, we had to settle on a T1. However, since both locations in the States will have T1s through the same company, the quality should be decent. Since I&amp;rsquo;m telecommuting now, my colleague organized what company to order the T1 through, and had the line installed. Since our offices are both quite small, there isn&amp;rsquo;t a need for any huge routers, we aren&amp;rsquo;t moving a tremendous amount of traffic. Then again, we do need a certain amount of features. Initially the T1 company almost required us to use their equipment (which was luckily discounted highly), and after we gave them our set of requirements, they gave us a pair of Cisco 1723s, which I was a little skeptical about. A Cisco technician came out and sort of set them up (enough for me to gain remote access at least). However, a slew of issues surrounded the 1723s. The routing wasn&amp;rsquo;t setup up quite properly, and the IOS was a little outdated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inventory Tracking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2005/10/inventory-tracking_1633.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2005 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2005/10/inventory-tracking_1633.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RATS, or Return Authorization Tracking System, is a way for us to handle RMAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site uses modified TOES code (although cleaned up significantly) to track returns and warranty claims (and depending on which type of claim it, this determines which part of the U.S. the warehouse will be shipped). It categorizes where they order is going, the status of the order, which company the return belongs to and customer information. Nothing too complicated, although I&amp;rsquo;m contemplating integrating it with our website so customers can check the status of their returns online.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Overseas Update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2005/09/an-overseas-update_1045.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2005 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2005/09/an-overseas-update_1045.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kuala Lumpur represents a new adventure for me, and a new project. The goals were simple: update/clean the systems, upgrade the internet connection, give pseudo-voip capability and try to get them on the VPN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before leaving the states I had to make sure several things were in order. First, I needed to order the rotuer I was going to bring out with me. Next, I needed to make sure KL had arranged the appropriate DSL upgrades, and last: pretest the connection. Before leaving L.A. I had the opportunity to test the new router and have it connect to the VPN. All is good to go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ERP Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2005/09/erp-time_2348.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2005 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2005/09/erp-time_2348.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently our ERP setup is a nightmare, both in stability, features and especially administration. A new solution is in order. After collecting goals/requirements we have begun researching, and even started testing some platforms. The &amp;ldquo;other half&amp;rdquo; of the IT department and I installed and tested &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.compiere.com&#34;&gt;Compiere&lt;/a&gt; today on a spare (albeit low performance) rackmount. For those of you (most) who don&amp;rsquo;t know, Compiere is an ERP solution that ties together all the faucets of a company under one hood. We are impressed with Compiere, but installation is a bit on the complicated side.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TOES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2005/09/toes_1320.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2005 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2005/09/toes_1320.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toes, aka the Temporary Order Entry System, is a, get this, a temporary ordering system to buy some more time while the full ERP is designed and implemented. Because we grew so quickly, orders needed to be put in a temporary zone, then moved somewhere else (apologies for being vague, you can understand why). Myself and a co-worker hacked up a temporary holding zone for the orders. It allows New Invoices, to View Invoices, whatever is In Queue, Voided and Search. The order entry page is auto-loads prices and things from the database, so totals are pulled out of the database and added up automatically. We ultimately entered well over 1500 invoices into TOES before the ERP was implemented, and besides a few odd hiccups, it was pretty stable. The UI doesn&amp;rsquo;t look all web2.0-like, but for an intranet project, it didn&amp;rsquo;t need to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track My Hours Please</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2005/07/track-my-hours-please_6190.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2005 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2005/07/track-my-hours-please_6190.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially all CSRs were hired as temps, which means they had their own timesheets. Some new people have been hired as full/part-time employees, so we need to handle their timesheets &amp;ndash; plus, several people (including myself) are paid on an hourly basis. Perfect time to setup a Timesheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we are still small, with no ERP, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have time or desire to write a timesheet app, I decided to do some research. I found a few on SourceForge, but I wanted something uber-simple to use and uber-simple to install. I settled upon &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.timesheetphp.com/&#34;&gt;TimesheetPHP&lt;/a&gt;. Luckily it even allowed LDAP support, which would be useful eventually for SSO. Installation was a breeze, and now everybody logs hours onto the an intraweb server.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faxing, Hurrah!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2005/07/faxing-hurrah_6354.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2005 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2005/07/faxing-hurrah_6354.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another line needing to be ported over: fax. Since time is very constrained, I quickly setup an extra server (OS X, actually) to act as a fax server. The fax line inserts immediately into the server, then from there any new faxes are printed on a normal printer and dropped into a central shared repository for the CSRs to access. Surely we will replace this setup sometime in the future, but for now it gets the job done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Division in 30 Days</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2005/06/a-division-in-30-days_9756.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2005 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2005/06/a-division-in-30-days_9756.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a Friday I was told we might purchase a division from another company. Monday I heard that we purchased the division, and that we needed to have a website taking orders and a call center, capable of handling 500+/day (and not short calls); by the end of the month. Not to mention that the products wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even ship out of the same warehouse that held the call center, but a warehouse half-way across the country. And that a recall was occurring, which had additional requirements. On Tuesday the CEO, and my boss, left for Asia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Britney Spears&amp;#39; Toxic, Remixed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2004/06/britney-spears-toxic-remixed_6603.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2004 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2004/06/britney-spears-toxic-remixed_6603.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started University as a CS major trying to get a business degree as well. The first two terms I was overloaded with classes (taking 19 and 22 credits, respectively). At one point I was in my C++ class and chatting to my mom, mentioning how I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really meeting that many people, especially females &amp;ndash; which when you are an 18 year old male, is something typically on your mind. She replied that most of the students in her communication class were female, and taking a few communication classes would make me a better husband one day blah blah blah; I dropped the CS degree and picked up a minor in Communication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
