<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Esxi on Kelvin Nicholson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/esxi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Esxi on Kelvin Nicholson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2009 20:30:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/esxi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>True Consolidation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/04/true-consolidation_6503.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2009 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/04/true-consolidation_6503.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2000 I managed to acquire several retired systems to bring to Uni: this included 4-5 cheap P120 machines. At the time, I thought this was great; I had an OpenBSD box as my gateway, a FreeBSD box, a few Linux boxes, and likely something else that doesn&amp;rsquo;t even exist now. The school has a superfast connection, unlimited bandwidth, and I was curious. Although I didn&amp;rsquo;t really have &lt;em&gt;time&lt;/em&gt;, I still managed to install and have all these servers running from my room.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Files between ESX and Linux via NFS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/03/files-between-esx-and-linux-via-nfs_6022.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/03/files-between-esx-and-linux-via-nfs_6022.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like ESX. I like Linux. It is absurdly easy to configure Linux as an NFS server and mount it in ESXIi).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Installed NFS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I currently use Ubuntu Server for my home lab, but the process is basically the same for Red Hat and derivatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install nfs-common
sudo apt-get install nfs-kernel-server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, configure NFS so it can server your local LAN. Normally you would list only specific servers, but, well, we&amp;rsquo;re being cheap and dirty today. Open /etc/exports in VI or your editor of choice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beginning Scripting ESXi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/01/beginning-scripting-esxi_6126.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/01/beginning-scripting-esxi_6126.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not impressed too often with much software, especially the closed source kind. I find a leaning preference to all things FOSS. If I had a million dollars, I&amp;rsquo;d likely spend all day contributing to all the projects I wish I had time to contribute to. Regardless, there are a select few closed-source products that I believe are truly excellent. I mean, the type of software where you aren&amp;rsquo;t asking &amp;ldquo;I wish this could do this&amp;rdquo; and start asking &amp;ldquo;I wonder what else this can do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install ESX from a USB (no CDROM)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/install-esx-from-usb-no-cdrom_3723.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/install-esx-from-usb-no-cdrom_3723.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My little server doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a cdrom, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to actually run ESX from a USB (i.e. esx-on-a-stick). Here are my notes of configuring a flash disk to boot the ESX installer (so you can install it onto a local disk). For this demo, my USB is /dev/sdb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install the syslinux utils to your computer (apt-get install syslinux mboot)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install the MBR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo install-mbr /dev/sdb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy all the files from the ISO to your fat32 formated partition&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrating large disks into ESXi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/migrating-large-disks-into-esxi_4692.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/migrating-large-disks-into-esxi_4692.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had the need to move a rather large (450GB) VMDK file from an external hard drive into ESXi. Since ESXi doesn&amp;rsquo;t support external hard drives, this makes things quite a bit more difficult. At first I tried using SCP to copy the file over (after enabling SSH access for ESXi). However, when I tried to do this the time left was almost 20 hours &amp;ndash; a tad too long!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 8.04 64-Bit and VMware Server 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/ubuntu-804-64-bit-and-vmware-server-2_1451.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/08/ubuntu-804-64-bit-and-vmware-server-2_1451.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I now have successful installation of VMware Server 2 (Beta RC1) on top of Ubuntu 8.04 64-bit. I have been using various virtualization technologies for years, and VMware is usually the easiest to install and configure. So far, VMware Server 2 RC1, has proven to be the exception to the rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I am very excited by the direction VMware is taking &amp;ndash; this new server version looks to have great potential.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
