<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Google on Kelvin Nicholson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/google/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google on Kelvin Nicholson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 23:10:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>February Sydney Python Presentation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/02/february-sydney-python-presentation.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 23:10:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/02/february-sydney-python-presentation.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February I gave a presentation to about 80 people at the Sydney Python group hosted by Atlassian. Firstly, Atlassian&amp;rsquo;s office was beautiful, feeling a little like Google&amp;rsquo;s Sydney office, but with beer on tap instead of cereal dispensers. Secondly, the talk before me on Cython by &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/113985890803565448326/posts&#34;&gt;Aaron Defazio&lt;/a&gt; was exceptionally interesting, garnering lots of questions from the audience. My presentation, more of a show and tell on piping location data to Google&amp;rsquo;s Latitude through App Engine, was also meant to subtly share my views on the need for innovation in the public sector (all sectors, really).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrate Custom Blog to Blogger</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/01/migrate-custom-blog-to-blogger.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 20:14:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/01/migrate-custom-blog-to-blogger.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last ten years I have run this website from various systems. First it was on Wordpress, then Mambo, then Joomla, and since early 2006 it has been running on custom code written using Django. I used this site as a learning tool for Django, re-wrote it after gaining more knowledge of Django, and then re-wrote it again when Google released App Engine. However, I recently realised that for the last few years I have spent more time writing little features than actually writing. I have entire trips that I never wrote because I was too busy writing code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baby Steps at Graphing Traffic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/baby-steps-at-graphing-traffic_522.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/04/baby-steps-at-graphing-traffic_522.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;br&gt;
You can likely tell that I&amp;rsquo;ve been having some fun with graphing and mapping recently. I was reading a few articles about GIS and stumbled upon a pretty darn cool project at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webopticon.com/projects/neighborhood_nets&#34;&gt;Webopticon&lt;/a&gt;, which included cool pictures. I showed it to my girlfriend thinking she would find it interesting, and then realized: oh! KML has an altitude attribute. That could be interesting.&lt;br&gt;
One of my projects is to create &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/2007/12/sydneys-driving-habits.html&#34;&gt;maps of Sydney&amp;rsquo;s traffic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, so I have been experimenting heavily with Mapnik and OSM. I figured I could have some fun and finally parse some gps tracks and display the data.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/bkhs8KqkZyS7yIoA6AeNnA?feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi8Ju2Qv3TAIupmzBjORZ5wUBGjxIlwZ_0mrPb0Mku5Yob6_ldYEmtRO0GP_kQ62-aZDZ3fP8_vh6nfXv9NpP5X98oneS25YXXf9Tr-pD1RMkp7l_jbDBWBsqxrA5hIDhH8KvfVjZI0TvGc/s288/gpstracks3.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turn Off Google Suggest in Firefox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/turn-off-google-suggest-in-firefox_857.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/turn-off-google-suggest-in-firefox_857.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I generally like Firefox, and generally like Google. But having Google suggest enabled when I search for things is annoying, at least on my rather small laptop screen. Mostly it is because my internet right now is pretty crap, so I try to cut down on any extra traffic. Anyhow, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even both Googling how to do this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type in &amp;lsquo;about:config&amp;rsquo; into your address bar and type &amp;lsquo;search&amp;rsquo; in the top filter bar. Look about half-way down for this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
