<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Quantified Self on Kelvin Nicholson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/quantified-self/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quantified Self on Kelvin Nicholson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2013 16:44:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/quantified-self/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Self Interview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/quantified-self-interview.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2013 16:44:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/quantified-self-interview.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;YS and I were recently interviewed about self-tracking and Quantified Self by one of the major news channels in Australia. I will reflect on the experience after the show has aired, but it was an overall great experience. We have a new respect for filming what may ultimately be just a two minute segment. Depending on how the editing is done it will either provoke the hosts to contemplate the value of a data-centric macroscopic view of the world, or give them lots of fodder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coffee, Beer, Wine and Time of Day</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/coffee-beer-wine-and-time-of-day.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2013 16:23:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/coffee-beer-wine-and-time-of-day.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I like Tableau, a piece of software to visualise data, is that it aggregates on dates really well. Below is a spread of beer / wine / coffee over 18 months, but grouped by what hour is fell in. You can see some trends, like I usually consume coffee in the morning, and that I usually drink after 17:00. There are exceptions, of course, like that beer I had at 10AM, and that coffee I had at 1AM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some QS Numbers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/some-qs-numbers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 08:26:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/07/some-qs-numbers.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is the possibility I will be giving an interview on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantified_Self&#34;&gt;Quantified Self&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;movement&amp;rdquo;. What follows is a brief summary of QS, the things I track, and some pretty charts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Quantified Self&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose it depends on who you talk to. Wikipedia states that it is &amp;ldquo;a movement to incorporate technology into data acquisition on aspects of a person&amp;rsquo;s daily life in terms of inputs&amp;rdquo;, but I side more on the idea that the movement is &amp;ldquo;a collaboration of users and tool makers who share an interest in self knowledge through self-tracking.&amp;rdquo; It is at this point that it is probably important to interject that most people are self-trackers: weight, height, reps at the gym, hours worked, and so forth. If you have ever made a goal, you probably tracked how you could reach it. What makes us QS folk a bit different is that we tend to track &lt;em&gt;lots&lt;/em&gt; of things, correlate between them, and share our results. So, with this theme, let me share what I track.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
