<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tips and Tricks on Kelvin Nicholson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/tips-and-tricks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tips and Tricks on Kelvin Nicholson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 10:02:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/tips-and-tricks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Error opening /dev/sda: No medium found</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/03/error-opening-devsda-no-medium-found.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 10:02:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/03/error-opening-devsda-no-medium-found.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had this issue before, solved it, and had it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say you plug in a USB drive into a Linux machine, and try to access it (mount it, partition it with fdisk/parted, or format it), and you get the error&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;  Error opening /dev/sda: No medium found  &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally the first thing you will do is ensure that it appeared when you plugged it in, so you run &amp;lsquo;dmesg&amp;rsquo; and get:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;  sd 2:0:0:0: [sda] 125045424 512-byte logical blocks: (64.0 GB/59.6 GiB)  &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned from Kathmandu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/01/lessons-learned-from-kathmandu.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 23:34:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/01/lessons-learned-from-kathmandu.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our first trip to Kathmandu is now over, so there are some lessons learned I should scribe. Some of these are obvious, and which we abide by whenever travelling, and some we simply forgot in our (very) impromptu trip to Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When agreeing on a price, make 100% sure the other person states the price back to you. I thought a price had been agreed to when the other person responded &amp;ldquo;ok ok, you are a lucky man&amp;rdquo;, but this does not count. As they say, reconfirm, reconfirm, reconfirm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned for Lightweight Travel to Europe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/01/lessons-learned-for-lightweight-travel.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 22:55:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/01/lessons-learned-for-lightweight-travel.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that our Europe trip has ended, I need to leave a note of things I wish we had done better, both travel-wise, and the stuff we brought along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to travel light, and find it a little comical when I see people struggling with giant 70L backpacks; my partner and I always do carry-on, no matter for a two week trip, or two months. (This means our packs have to weigh less than 7KG). Even in winter it is possible to pack light. The trick seems to be only packing what one will use regularly, with no duplicates, of appropriate size, and hopefully reusable for other purposes. Don&amp;rsquo;t pack anything you would be gutted if it broke.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reload a Cisco Router WIthout Worry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/reload-cisco-router-without-worry.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 14:15:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/reload-cisco-router-without-worry.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I tried editing my Cisco&amp;rsquo;s ACL at home on the train. It went something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I logged in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started updating the ACL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I hit a blackspot in my 3g coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My command stops at &amp;ldquo;router(config)#access-&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I get a call from my partner saying &amp;ldquo;what did you do to our internet!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it is simple enough to just ask her to &amp;ldquo;flip the switch on the black box&amp;rdquo;, I still don&amp;rsquo;t like doing it. Plus, if she&amp;rsquo;s not home, I&amp;rsquo;m stuck. This accident immediately reminded me of one of a trait of the &amp;lsquo;reload&amp;rsquo; command: it can be scheduled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beginning Scripting ESXi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/01/beginning-scripting-esxi_6126.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/01/beginning-scripting-esxi_6126.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not impressed too often with much software, especially the closed source kind. I find a leaning preference to all things FOSS. If I had a million dollars, I&amp;rsquo;d likely spend all day contributing to all the projects I wish I had time to contribute to. Regardless, there are a select few closed-source products that I believe are truly excellent. I mean, the type of software where you aren&amp;rsquo;t asking &amp;ldquo;I wish this could do this&amp;rdquo; and start asking &amp;ldquo;I wonder what else this can do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speeding Up VMWare Server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/speeding-up-vmware-server_791.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/speeding-up-vmware-server_791.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found VMWare Server to have very slow I/O, and sought to improve it. Below are a list of tests I performed, the change, and the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  
  
\### Host OS ###  
/dev/sdb1:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:  220 MB in  3.05 seconds =  72.17 MB/sec  
kelvin@gorilla:~$ sudo hdparm -t /dev/sdb1  
  
/dev/sdb1:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:  266 MB in  3.01 seconds =  88.33 MB/sec  
kelvin@gorilla:~$ sudo hdparm -t /dev/sdb1  
  
/dev/sdb1:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:  310 MB in  3.01 seconds = 102.99 MB/sec  
  
  
\### Before Changes ###  
  
/dev/mapper/openfiler-data:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:    8 MB in  3.36 seconds =   2.38 MB/sec  
\[root@files etc\]# hdparm -t /dev/mapper/openfiler-data  
  
/dev/mapper/openfiler-data:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:   24 MB in  3.63 seconds =   6.61 MB/sec  
\[root@files etc\]# hdparm -t /dev/mapper/openfiler-data  
  
/dev/mapper/openfiler-data:  
 Timing buffered disk reads:   28 MB in  4.54 seconds =   6.16 MB/sec  
  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I made several changes, but the changes that seemed to have the most impact are below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Portable Travel Stick</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/my-portable-travel-stick_1543.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/my-portable-travel-stick_1543.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This will be my last post from Taiwan, and I&amp;rsquo;m placing it in my tech section. Shortly I will be flying to Hong Kong, and then traveling into China. I&amp;rsquo;m not bringing my laptop with me. I&amp;rsquo;m always a little wary of using public computers, especially in many of the poorly run internet cafes. Often the logged in user is the administrator, and we all know the computers are obviously crawling with worms and keyloggers. What can I do?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turn Off Google Suggest in Firefox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/turn-off-google-suggest-in-firefox_857.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/06/turn-off-google-suggest-in-firefox_857.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I generally like Firefox, and generally like Google. But having Google suggest enabled when I search for things is annoying, at least on my rather small laptop screen. Mostly it is because my internet right now is pretty crap, so I try to cut down on any extra traffic. Anyhow, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even both Googling how to do this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type in &amp;lsquo;about:config&amp;rsquo; into your address bar and type &amp;lsquo;search&amp;rsquo; in the top filter bar. Look about half-way down for this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where the &amp;#39;f is my Diskspace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/04/where-is-my-diskspace_4579.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/04/where-is-my-diskspace_4579.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Logs spiraling crazy, we run out of disk space all the time. A nifty trick to find where the disk went is to issue: du -cks * |sort -rn |head -11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This returns where the disk usage is, and makes finding the bloated log a lot easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firefox &#43; BugMeNot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/02/firefox-bugmenot_9551.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/02/firefox-bugmenot_9551.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a tip for Firefox. An extension called BugMeNot enables you to right click on &amp;ldquo;general&amp;rdquo; forms and say &amp;ldquo;Login with BugMeNot.&amp;rdquo; Firefox will call the BugMeNot extension which looks up in an external database login information. For instance, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com&#34;&gt;www.nytimes.com&lt;/a&gt; requires a login, which is a great place to test it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://extensionroom.mozdev.org/more-info/bugmenot&#34;&gt;http://extensionroom.mozdev.org/more-info/bugmenot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Custom LiveCDs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/01/building-custom-livecds_4795.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2006 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/01/building-custom-livecds_4795.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a feeling we will shortly be deploying many Linux servers to perform certain actions. Maybe we will implement Asterisk to be used as a VoIP interchange between locations, maybe the backup servers will be Linux based, maybe the BDCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that could speed up implementation at remote sites is to build live cds for certain purposes. For instance, on the file server in PDX to keep updated live cds for certain projects. Like, a BDC live cd or a backup live cd. Already setup with the most current packages (or scripts to fetch+install them). So when we get to the site we just put the CD in, click or type &amp;ldquo;load&amp;rdquo; and poof, the server is installed and configured.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
