<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>IDS on Kelvin Nicholson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ids/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IDS on Kelvin Nicholson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 21:30:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ids/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrating OSSEC with Cisco IOS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/integrating-ossec-with-cisco-ios_7061.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/11/integrating-ossec-with-cisco-ios_7061.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I rank OSSEC as one of my favorite pieces of open source software, and finally decided to play around with it more in my own free time. (Yup, I do this sort of stuff for &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt;). My goal was quite simple: send syslog packets from my Cisco to my &amp;ldquo;proxy&amp;rdquo; server, running OSSEC. I found that, although OSSEC supports Cisco IOS logging, it didn&amp;rsquo;t really work. In fact, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any examples or articles of anybody actually getting it to work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PSAD and Syslog-NG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/04/psad-and-syslog-ng_7378.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2007 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/04/psad-and-syslog-ng_7378.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really like using PSAD, both on my server and my laptop. You never know where the mean people are. I also seem to use syslog-ng quite often, meanwhile PSAD seems oriented to syslog. This is fine, and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure the install.pl for the source built will configure syslog-ng.conf automatically. However, I almost always tend to stick with packages if I can &amp;ndash; if they are even remotely close to the current version.&lt;br&gt;
Anyways, if you need to get syslog-ng.conf configured for PSAD, this is what you need to do:&lt;br&gt;
Add this code to the &amp;ldquo;# pipes&amp;rdquo; section, maybe stick to keeping it alphabetical.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight Detection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/01/lightweight-detection_8013.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2007 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/01/lightweight-detection_8013.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love my Snort, I really do.  But sometimes, I just don&amp;rsquo;t need all the extra overhead &amp;ndash; sometimes the resources on a server are somewhat, limited.  Looking for a solution I stumbled upon &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cipherdyne.com/psad/&#34;&gt;PSAD&lt;/a&gt; , a way to detect port scans.  Since port scans are often one of the first tactics used to find vulnerabilities on a server, it is a pretty good idea to detect them.   Depending on the attack, I receive a nice little email telling me what is going on.  To test it out I first fired up nmap, and received a few emails.  Next I fired up nessus with updated plugins &amp;ndash; you can be the judge.  I now have 50 emails from myself telling me somebody is doing something naughty:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
