<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tdx on Kelvin Nicholson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/tdx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tdx on Kelvin Nicholson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 13:59:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/tdx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to convert 131500 TDX to GTFS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/07/how-to-convert-131500-tdx-to-gtfs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 13:59:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/07/how-to-convert-131500-tdx-to-gtfs.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TDX data has been available for a number of years on 131500.info, but many tools are GTFS specific. I also find GTFS easier to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, converting from TDX to GTFS is not overly difficult, and below are some instructions. This howto is a bit old, as I am only now copying it from my &amp;ldquo;Notes&amp;rdquo; folder to put online to help others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; You can now directly download GTFS from the TransportInfo website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://tdx.131500.com.au/&#34;&gt;https://tdx.131500.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Transport</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/04/visualizing-transport_1492.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/04/visualizing-transport_1492.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had several conversations with neighbors and co-workers about the &amp;ldquo;lack&amp;rdquo; of forward thinking, or at least the lack of forward action. Of course, I keep in the back of my mind that we aren&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;experts&amp;rdquo;, and the more I learn about transport the more I learn how complex it is. Dr. Sussman&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;CLIOS&lt;/em&gt; process (Complex, Large-&lt;br&gt;
Scale, Integrated, Open Systems) appears more and more true the longer I work in and study transport. There is a plethora of excuses that can be made, but the general conclusion was that the earlier we prepare the better. I can remember working near Zhongshan 7-8 years ago and driving around on huge roads in the middle of empty fields. There weren&amp;rsquo;t even stoplights at every intersection. It was then that I had an epiphany of how smart the planning was to build the infrastructure &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the masses arrived.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
