<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Netflow on Kelvin Nicholson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/netflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Netflow on Kelvin Nicholson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/netflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>NetFlow into MySQL with flow-tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/netflow-into-mysql-with-flow-tools_5439.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2008 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/12/netflow-into-mysql-with-flow-tools_5439.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been side-tracked on another little project, and keep coming back to NetFlow. For this project I&amp;rsquo;ll need to access NetFlow data with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.djangoproject.com&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;, but this is a bit tricky. First, I&amp;rsquo;m sort of lazy when it comes to my own project; maybe not lazy, I just like taking the most direct route. The most up-to-date NetFlow collector I noticed was &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/flow-tools/&#34;&gt;flow-tools&lt;/a&gt;, and there is even a switch to export the information into MySQL. Sweet! However, I wanted to insert the flows into MySQL automatically, or at least on a regular basis. I first started writing a python script that would do the job, but after a few minutes noticed flow-capture had a rotate_program switch, and started investigating. Since I somehow couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anywhere instructions how to insert the data automatically, here&amp;rsquo;s what I came up with:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hunt the Anomaly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/09/hunt-anomaly_560.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/09/hunt-anomaly_560.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Information is power, or so many of us think. As an I.T. administrator, no matter what the level, it is of my opinion that knowing what your network is doing is important. This includes regular operation, what it could do in the event of a disaster, or when it is just slightly not functioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeez, I&amp;rsquo;m personifying a computer network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I wrote in another post, I setup &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kelvinism.com/projects/monitoring-traffic-usage/&#34;&gt;network monitoring&lt;/a&gt; for several nodes. But, what happens when an anomaly occurs? This is the story of hunting down a worm/virus, from far, far away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Traffic Usage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/08/monitoring-traffic-usage_3593.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2006 20:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/08/monitoring-traffic-usage_3593.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the greatest benefits, in my opinion, of Cisco routers is the ability to generate netflows. In a lot of ways, I would prefer to do this than implement some appliance (say, using ntop). The ability to analyse the amount of traffic becomes extremely valuable. Not only can one measure the amount of traffic, but the type of traffic that is being generated through the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a similar configuration, I setup all four Ciscos to export netflows that stream back to a server in the States. I decided to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://nfdump.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;nfdump&lt;/a&gt; as a collector. After the dumps are collected, it is simple to setup &lt;a href=&#34;http://nfsen.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;nfsen&lt;/a&gt; to parse and analyse the received flows. It even allows you to generate &lt;a href=&#34;http://nfsen.sourceforge.net/details-graphs.png&#34;&gt;really pretty graphs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
